[{"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "In your own words, explain to me the 'Agreement on Agriculture' (AoA).", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know the extent of your knowledge within the agriculture industry. No matter which position you are interviewing for with Company ABC you should always be able to display a real and natural interest in the company's operations. Briefly explain your understanding of the AoA.", "\"From my understanding, The Agreement on Agriculture is an international treaty created in the mid-1990's. It was considered an answer to improving the economic conditions for farmers at the time.\"", "\"To my knowledge, the AoA (Agreement on Agriculture) is an international treaty set forth by the WTO (World Trade Organization).\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "At Company ABC we have restrictions surrounding the export of particular products. On a scale of 1-10 how familiar are you with agriculture export regulations?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know the extent of your knowledge within exporting. No matter which position you are interviewing for with Company ABC you should always be able to display a genuine and natural interest in the company's operations. Briefly discuss your experience with agriculture export regulations.", "\"In my previous position with Nicaragua Banana Corporation, everyone was expected to understand the rules surrounding banana export. I would rate my knowledge of agriculture export regulations as a 7 out of 10 because there is always more to know and some regulations change with time. I am happy to study these further, should I be the successful candidate for Company ABC.\"", "\"As I am newer to my career, I would rate my current knowledge around a 5/10. With that said, I am eager to learn and can grasp new concepts easily while maintaining a strong retention record.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "Do you have experience in corrective discipline and terminations?", "answers": ["Terminations and corrective discipline measures can be very difficult to do but, with experience, they do get more comfortable. Talk to the interviewer about the extent of your experience with terminations and discipline. \n\nIf you do have the experience: \"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "\"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "If you do not have the experience: \"I have not been in a position to perform terminations or hold corrective discipline meetings; however, I would be willing to perform these types of tasks with a small amount of training and research.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "What is the Doha Development Round?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know the extent of your knowledge within the agriculture and trade industry. No matter which position you are interviewing for with Company ABC you should always be able to display a genuine and natural interest in the company's operations. Briefly explain your understanding of the Doha Development Round.", "\"From my understanding, the Doha Development Round is primarily in place to increase global trade by lowering trade barriers. This Agenda has been in place since 2001.\"", "\"I am not completely familiar with the Doha Development Round; however, I do believe that it is a trade negotiation meant to encourage the increase of global trade.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "How do you handle communicating bad news to a fellow worker or subordinate?", "answers": ["One of the toughest parts of communication can be delivering bad news to people that you work with and care about. Whether it is delivering a less than positive work review or terminating someone - it doesn't come easy. Assure the interviewer that you can handle this type of task in a clear, concise, and professional manner.", "\"I certainly do not enjoy communicating bad news to a co-worker, but I do have experience in doing so. When this type of task is required of me, I make sure to practice empathy. Truth is always key, so I will be honest and clear when communicating the news. For instance, if I am to terminate someone's employment, I will not sugar coat the reasons why. It's best they know so that they can learn from the experience.\"", "\"Bad news is, unfortunately, just part of the job some days. When I have to deliver bad news, I will deliver it swiftly, but with kindness.\"", "\"Bad news is, unfortunately, just part of the job some days. When I have to deliver bad news, I will deliver it without delay. I will be honest and clear when communicating the news. Truth is always key!\"", "This is a great way to personalize MQ's sample answer."]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "Do you always double check or proofread your work?", "answers": ["Double checking and proofreading are essential parts of a job well done. Assure the interviewer that you are diligent when it comes to submitting good, clean work.", "\"Spelling and grammatical errors are a pet peeve of mine. I will triple check my work if there is time! I feel that it is imperative to submit error-free work.\"", "\"I try to double check my work as often as possible. Everyone makes mistakes; however, I do my best to submit error-free work.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways you remain motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of competition in me as well.\"", "\"New responsibilities and fresh challenges are a couple of things that motivate me.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "Would you rather be considered a personable leader or a dynamic leader?", "answers": ["This question can be a tough one because everyone wants to be liked and considered personable. However, being a dynamic leader can make you a proponent for change in the organization. A hiring manager is going to want to know that they are hiring a change agent for their organization vs. a friend for their employees.", "\"I do feel that I am a personable individual, but I won't always be everyone's cup of tea. I would much rather be a dynamic leader. As a dynamic leader I can ensure that the organization is benefiting from my presence and, at the same time, I can lead my team by example.\"", "\"I feel that being a personable leader is very important because when your staff feels like you are on their side, performance and morale goes up.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "At Company ABC we communicate often with the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA). Do you have experience working with this level of Government?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you have strength in communication when it comes to the Government and other essential business bodies. Give an example of a time when you have communicated directly with the U.S. Department of Agriculture. If you have not been responsible for a task like this, then you can discuss your communication style and strengths.", "\"The majority of questions that I have had in regards to the USDA are answered through their website FAQ section. I have been required to call the USDA hotline on occasion though. My communication skills are professional, so I do not foresee any difficulty related to this level of contact.\"", "\"I have extensive experience communicating directly with the USDA, over the span of 17 years. I am very comfortable with this job requirement.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals with a true passion for the agriculture industry. Where do you see this position taking your career in the next few years?", "answers": ["Onboarding new employees is an expensive and time-consuming endeavor for any employer. Assure the interviewer that you see long-term career potential with Company ABC. Research the company online to discover any opportunities for future growth. Do they have multiple locations? Is there a variety of departments? Where do you see yourself growing within Company ABC? Be enthusiastic when you discuss your long-term career plans!", "\"I am looking for a long-term career opportunity within the agriculture industry. I feel that this role with Company ABC is a perfect step in my career now, and for the future. I see that you have operations in Canada and Mexico. My dream would be to relocate to Mexico and be a production manager with Company ABC there.\"", "\"In my current position, I have had my sights set on the senior leadership position in my department. If I were to join Company ABC, my goal would be the same. I plan to take a few leadership workshops in the coming months to help get me there.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "At Company ABC we have many competitors. In your opinion, what makes us stand out in this competitive space?", "answers": ["It is essential that you research Company ABC before your interview and also that you include research on their competitors. In your opinion, where does Company ABC stand out from the rest? Be sure to check out their website and look for any recent press releases, product launches, or industry related accolades. These are all great points to discuss when asked a question such as this.", "\"This industry is competitive; however, I feel that Company ABC does an excellent job with standing out from the crowd. I see that you are the recipient of a Top 100 Employers award and that last year you were recognized for having the second most sustainable product in your industry. Congratulations on those big successes!\"", "\"After researching Company ABC I think that the verbiage you use on your website and your social media content has the most positive and client-centered message. That was a real stand out to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "Do you have any agriculture related post-secondary education? How do you feel your education will help you in this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Walk the interviewer through your post-secondary education. Be sure to highlight any related coursework that you feel will help you be successful in this role with Company ABC. You can take keywords from the company job description or job posting.", "\"I graduated in 2009 with my Bachelor of Science Degree (BSc Agriculture) from UC Davis. My primary focus was on environmental science and biology. This degree will help me immensely in my future career with Company ABC because my studies were highly interdisciplinary. I could be a valuable employee in a range of roles and departments.\"", "\"My education has been primarily on-the-job training and additional coursework on the science behind agriculture. You will see a full list of my certificates on my resume. In addition to these credentials, I have enrolled in a chemistry workshop this fall.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "We are always working hard to be innovative. What is your favorite product or service offered at Company ABC, and why?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for assurance that you are invested in the interview process. Show that you have researched Company ABC by offering your thoughts on some of the products/services you find to be unique or innovative. Be sure to show your enthusiasm!", "\"I was impressed when reading up on how you partner with farmers to understand their assets and teach them how to protect those important assets. It seems like you care deeply about all of your business partners and their needs.\"", "\"Your company offers a lot of great products, but I believe that the best thing you offer your customers at Company ABC sits in your values. Your organization has a very positive reputation for going over and above what is required, to satisfy your customers.\"", "\"The Simplot company offers a lot of great products like the innate potato, but I believe that the best thing you offer your customers at Simplot sits in your values. Your organization has a very positive reputation for going over and above what is required for satisfying your customers.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "At Company ABC we place great pride in our health and safety standards. Walk me through your health and safety related education or training.", "answers": ["When working in the agriculture industry, you will need to learn how to safely work around products such as grains, meats, chemicals, produce, and more. Briefly walk the interviewer through your related health and safety training. If you do not have any appropriate training, it is best that you ask the interviewer for a recommendation on where you can go to become qualified.", "\"I primarily have on-the-job training from my last two places of employment. I do not have any specific certifications or licenses. Is there a particular course you would like me to take before starting with Company ABC? I would like to note that I have a perfect safety record from all of the positions listed on my resume.\"", "\"I am certified in A, B, and C. Also, I recently completed a course on X. I do have extensive safety training, and a full list of my coursework and certifications is listed on my resume.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "In your own words, describe the part that the World Trade Organization (WTO) plays in the agriculture industry.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know the extent of your knowledge within the agriculture and trade industry. No matter which position you are interviewing for with Company ABC you should always be able to display a real and natural interest in the company's operations. Briefly explain your understanding of the World Trade Organization (WTO).", "\"From my understanding, the purpose of the World Trade Organization (WTO) is to ensure that everyone fairly benefits from international trade.\"", "\"I believe that when it comes to agriculture, the WTO (World Trade Organization) acts as a mediator in trade disputes and assists in trade negotiations.\"", "\"From my understanding, the WTO (World Trade Organization) acts as a mediator in trade disputes and assists in trade negotiations.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "Tell me about your greatest work related accomplishment.", "answers": ["Talking about your most significant accomplishment will give the interviewer a firm idea of where you place your values. It will also show the interviewer more about your personality, how you like to be motivated, and how to coach you in the future. It is okay to brag a little bit when answering this question. Show that you are proud of yourself and your career accomplishments!", "\"The greatest accomplishment in my career was graduating University as an honors student while still working full time in a related field. I was top of my class, and working full time. This accomplishment showed me that I could dedicate myself to my career, and reach the goals that I set for myself. It felt great to accomplish so much and be recognized for my dedication.\"", "\"My greatest work-related accomplishment is the fact that I have received three promotions, with my current company, in only 16 months. I have worked hard to build my career and look forward to continuing the progression, with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "Tell me about a time when you made a suggestion requesting change in an organization.", "answers": ["In addition to being able to handle change, can you also recognize when change is required and be confident enough to present that to your organization? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you were able to suggest a change in the workplace.", "\"Last year when I was managing dispatch I noticed a pretty solid opportunity for us to save on overtime hours. I created a presentation and gave it to my manager who took it to upper management. The changes were implemented, and I was very proud of the suggestion that I made.\"", "\"Just last week I suggested to my employer related to changing vendors of a particular product we use a lot. We looked into things further, and the change could present a significant 15% cost savings. We are likely going to make the change this year. It's exciting to present new ideas, and to be heard.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "By this time in your career, you should have advanced further, what has slowed down your career progression?", "answers": ["When an interviewer sees slow career progression on your resume, they will immediately want to determine whether this is by your own choice, any outside circumstances, or if you are not motivated to create growth in your career. If your job has progressed slower than you wish, you must be honest with the interviewer when discussing this.", "\"I agree with you that my career progression has been slower than some. You will see that between 2001 - 2009 I worked for the same company without an increase in a title. The company was too small to offer a promotion to me as the next level was ownership and the business wasn't for sale. After this, from 2009-2012 I was on leave as I needed to care for my ailing parents. The growth since returning to work has been steady but those years were a bit of a standstill for me. I am ready to spring into action now, and forge ahead in my career.\"", "\"Overall, I am satisfied with my career progression. Although my job titles may not have changed significantly, my employers always offered additional responsibilities and fair wage increases.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "How would you describe your work ethic?", "answers": ["When the interviewer asks about your work ethic, they are looking for specific examples or keywords to which they can relate. When you read the company job, posting or job description do they refer to particular company ethics? Talk about their values and how those align well with your work values. \n\nSome characteristics you may want to use are: \n\n- Determined/Driven\n- Accountable\n- Humble\n- Respectful\n- Dependable", "\"I am a very dedicated and loyal employee. I saw on your website that you describe your company as honest, transparent and you go the extra mile for your clients. My work ethic is the same. I am honest, flexible, and come ready to work hard for my employer every day.\"", "\"My work ethic can be described as reliable, honest, and consistent. You are welcome to speak to my references in regards to my work ethic. I am very proud of my reputation as a reliable executive assistant.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "What work situations excite and motivate you?", "answers": ["It is essential, for your success, that the hiring manager knows how to keep you motivated and excited to come to work every day. Share with the interviewer what they could do to ensure that you are happy and productive.", "\"I am most motivated, on the job, when there is a solid level of organization, and the vibe is positive. I value strong teamwork and good leadership.\"", "\"I am most motivated on the job when I feel like an active contributor and an important member of the team. When I feel listened too and valued, I am excited to do my best work.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "Name a few things you were asked to do in your last position that you weren't trained for.", "answers": ["When you don't have the skills to complete a task, how do you approach it? Often you need to ask others for help or research the process to find the answers yourself. To prepare for this question, start by making a list of some of the tasks you tackled that were outside of your job description. Perhaps you were asked to do a presentation but didn't have the knowledge or experience to put together a slideshow. How did you deal with it?", "\"I was asked to present to the team about an idea I wanted to implement that would save the company money and time. I had never done this before, but I was knowledgeable about the topic and researched the solution further. I played around with PowerPoint and put together a slideshow that was easy to understand. It turned out great, and I learned a lot from the experience.\"", "Here is a list of some tasks that you may be asked to do even if you were not trained: \n\n- Training new employees \n- Dealing with customer disputes\n- Learning a new software \n- Giving a presentation \n- Attending trade shows \n- Up-selling products\n- Resuscitating dormant accounts"]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "When have you spoken up for cause, knowing that it would directly look unfavorable on you, because it was the right thing to do?", "answers": ["Every manager wants a team player who will not resist company policy or argue about every detail of the workload. However; a time may come when you need to speak up about something, and it may not look the best on you. Talk to the interviewer about a time that this may have happened to you on the job.", "\"For the most part, my company abides by all labor regulations. In the case of overtime, they did not abide by the regulations, and I had to speak up for my team. The company was not happy about it because it cost them a lot of money but, in the end, they realized that they were in error.\"", "\"I have had to stand up to workplace bullying a couple of times in my career. It's never fun to rock the boat; however, respect in the workplace is fundamental to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "When it comes to problem solving, are you a strong collaborator?", "answers": ["Show off your teamwork skills by giving an example of when you successfully collaborated with your coworkers. Be sure to demonstrate how you communicated your thoughts or opinions. Highlight how your contributions, or ability to ask for help, made a difference. Explain how you are a team player who enjoys working alongside others.", "\"Last month, I recruited a couple of coworkers to help me solve a problem for a client. We were looking at their financials, but something didn't add up, and I didn't have the analysis background that these two co-workers had. Together we molded our areas of expertise and created a bulletproof financial plan for our client. I enjoyed the collaboration and would do it again in a heartbeat.\"", "\"I love having impromptu brainstorm sessions with my team. It keeps everyone on their toes! When an issue comes to light, I will approach the problem with the entire team and open the floor, at the end of the meeting, for suggestions.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "How many people did you supervise at your last position?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer your level of responsibility in your current position. If you have managed larger teams than you currently are, you can also discuss that particular role from your work history.", "\"Currently, I am supervising 12 employees with an overall portfolio responsibility of $24MM. In my role, before this one, I managed 23 employees but with a smaller portfolio of $6MM. I can handle a large range of employees.\"", "\"Although I did not directly supervise anyone in my last position, I did end up being the 'go-to' person for many of the more junior employees. My natural leadership skills shine through in most situations.\"", "\"Although I did not directly supervise anyone in my last position, I did supervise two master's students and one undergrad student during my Ph.D. My natural leadership skills shine through in most situations.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"Although my current salary is $45K/year, I am seeking $52K in my next position. Because I work for a very small organization, they are not able to offer me a competitive compensation compared to the industry marketplace.\"", "\"Although my current salary is $51K/year, I am seeking $90K in my next position. Because I work for a university, they are not able to offer me competitive compensation compared to the industry marketplace.\"", "Your ask for a larger salary is appropriately backed by research, which is great."]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "If you had a co-worker call in sick and you were asked to take over their project requiring overtime from you, how would you react? Where do you draw the line when it comes to being a team player?", "answers": ["Show your confidence to your interviewer by explaining your willingness to be part of the team and not being afraid to pick up the slack when needed, but make sure you don't allow someone to take advantage of you.", "\"I will always choose to be a team player. If I had a co-worker call in sick, I would take over the tasks I was capable. The only time I would draw the line would be if I felt I was being taken advantage of for some reason. For example, if they were purposefully being inefficient and expecting me to pick up the slack.\"", "\"For the sake of the company, I am always willing to go above and beyond my expectations. I don't mind covering for others, and taking additional shifts, whenever possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "How would you rate your performance in this interview so far?", "answers": ["This question is a bit of a pressure test because if the interview is not going well, the interviewer wants to see if you can recover from it. Be honest and address any points in the interview that you feel may have been inconsistent.\n\nIf you feel that your performance in the interview is going well: \"I believe that this interview has been quite informative and I am happy with my performance. Is there anything that I can clarify for you from this conversation?\"", "\"I believe that this interview has been quite informative and I am happy with my performance. Is there anything that I can clarify for you from this conversation?\"", "If you feel that your performance in the interview is not going well: \"I am not sure if I have been able to portray myself 100% accurately in this interview; although, I am trying my best. If there is anything more I can clarify for you, I would be happy to do so.\""]}, {"topic": "Agriculture", "question": "Do you have any questions for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in this industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\"", "\"Thank you for asking! A couple of questions come to mind. What do you see as the biggest challenge your company will be facing in the next 12 months? Also, what is your employee turnover rate, and could you tell me a bit about the retention plan you currently have in place?\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Tell me about the products available from Company ABC. How familiar are you with our products?", "answers": ["You must have a firm understanding of the products you will be representing before your interview. Company ABC offers a range of products and you should be able to list off quite a few of them. The more you know, the more you are showing engagement and interest in the role. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about the products that you have tried, the ones you like the most, and the ones that you look forward to trying. Confirm your ability and interest in learning new products.", "\"I have tried many Company ABC products, including (A), (B), and (C). I find your products to be premium to anything else on the market. I believe your products to be superior in many ways and will have no trouble selling in the (D) and (E) markets. I see that you launch new products every year, which is exciting! I look forward to seeing the innovative products that come from Company ABC next.\"", "\"I have gone to Company ABC products as my top beverage brand choice for many years! Your products are versatile; especially (A), and (B). I will quickly learn your range of products and will proudly represent them!\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "How can Company ABC motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Many people find motivation through financial perks, bonus opportunities, words of encouragement, or the chance for promotion and career growth. The interviewer wants to know how to keep your motivational levels high, ensuring that you are productive on the job. Discuss what keeps you motivated, even on days that do not offer a ton of excitement or activity.", "\"Friendly competition is always a great motivator for me, even if its competition against myself such as beating my best weeks' sales numbers.  A friendly yet competitive environment allows me to have a fun and new goal to look forward to even on days that may not be as action-packed.\"", "\"I live for new opportunities and chances to gain promotion or career growth. I am newer to my career, and I want to grow and prove what I can do, so any opportunities related to career growth are highly motivating for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Being an account rep for Company ABC is a very independent role. How well do you work with little supervision?", "answers": ["Depending on your role with Company ABC you could be on the road a lot, driving to visit clients which could include liquor stores, restaurants, hotels, or corporate accounts. This independence means that you need to be very communicative and organized. \n\nIf you have worked in an environment that offers little supervision in the past, this question is an excellent opportunity to mention this experience. The interviewer wants to see that you can be productive and accountable for your time.", "\"As a territory account manager, I am accustomed to very little supervision. I spend Mondays in the office and most other days on the road, on the phone, and making site visits. To keep myself accountable for my work and performance, I am sure to be highly communicative and keep up-to-date documentation in our shared CRM. I set goals and mark myself against those goals at the end of every single day.\"", "\"I currently work in a close-knit office. There is a lot of supervision, as my desk is just feet away from my direct manager. With that said, I am very diligent and have never had an issue with being self-led and independent. Regardless of the level of supervision, I always exceed expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "How would you go about developing and nurturing a new client account?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to understand your sales process, how you build rapport with your clients, and how you ensure a great relationship with all of your accounts. Talk about the way that you approach new clients, how you get to know their needs before making product suggestions or asking for a sale.", "\"I must understand their business, customer demographics, and existing products before ever making recommendations or asking for a sale. I go in person when approaching a new client account. I introduce myself, offer free samples of my product, and ask them about their business and customers. Being inquisitive and allowing the business owner to do most of the talking is a significant factor in rapport building.\"", "\"When approaching a new prospect, I would be sure to show them that I have done my research on their business. I look at who the owners are and if they own other businesses, what the demographics are within a 3-mile radius, and more. I will visit the store as a customer and take note of the stock they give priority placement to in their store. Once I am ready with an idea of how my product can benefit them, then I will approach with my sales pitch.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "What is the difference between on-premise and off-premise sales?", "answers": ["On-premise and off-premise sales are terms that you will come across often in the alcoholic beverages industry. On-premise sales mean direct to consumer sales for consumption. On-premise establishments would be bars and restaurants, for instance. Off-premise sales would be if you sold to liquor stores and other retailers. Take a couple of minutes to show the interviewer that you understand the difference between the two and that you know basic industry lingo.", "\"I have sold in the alcoholic beverage industry for a few years; in both on-premise and off-premise sales. For on-premise sales, I sold craft beer for a local brewery, direct to bars and restaurants. When working off-premise, I sold various liquor products to independently owned retail liquor stores.\"", "\"My experience in the industry has been strictly off-premise sales, meaning that I have sold to retailers such as liquor stores. I am eager to learn more about on-premise sales as I feel it would be an even greater challenge to sell directly to restaurants and bars.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "What is the most significant contribution you have made to your current company?", "answers": ["The interviewer at Company ABC wants to see that you are a team player who strives to meet and exceed corporate goals. Think about a time when you took an action that improved a process, helped out your teammates, or helped to grow your company's bottom line. Keep your story to the point and be sure to include actual numbers and results that the interviewer will be able to remember.", "\"In my current team, I had the pleasure of introducing some new cold calling techniques. I now teach these techniques to every new salesperson that we hire. I teach a 'questioning' approach where the conversation focuses' on how our product can help the end-user, encourage more profitability for the prospect, and enable them to succeed. This approach is very different from the pushy sell we see typically see in cold-calling. Since introducing this technique, our cold-call-to-conversion rate has increased a whopping 33%.\"", "\"In my spirits department, I am the only one with food and beverage experience. I have made it my mission to create educational materials to help our team better understand the benefits and features of our products. Being armed with this information ensures that everyone feels more confident when discussing new product launches or selling our existing product line. Our sales have increased by 12% this year. Much of this success is due to our team possessing greater product knowledge and enthusiasm for what they are selling.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Walk me through your experience with CRM software. With which programs are you most experienced?", "answers": ["A CRM is a Customer Relationship Management tool that helps you to organize your customer data and track the actions that you need to take, to nurture accounts. Think of the names of all software and programs that you have used in your current or previous positions. Think about the features that you used and how the system helped you to better perform at work. \n\nSome of the most popular CRMs in North America include Oracle, HubSpot, Zoho, Salesforce, NetSuite, and Microsoft Dynamics. If you are not sure of the system used at Company ABC you can certainly ask!", "\"I understand two different CRM programs which include Oracle and Salesforce. My previous companies were enterprise-level organizations, requiring strong CRM support and options. I would rank my skills in these systems as an 8 out of 10. Could you share with me the CRM you use at Company ABC?\"", "\"Being new to my career, my exposure to a CRM is limited; however, I would be happy to get a head-start on my learning if you would like to share with me which CRM you use. I pick up on new tech and systems very quickly.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "How do you plan to drive the performance of Company ABC brands over your first 90 days?", "answers": ["The performance of Company ABC products should be one of the most critical concerns for you. Discuss how you will contribute to the performance of their brands and products during the first three months of your employment. Chances are, you will be on a 90-day probationary period, so it's especially critical that you have a plan for success.", "\"In the first 90 days of employment at Company ABC I plan to call on every existing account given to me and book a time to meet with the client. I will take the time to discover what I could do to improve their service and gain more of their business. I will reach out to my existing network and drum up at least five new accounts, ensuring that I exceed my sales targets as soon as possible.\"", "\"Besides cold calling and spending a fair amount of my time prospecting new business, I will also dedicate myself to fast-track my training. My success will depend greatly on my product knowledge, so I plan to take additional time studying and learning every SKU under the Company ABC brand.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "This position aside, which department of Company ABC are you most interested in gaining experience?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know where your interest is, aside from the position for which you are currently interviewing. The best employees are often the ones who understand the ins and outs of more than just their job function. \n\nPerhaps you want to learn more about research and development, marketing, human resources, data and analytics, talent acquisition, or even finance. Express to the interviewer that you have an interest in getting to know Company ABC and their overall operation.", "\"Aside from this sales-based position, I would love to have a peek inside how product research and development work with Company ABC. I have a curiosity and keen interest in the process that goes into deciding which products make it to market, and which ones are scrapped.\"", "\"My educational background is in Marketing. I would love to get to know more about the marketing process at Company ABC. It would be exciting to learn how product launches are born and executed.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "What are POS materials, and how can you best leverage them to boost sales?", "answers": ["POS materials, or Point of Sale materials, are highly essential marketing tools that showcase and present products, generally at checkout. POS materials attract consumer attention and promote the brand or product. \n\nPOS materials are usually informative and eye-catching to encourage impulse purchases. Show the interviewer that you know how to leverage POS materials, ensuring Company ABC product always performs to its highest potential.", "\"I have a great deal of experience with POS materials. I visit my accounts frequently and place my products in the best position possible, to optimize sales potential. Some tools that I have used include shelf-talkers, brightly colored price tags, promotional stands, and wrap-around banners. In my current role, these POS materials, when placed strategically, have increased sales by up to 22% in some months.\"", "\"I understand POS materials to be the tools used at checkout, or the point of sale, to attract buyers to make impulse purchases. The POS materials that catch my attention the most are informative or humorous and brightly colored. Could you share with me the types of POS materials that perform the best for Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Are you comfortable selling products that come with health-related warning labels?", "answers": ["Company ABC does it's best to ensure its products are premium, and available only to those of legal drinking age. Regardless, the truth is that alcohol comes with a warning label in most regions. These warnings include not to drink during pregnancy, that drinking impairs your driving, and heavy drinking can cause health problems. Talk to the interviewer about your level of comfortability in selling products that come with a health warning.", "\"I believe that most things are fine to be enjoyed, in moderation. Alcohol can be terrible for you if you misuse it. I will ensure that my customers are knowledgable in how Company ABC products are best enjoyed.\"", "\"I have researched Company ABC products, your company's demographic, and also your marketing approaches. Many industries have products that come with health-related warning labels, so this is a non-issue for me. So long as people drink responsibly, and do not drive after drinking, I see no issue.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Tell me about a time when you retained a customer who wanted to cancel their order.", "answers": ["This customer-service based question will show the interviewer how you handle challenging customer issues. Now is the time for you to showcase your approach when it comes to retaining customers and meeting your sales goals. It's essential to be able to save a sale! Show the interviewer that you can represent the company while ensuring that your clients get what they need.", "\"I was able to gain a lot of training and experience early in my career, related to saving a sale before the customer churns. I understand that losing a customer is not just a one-time financial hit, but a loss of recurring revenue. I had a customer who wanted to cancel 50% of their product order. They believed the product did not move fast enough, and their profit margin was too low. I spent time in their business to see how product moved and was able to customize a plan for them. This customization included the same spend but different products I believed their customers would enjoy. I kept close follow up with the customer over the three months following the change, and they were thrilled with the results. They were profiting more, and I was able to increase their spend over the following months.\"", "\"In my first retail-based job, I had a customer who had buyers' remorse the following day and wanted to return their entire purchase. I asked a couple of questions regarding why they no longer wanted the product. After asking questions, I realized that it was a financial issue for the customer. I asked them if they were aware of our layaway program. I walked the customer through the layaway process and was able to save the sale. It felt great to accomplish this goal while also ensuring that my customer was happy with their purchase at the end of the day.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "How did you develop your largest existing account, in your current position?", "answers": ["Think about a time when you made a significant difference to your current employer by nurturing and growing a critical client account. In sales, your existing accounts offer considerable opportunities, so you must be able to maximize the relationships that you currently have. Share a success story from your current position, being sure to share numbers and percentages when available and appropriate.", "\"With my largest account, the majority of my success has come from getting to know their needs, and being available to them when they need me. I am genuine and take the time to get to know their business. I understand what their biggest pain points are and how my products can offer them higher profit margins than competing brands. My largest account has grown by 40% this year simply due to my personal approach and ability to help them make sense of the numbers.\"", "\"I want to learn everything that I can when it comes to winning and growing large accounts. As a retail sales professional, I have clients who spend a lot of money, sometimes upwards of $5,000 per transaction, but they are rarely returning customers. I look forward to changing industries where I can learn more about customer relationships and nurturing accounts.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Company ABC has a very competitive employment offer. What do you know about our offering?", "answers": ["Before attending an interview, you must research and understand what Company ABC offers in the way of benefits, employee perks, and more. You may not have every detail; however, most companies will give you some information on their careers page. Show that you have done your homework before the interview and come prepared to discuss what excites you the most.", "\"In addition to advertising your competitive salaries, I see that Company ABC also offers holiday bonus', a 401k savings plan, medical and dental, and more. Your compensation packages sound very generous, and I especially look forward to hearing more about your tuition reimbursement program.\"", "\"I researched your careers site quite extensively and understand that you offer reward and recognition programs, quarterly bonus opportunities, holiday bonus' and more. I am thrilled to see that there are so many opportunities present at Company ABC to prove myself and be eligible for payment based on a stellar performance.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "If you could change one thing about Company ABC marketing, what would it be?", "answers": ["It's time to take a look at the marketing efforts of Company ABC with a critical yet open eye. Of course, you don't want to answer this question by completely knocking down their marketing efforts, and offering a thousand ways they could change. \n\nWhat the interviewer is looking for is an insightful suggestion on how they could boost their marketing efforts in one specific area. Perhaps you think they could be more active on social media, or you know of a new advertising avenue  Company ABC could benefit from.", "\"I have seen a lot of popular brands advertising on Spotify. I think Spotify could be a fascinating new avenue to look into when it comes to Company ABC marketing efforts. I like the commercials that I see and hear on television and radio; however, I believe that other digital approaches could be more lucrative and less expensive for Company ABC.\"", "\"I enjoy the advertising efforts of Company ABC and find the messaging to be consistent and well thought out. If I could add to your marketing efforts I would suggest adding more drink recipes onto IGTV, showing bartenders making fun cocktails with your products.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Company ABC promotes the choice to drink responsibly. What does this mean to you?", "answers": ["In most regions, alcoholic beverages come with health warnings, and messages to 'drink responsibly.' You will likely see this statement on Company ABC website, and much of their advertising. Responsible drinking is much more than merely not drinking and driving. Show the interviewer that you have the insight required to sell their products in a responsible manner.", "\"The choice to drink responsibly goes far beyond drinking and driving. Responsible drinking means limiting yourself to a certain number of drinks. It means always remaining in control while under the influence, not binging, and not allowing alcohol to ruin relationships important to you. Responsible drinking also means ensuring that you listen to medication labels if you take prescription meds.\"", "\"Responsible drinking means only consuming alcohol when you are of legal age. It means having a designated driver or taking a cab when you are drinking. This phrase also refers to binge drinking or mixing alcohol with illegal or prescription drugs.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Are you aware of some of the awards won by Company ABC recently?", "answers": ["Any awards and accolades by Company ABC will likely be listed on their corporate or careers website. You can do an online search, or take a look at their social media for any recent bragging points. If Company ABC has a blog or news section on their website, you may find helpful information there. \n\nDiscuss a recent accomplishment by Company ABC, showing that you have researched their organization before your interview. You can express how their stellar reputation adds to your desire to work for their organization.", "\"I saw many badges on your website, which included accolades such as 'Best Place to Work,' 'Best New Product,' and other forms of recognition related to diversity and inclusion in your talent acquisition plan. It seems that Company ABC is very involved in community efforts. You have earned credit for building teams of people who care about your corporate success because you care about their career growth.\"", "\"I have read through your corporate website and have looked at other sources such as Glassdoor and Best Place to Work. It seems that Company ABC has consistently earned recognition for being the best place to work! Seeing all of your awards in this category makes me even more excited to join your organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "How can a liquor brand best influence a customer at the point of purchase?", "answers": ["You probably know that great merchandising is critical to the success of a product when placed in a retail setting. If you fail to merchandise effectively, your products may not sell as fast as expected. Assure the interviewer that you understand the importance of on-point merchandising. Discuss some of the strategies that you would implement to ensure that your product moves, should you become a new team member at Company ABC.", "\"The checkout area is critical when it comes to upselling opportunities. I like to teach my customers about the value of impulse buys at the point of sale and how much they can increase their profitability. Customers waiting in the line need something to look at, so why not put fun promotional products around the checkout, with graphics and catchy signage? As a rep, I put a great amount of focus on displays and promotions seen from the counter or the checkout.\"", "\"When it comes to overall influence, a liquor brand can have window signage, neon signs, competitive placement inside coolers, and eye-catching signage for 'grab' items at checkout to encourage impulse buys. I look forward to learning more about your merchandising standards at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "This position requires extensive travel. Are you able to travel at least 60% of the time?", "answers": ["Depending on your role with Company ABC, you may be required to travel. Much of this travel will be within work hours and may require overnights. It's essential that you have a solid idea of the expectations in this role, and whether or not you can meet them. If you are not clear on the travel expectations, be sure to ask for clarification.", "\"I can travel 60% of the time, including overnight travel out of town. I have a reliable new vehicle, and currently, do not have restrictions when it comes to my schedule. I love to get out and meet my clients and introduce myself to potential new customers as well. Could you share with me more on the travel expectations for this position?\"", "\"At this time, I can travel wherever it is required of me between 7am-6pm Monday to Friday. I have a commitment to my family on evenings and weekends; however. Do you have a travel schedule that you could share with me? I certainly want to meet your expectations in every way.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Walk me through your sales experience and training.", "answers": ["Your answer to this question should go beyond the information provided on your resume. Discuss the highlights of your sales experience, with a spotlight on your brightest accomplishments. \n\nKnowing your career highlight reel is especially important if your resume doesn't give a full picture of your accomplishments, and is more task-based. This question is your time to show off just a bit; discussing your training, education, and experience.", "\"I have been in sales for over six years with my first role being a door-to-door alarm sales position. In that job, I worked my way into a team-lead position where I would train new reps on sales and closing techniques. Over the years, I have put a lot of emphasis on professional development. I recently completed 'The Future of Selling,' a Dale Carnegie program. I keep myself up to date on new sales processes, and utilize my CRM to ensure my pipeline of business is always full.\"", "\"I currently work as a business development researcher, which means that I spend most of my day prospecting and cold calling, up to 150 calls per week. I am the top researcher in my company, and I account a lot of this success for the business reading that I do on sales, account development, closing deals, and asking for the sale. I know I am ready to take the next leap to become an account manager with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "What are some challenges the liquor industry will face in the next three years?", "answers": ["When you are in-the-know of industry challenges, you show the interviewer that you are engaged in the interview process. The more you know, the keener you will appear to Company ABC, increasing your chances of being hired. \n\nTraditionally, the biggest obstacles in the liquor industry include regulation, taxation, tight profit margins, and social issues related to drinking and responsible consumption. Talk about an article you recently read or statistics that you found interesting. Show that you have done your research!", "\"I believe that one hot topic impacting the liquor industry now, and in the next few years is the rising popularity of cannabis-based beverages. Cannabis is a shining star at the moment and is competing heavily with the alcoholic beverage industry in many regions as of late. We will see some changes coming up, I believe, as these product gain popularity.\"", "\"Government and policy change will be a continued challenge in the liquor industry. As we begin to see trade laws change, we may see less product exported globally. I recently read an article on the liquor industry and trade agreements. The idea was that the alcohol industry is becoming more aggressive in trade agreements and other agreements related to the reduction of tariffs.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "The liquor industry is highly regulated. How will you stay up to date on the rules and regulations of our industry?", "answers": ["Depending on the region where you are interviewing, you will have to learn different rules and regulations related to the sale of alcohol. Do some research on the governing bodies in your area, and to which you believe you'll have to comply should you be the successful candidate. \n\nKeep your answer straightforward by discussing how you plan to keep up to date on rules and regulations. Show the interviewer that you are interested in remaining in-the-know and well-educated in the alcoholic beverage industry.", "\"I believe that in this region the most important governing bodies would be the FDA, the FAA, and the Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration. Is this correct? I believe the best ways to stay up to date on rules and regulations would be to subscribe to their newsletters and alerts.\"", "\"From my research, I know that the regulation of wine, spirits, and malt beverages is by the Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau (TTB). Sometimes the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has jurisdiction and also the FAA, the Federal Alcohol Administration Act. To remain in-the-know on important topics related to the regulation of alcohol, I will set up news alerts for these governing bodies as well as subscribe to their email and updates.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "What stage of the sales cycle do you find most challenging?", "answers": ["In the sales cycle, there are a variety of stages, including: \n\n- Prospect\n- Approach \n- Present\n- Overcome Objections\n- Close \n- Follow Up \n\nThe interviewer would like to know if there is one particular area where you will need additional training. When it comes to your current position, discuss any areas that you could improve on, and talk about what you are doing to overcome the challenge.", "\"I can always become better at overcoming objections. When I know my product very well, and I believe in it, I have no problem selling. However; the product that I currently represent is in an oversaturated market, and our pricing is not as competitive as it could be. For that reason, right now, I find overcoming pricing related objections to be the most difficult. I have been reading 'Sales EQ' by Jeb Blount, which is very helpful, as well as listening to a variety of sales-based podcasts.\"", "\"I find prospecting to be the most challenging since the majority of my work experience has been customer service and existing account management. To work on this shortcoming, I have been reading many resources and blog posts on the Salesforce website. I also have been reading 'High-Profit Prospecting' by Mark Hunter. There is a lot to learn, but I am ready!\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "How do you balance managing your existing liquor accounts while also searching for new business opportunities?", "answers": ["Working for Company ABC, you will have many tasks to juggle at one time, and the interviewer wants to see that you can handle the volume of work. If you are applying to an account manager position or any sales role within the organization, this question will be especially crucial for you. \n\nThink of a time you expertly balanced your work, ensuring that you kept the momentum going with existing accounts while never forgetting the importance of bringing in new business.", "\"In my current role I have a 60/40 split of existing business versus new business. To ensure that these streams of business get the attention they need from me, I time block my business development activities such as site visits, cold calls, and prospecting. If hired at Company ABC, I will do the same; ensuring that I exceed my targets and goals.\"", "\"To manage my existing accounts and still have time to look for new business, I will set aside specific times of day to prospect and cold call. I believe it's important to have a good balance so that my new business pipeline never runs dry. I will lean on my CRM and properly document; ensuring that everyone is in the loop as far as my activities every day.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "How do you prefer to be managed?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see your dedication to delivering quality work, which means understanding the type of management to which you best respond. Show that you are self-aware and that you know the kind of management style that brings out the best in you. \n\nSome people enjoy a close working relationship with a lot of accountability, while others prefer space and autonomy. This question offers an excellent opportunity for you to ask Company ABC about their management approach, or the approach of the person to whom you will be reporting.", "\"I prefer management where I am assigned my tasks and goals, and then allowed to run with it for the most part. Collaborative team environments where trust is present, but I am still held accountable for my goals and targets best suits me. Could you describe the management style at Company ABC?\"", "\"I find that I am most successful when given the space to explore sales approaches and build customer relationships the way that I know best. I have had roles where I needed to follow a sales script verbatim, which felt unnatural and uncomfortable for me. I look for mentorship and coaching qualities in the people whom I report to, and in return, am highly accountable for my goals and targets. Would you say this describes the management style at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "How important is it to be persuasive when working in a retail sales-based industry?", "answers": ["Being a persuasive person is not a negative factor; in fact, many esteemed sales organizations train their front-line employees and management on the art of persuasion. \n\nGood communicators are often persuasive and can influence others to see their point of view without being pushy, demanding, or aggressive. It is essential to have the power of persuasion when you are selling any product or service.", "\"I see persuasion everywhere; in marketing, advertising, most business conversation, and even casual communication outside of work. I do consider myself persuasive but not pushy. I can convey my goals, and the reasoning behind them, very clearly. I build rapport with my clients and get to know their needs. When the time comes to ask for a sale, I can express to them how they will benefit. So, in sales, product sales, and retail sales, the power of persuasion is critical.\"", "\"As an account manager, persuasion is critical. I need to gain buy-in from my clients, and prospects when it comes to the belief and understanding that the product I represent is superior. I have trained on persuasive techniques such as 'Appeal to Reason,' 'Appeal to Trust,' and 'Appeal to Emotion.'\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Describe your personality to me. Will your references agree when I call them?", "answers": ["The liquor, alcoholic beverages, and wine industries all look for team members who are confident, dynamic, persuasive, and energetic. You will be representing the Company ABC name and their brands/products, so it's essential that your personality be a fit for the overall culture of the organization. Speak briefly about what your references would say about you; describing your personality in a sentence or two.", "\"My personality is energetic, positive, intuitive, and inventive. I take the time to understand my clients' needs, and I bring energy to every meeting that I attend. When people have a good time around you, they are much more likely to buy your product or agree to carry your brand. My references will agree that I bring a great amount of energy and positivity to my work.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "Company ABC has a healthy diversity plan in place. In which ways do you embrace diversity and inclusion?", "answers": ["The conversation on diversity and inclusion has become an important one. Companies are making significant efforts to broaden their talent acquisition efforts to attract a broader range of candidates. Recruitment processes are beginning to eliminate unconscious bias due to AI tools, and many companies believe that diversity is a core competency versus a 'nice to have.' Discuss with the interviewer what diversity and inclusion mean to you, and how you will uphold their efforts as an employee of Company ABC.", "\"For a company to operate sustainably, I believe they must have a long-term diversity plan. I was thrilled to see in my research that Company ABC is so forward-thinking when it comes to your multicultural workforce and global markets. I support diversity and inclusion by helping my co-workers to leverage their unique abilities and engage in a variety of activities and conversations within the workplace.\"", "\"I believe that when a company has a sense of community, it only enhances performance and competitive business advantage. I was pleased to see that Company ABC offers employee resource groups, personal and professional growth opportunities, and other collective ways for coworkers to collaborate and cross backgrounds and experiences. I look forward to becoming involved in any way that I can.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "What does exceptional client service mean to you?", "answers": ["Company ABC is a well-known brand with popular products and an excellent reputation to uphold. Your part, as an employee of the company, will be to deliver exceptional experiences to everyone that you encounter during your workday. \n\nBy delivering excellent customer service, you are one to look for opportunities to go above expectations. You listen to your customers and sell from a perspective of their needs versus your wants. You offer support to your customers, even when you feel too busy to pick up the phone or pop in to see how they are doing.", "\"The basics of customer service is to be of service; meaning I make myself available to help when my client needs me. Exceptional customer service means being reliable and friendly, knowledgable in my own business, but in that of my customer as well. I was proud to win 'rep of the year' last year, with votes coming from my actual customers. It was an honor, and it felt great to know that my customers feel that my added efforts make a difference in their business.\"", "\"When my customers are thrilled with every one of our encounters, to me that is exceptional customer service. I deliver what my customers need, even when it means inconveniencing myself. I take the time to get to know their business and what keeps them up at night. Then, I ensure that my product recommendations are helpful and will ease their pain points as much as possible. My customers can lean on me, and they can trust that I will only recommend a product that they can move and profit from.\""]}, {"topic": "Alcoholic+Beverages", "question": "To which Company ABC competitors are you applying?", "answers": ["The hiring authority wants to know if you are applying to any competitors, for a variety of reasons. First, they want to see which brands you have an interest in. Second, it's relevant data for a company to gather when it comes to competitive talent acquisition. Third, the interviewer would like to know what kind of time-frame they are operating in when it comes to your interview process and a potential job offer. You are under no obligation to disclose every detail of your job search. With that said, it is a professional courtesy to let Company ABC know if you are in final stages with other organizations.", "\"I have applied to Company  ABC and Company XYZ around the same time that I applied with Company ABC. I have had a prescreen interview via telephone with Company ABC and a first interview booked with Company XYZ next week. My first impressions tell me that Company ABC is more organized and thoughtful in your interview process, which I like. I have felt very comfortable here from the start. Could you share with me the next steps in your interview process?\"", "\"I am active in my job search, although I have not applied to any of your direct competitors. I want to start my career off right by joining an organization where I can be trained very thoroughly, and grow with a supportive team.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of effort into our safety and hygiene standards. Do you have any formal health and safety training?", "answers": ["Your health and safety credentials are on your resume; however, the interviewer would like for you to go into a bit more detail. You can talk about a course that you most enjoyed or perhaps discuss a certification that you would like to achieve down the road. It is excellent if you can open the discussion by asking the interviewer if Company ABC is looking for a particular set of credentials when it comes to health and safety.", "\"I have a certification in grain handling, keg cleaning, and bottling. I took these courses and became certified in 2013 by The Brewers Association. I would like to take additional training in Filtering and Pumping. Are there any particular courses or training sessions you would like to see me attend?\"", "\"I am happy to take any health and safety training that you require. I have taken some courses in the past but am unsure if they are still valid.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "In such a competitive industry, how do you think Company ABC stands out from competitors?", "answers": ["Interviewers often use these conversations as ways to gain insight into what their consumers like about their product. Research the Company ABC website and check out their 'News' and 'About Us' sections to discover where they are currently gaining recognition.", "\"I believe that Company ABC stands out from your competitors because you put a strong emphasis on shrinking your economic footprint. The news page on your website talks about how you've reduced water usage this year by 12%. It's a great accomplishment, and your efforts are standing out in this industry.\"", "\"In my opinion, Company ABC stands out through your reputation for taking care of your employees. Your company culture is unmatched. I believe that happy employees create great products so this could certainly give you an edge over your competitors.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Tell me about a time that you have helped a co-worker accomplish an important goal.", "answers": ["Being goal-oriented and determined is imperative when working at Company ABC. What do you do, outside of your own goals, to ensure that everyone on your team is successful? Assure the interviewer that you are always willing to keep the team, or company as a whole, in mind.", "\"As a Sales Manager my team is only as successful as the lowest producing employee. It is crucial that my entire team is motivated, engaged, and on point with their KPI's. Last month I hired a new employee who was struggling significantly with sales. I sat him down and realized that he didn't understand the product. We spent a few hours together over that next week learning the product. In the end, his sales increased by 64%, and he was significantly more confident. It helped the team morale as well.\"", "\"I had a coworker who recently needed some flexibility in his schedule so that he could finish his final university exams. I offered to take his overtime shift as well as to swap a couple of shifts with him. It always feels good to help someone accomplish things that are important to them.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "When have you been asked to perform a function or complete a task in which you had little or no experience in doing?", "answers": ["Have you ever had to take on a task or a role that you felt was over your experience level? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have dealt with this type of situation. What was the outcome, and what did you learn?", "\"When my manager went on unexpected medical leave for three months last year I was asked to step into her position in the interim. I knew the basics but was certainly not trained on the specifics of the role. I was able to take it on successfully by leaning on my team, reading a lot of company manuals, and asking many questions. Once my manager returned she was very pleased with the progress that I made, and I gained a promotion.\"", "\"My current company recently implemented a new SAP system which means that every day has been a learning curve for me. I have had to learn how to manage inventory levels and document in the SAP system. I enjoy taking on new tasks and learning new things.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "What type of work environment allows you to be the most productive?", "answers": ["Are you able to be productive in any environment? Are there particular types of situations that you find distracting? Discuss your preferences with the interviewer. Be sure to research the kind of environment present at Company ABC before the interview.", "\"I understand that your work environment is very collaborative. I come from a similar environment and found that I could be very productive when there was the \"", "\"I am pretty versatile and can handle a variety of work environments, but I do prefer to work in an organized environment with a positive beat.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Outside of work, what type of creative activities do you like to pursue?", "answers": ["A genuinely creative minded person will have outside activities aside from what's happening in the workplace. Tell the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you express your creativity.", "\"Outside of work I like to attend dance classes and I also attend the odd paint and sip wine nights at a local wine shop. I also enjoy reading as a way of nurturing my creative side.\"", "\"I love to attend concerts! I am really into music and have started taking piano lessons twice per week. I believe that exercising creativity is important for everyone to do from time to time.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals who are passionate about the beer and brewing industry. What do you do to stay on top of industry news and trends?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you have a genuine interest in the brewing industry by talking briefly about the ways you stay up to date on new trends. It's a great idea to ask the interviewer how they stay up to date, as well. You never know what you could learn!", "\"I make my home brew as a hobby, so I stay updated on new trends in brewing through my local homebrew store. I also follow a couple of great blogs such as brewbeerblog.com. I go to our local Beer Fest every year as well!\"", "\"I stay up to date on new industry trends and news by reading a few subscriptions on a regular basis. My favorite resources include A, B, and C. Which are yours?\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "How do you feel about our branding and marketing strategy at Company ABC?", "answers": ["It is essential that you research, and understand, the brand(s) promoted by Company ABC so that you can have an educated opinion on their marketing strategies. Perhaps they have great commercials, an informative website, or a strong presence at sporting events. Be prepared to discuss at least one aspect of their marketing and be sure to show your enthusiasm for the things you feel Company ABC does best.", "\"One thing that I appreciate about Company ABC is that your branding has always been consistent. It's entertaining and not over the top. I also like that you put a strong emphasis on supporting local sporting events.\"", "\"Your branding is what made me apply to work for Company ABC in the first place. Your brand is refreshing, and your workplace boasts a close-knit culture.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "At Company ABC we have a great selection of beers. Which is your favorite product?", "answers": ["It is crucial that you have a personal opinion on the product offered by Company ABC before you go into your interview. Perhaps they offer a variety pack that you can pick up or maybe you are already familiar with the product. Choose one product that stands out to you and be prepared to discuss what you love about it!", "\"I have always enjoyed the majority of the product offered by Company ABC; however, my new favorite has been the winter ale offered this year. It's crisp and has a lively finish. I keep it stocked at home because even non-beer drinkers enjoy it, so it's easy to bring out when people drop by unexpectedly.\"", "\"Although I am not a drinker, I can appreciate the care and attention that goes into all of your products. I am especially interested in your brewing process as it's unique and very much a craft process.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Our industry is a very competitive one. Tell me one thing you feel Company ABC could improve on.", "answers": ["Avoid giving a long-winded or overly opinionated answer when it comes to questions about company improvement. If you must provide feedback to Company ABC try to draw out an idea that isn't too severe or negative. Always follow your answer up with a comment on what the company is doing right.", "\"That is a tough question because I enjoy what you are doing at Company ABC. If I had to choose one thing I would suggest making your website more mobile friendly. Other than that - I think your branding is great and people love your product!\"", "\"One way I feel that Company ABC could improve, would be to improve your social media presence. Your customers are loyal ones, and I am sure they would love to have an inside peek of your operations and up and coming products.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Do you understand the difference between craft beer and big beer?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you understand the basics of the brewing industry. The biggest battle in the brewing market is often craft vs. big beer. It is best to answer this question in a non-bias manner.", "\"A craft brewer is small, independent, and usually employs traditional brewing methods. A big beer brewer generally has more funds for experimental brews and the retail price is usually a bit friendlier.\"", "\"I am not formally trained in craft beer but am somewhat familiar with the industry from my research on Company ABC. I believe that the primary difference between craft and big beer are the brewing methods, but I do look forward to learning much more!\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire those with an existing knowledge in the beer and brewing industry. Name 3 types of beers and how they differ from each other.", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you bring a real interest to the brewing industry. Display a bit of your knowledge by talking briefly about the three types of beers you are most familiar with and what the most noticeable difference is between them.", "\"The three types of beer that first come to mind are Ales, Stouts, and Lagers. Lagers are the most popular type of beer sold in bars and liquor stores - likely because they have a crisp and refreshing finish. Ales generally come in second to Lagers, as popularity is concerned, because they are heavier. Many people still enjoy the assertive taste of an Ale. Stouts are well known for their darker, creamier taste. They are not consumed as readily as an Ale or Lager but a very popular choice, nonetheless.\"", "\"I have researched the brewing industry extensively, to prepare for this interview. The beers I am most familiar with are Ales, Stouts, and Lagers. Lagers are light and refreshing. Ales are heavier than a Lager, and then a Stout is much darker and creamier.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Environmental responsibility is important to Company ABC. What do you think of our organization's sustainability efforts?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have done your research on Company ABC before attending the interview. You can easily find this type of information on most company websites so take a few minutes to research what Company ABC is doing regarding environmental sustainability.", "\"I noticed on your website that you are currently working on ways to reduce the water use in your breweries. Water is such a valuable resource, so I like to see that Company ABC is making a concerted effort to make a difference in this area.\"", "\"Not all companies are focused on sustainability and the environment. I think that your sustainability efforts are rare and responsible.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Tell me about an organization or group outside of work that you contributed to.", "answers": ["Many hiring managers will choose one candidate over another because of their volunteer experience. They feel that it shows strong character and selflessness...all qualities that make a great employee at Company ABC. Talk to the interviewer about your willingness to give back to your community in some form of volunteerism. If you do not have formal volunteer experience you can draw on things you do in your spare time to assist friends, family, or even your current employer. \n\nIf you do have volunteer experience: \"For the past eight months, I have volunteered every Wednesday evening at our local animal shelter. I will help with grooming the animals, feeding them, and walking them. It's been an enjoyable experience and rewarding at the same time.\"", "\"For the past eight months, I have volunteered every Wednesday evening at our local animal shelter. I will help with grooming the animals, feeding them, and walking them. It's been an enjoyable experience and rewarding at the same time.\"", "If you do not have volunteer experience: \"I have not formally volunteered in these most recent years, however; I spend a lot of time helping my sister who is a single mom. I will babysit on weekends, cook dinners for her and drive the kids to appointments when necessary. I feel that it is imperative to take care of the needs of the family.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Have you progressed in your career as you have expected?", "answers": ["Career progression can be a touchy subject, especially if you feel that your career hasn't progressed as well as you would have liked. Talk to the interviewer about your career progression and what you would like to see in the future with Company ABC.", "\"Overall, my career has progressed a touch slower than I would have liked. I have held a couple of positions that didn't offer the growth and learning that I was expecting; however, I have bounced back nicely. I feel that this particular position would take my career exactly where it should be.\"", "\"I had a pretty specific career mapped out and do feel that I am on track, as expected. I am happy with where my career is right now and would like to see future growth, at a manageable pace, with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Why do you want this job?", "answers": ["What interests you most about working for Company ABC? How will working for them help you to achieve your goals? Recruiters and hiring managers often receive hundreds of applications for the same job. If you are lucky enough to land the interview, make some effort to research the company. Think about how this job will help you in your career. It's crucial for you to know not only what you have to offer them, but what they can do for you. While your passion and excitement for the job are essential, it's always good to have some hard facts to back it up. For instance, \"I have heard great things about your company and I know I would be a great fit for this job,\" is not very specific. \n\nInstead, consider saying something like, \"Your values are very much in line with mine. I deeply care about giving back to the community. I also feel like this job will help me reach my goal of working in a management position, because of the leadership opportunities within this role.\"", "\"I have heard great things about your company and I know I would be a great fit for this job,\"", "\"I would like this job with Company ABC because your product is amazing and I would be so proud to be an employee here. Your company culture offers a dynamic that I have been seeking out, for quite some time.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "At your current or former place of employment, how important was communication and dealing with others?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working in an environment where clear communication with others is vital? Talk to the interviewer about your most recent work and how excellent communication played a part in your success.", "\"In my previous role, healthy communication was required in order to protect the safety of our employees. We transported dangerous goods, and our management required that we all take specific workshops on communication and documentation. Because of this, my communication skills are solid.\"", "\"Unfortunately, healthy communication was a missing element in my most recent position. It is a large part of the reason I decided to seek out a new opportunity. I believe that communication is incredibly important for the success of an organization as well as team morale.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "How do you respond to customer or client complaints?", "answers": ["If you are interviewing for a customer or client facing role, you want to show off your ability to deal with conflict and nurture client relationships. Give an example of a time you helped resolve a customer's issue.", "\"A customer called me very frustrated about a problem with one of our software products. I listened and told them I would be happy to help. I asked more questions to understand the problem and then suggested once I had a better idea of what might solve it. The customer was very relieved and grateful that I took the time to listen and make sense of the issue.\"", "\"If faced with a customer complaint I would spend my time listening to their concerns. Usually, people simply want to be heard. If things escalated to the point where the customer became threatening, I would call a supervisor for help in handling the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "What feedback did you receive at your last job?", "answers": ["Every manager has a different approach to giving feedback. Some prefer to save it for the performance review while others dish it out on the regular. Your response to feedback is much more important than the input itself. Even if it was negative, if you can take it as constructive criticism, you can improve yourself and your skills.", "\"My manager told me that I was spending too much time on the details of a project. I realized that I could be such a perfectionist that I lose track of time and hyper-focus on things that aren't that important. I'm learning to prioritize the steps I need to take and the tasks that need completion when working on a bigger project.\"", "\"I received primarily positive feedback from my previous manager, but one area of improvement that she suggested was to focus more on the details of my documentation. I tend to move onto other tasks before fully documenting the last. I have been working hard on improving that about myself.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "When given an important assignment, how do you approach handling it?", "answers": ["Are you the individual who will approach an assignment head-on, or do you need to research and plan first? Do you jump in and get it all done immediately or do you balance it with other assignments? Talk to the interviewer about how you approach essential assignments at work.", "\"When my supervisor gives me an important assignment or task I am sure to assess the depth of the project then take a look at my schedule to see how I can appropriately balance it with my other work. I do not procrastinate because then it's easy to forget to fit them in.\"", "\"I tend to jump right into a project! Not in a careless way, but in an enthusiastic one. I like to get my hands dirty and get the job going, right away.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "What was your biggest take-away from your post-secondary education?", "answers": ["What was the most significant thing that you learned from attending post-secondary studies? Tell the interviewer what you value most from this experience.", "\"My biggest takeaway from post-secondary education was the level of discipline that I mastered while there. I could multi-task, focus, and think in a completely different way once I had graduated.\"", "\"I learned a lot in the majority of my courses, but I have to say that the greatest things I learned were surrounding my business courses. Economics is of great interest to me, and I learned from some valuable case studies. I believe these prepared me very well for real-life business experiences.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Have you ever been advised by a fellow employee or supervisor to lie about a situation? How did you handle this ethical dilemma?", "answers": ["Ethical dilemmas in the workplace will come up from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you can handle these types of difficulties with professionalism and poise.", "\"I have never been told to lie to a fellow employee or supervisor on the job. If I were to be asked to lie, I absolutely would not do that. I am not the type of personality to be pushed around on the job. I will always be myself and keep my integrity first.\"", "\"I have been asked to lie about inventory counts, in the past. I don't want to say whom or where, but I have worked in an environment where the supervisor was not an honest individual. I ended up leaving the position because I did not appreciate being challenged on my ethics like that. Truthfulness and honesty are essential to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you at Company ABC.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "Try turning your answer into a positive by talking about what causes you to feel the most satisfied, on the job. \n\nFor example: \"I feel most satisfied when I am in a company with like-minded, positive people. I love to collaborate and try new and creative ideas.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "What do you see as the most difficult task in being a manager?", "answers": ["Being in a management role is always a significant challenge. Share with the interviewer what you feel is the most challenging part of being a manager, and why. Also, discuss what you are currently doing to make this task less stressful in the future.", "\"As a manager, the most difficult task for me is to delegate the work evenly. You will always have team members who are absolute rock-stars, then some who are a bit less enthusiastic or are lower producers. I have to remind myself to distribute the work and responsibilities evenly despite my natural inclination to give more work to the high performers. I am currently working with my underperforming team members to prepare them for a larger workload.\"", "\"I think the most challenging part of management is keeping a good balance between being a mentor, and a respected leader. I want to be the type of manager who people can come to when they need help, but also with boundaries when it comes to delegation and performance reviews.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "If you had $50,000 to build your own business, what would you do?", "answers": ["If money was no object, what kind of business would you start? The interviewer will be able to learn something new and unique about you through this question. Avoid answers that would include building a business that competes with the hiring company.", "\"If I had $50,000 to build my own business I would open up a community center in my neighborhood that offered inexpensive childcare, cooking classes, and other life skills programs. I am passionate about volunteering and see a strong need in those particular areas.\"", "\"If I had the funds to build my own business, I would follow my creative passion for music and start a studio where people could take music lessons and rent equipment that they may not be able to afford otherwise to purchase.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"In my next position, I would like to see a slight increase in my salary. An offer between $52-54,000 would be ideal for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "Discuss a time when you went above and beyond the call of duty. What did you do? How was it above your normal job requirements?", "answers": ["Think back to your previous projects in your current or past position. Did you exceed your manager\u2019s expectations on a project by doing additional research to provide more of a polished product? If you are having difficulty thinking of an example from a past project, did you help a coworker out with some of their work? When a new co-worker started, did you volunteer your time without being asked to train them and show them the ropes? Also, try to relate your answer to the position you are applying for to demonstrate your qualifications for this role with Company ABC.", "\"In my current position, I have exceeded my targets and goals by an average of 22% per week. I do this through additional account management duties like making in-person service calls and helping my clients with promotional ideas when their sales are down.\""]}, {"topic": "Brewery", "question": "I'm interested in knowing more about the culture and type of work you are seeking. What is your ideal position at this time?", "answers": ["The type of culture you are looking for will vary based on your field and personality. Every candidate is looking for a positive work environment and growth opportunities, so be sure to stress these aspects in your response. In regards to the position with Company ABC, think of three traits that get you excited about your ideal job and evoke happiness, ideally try and relate it to the position you are applying for to demonstrate to the interviewer how excited you are about the role.", "\"Ideally, I am seeking a role that offers a positive work environment with room for growth through challenging projects and continued training. I work best in a positive team environment where employees are respected and given some form of autonomy.\"", "\"My ideal position will offer me responsibilities such as A, B, and C. I also prefer environments where autonomy is offered, and trust is given. I am a very loyal employee and prefer working in a culture that rewards their passionate and reliable employees.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "When a problem arises, what are your first reactions?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if your reactions to problems reflect maturity and professionalism. How you react will significantly determine how you fit with their existing team. \n\nPerhaps your computer crashes, and you realize you may have just lost all of your hard work. Or maybe you are limited on time and have a deadline rapidly approaching. Demonstrate to the interviewer that you take a very methodical approach to problem-solving, rather than reacting in an impulsive way when a problem occurs.", "\"When a major problem arises, my first instinct is to take a step back and absorb what just happened. I then go into \"", "\"I have taught myself to become much calmer with my first reactions when problems arise. Now, I will step back and review my options for solving the problem rather than allow myself to become frustrated.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "At Company ABC we offer a strong training program. What aspects of training do you feel you need most?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any areas of training that you feel you may be lacking. If you could choose the focus of your training, what would you pick?", "\"If I could choose an aspect of training I would like to learn more about health and safety. My end goal is to gain a leadership position with Company ABC so some training as a team lead would be valuable as well.\"", "\"When it comes to training in the restaurant industry, I feel that I could use more training in the operation of the point of sale systems. I like to fully understand the software programs and platforms that I work with, to ensure efficiency and faster service for my tables.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Have you taken any Food Safety courses?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you have taken any food specific training or certifications? If you are Food Safety Certified, be sure to bring that certification with you to your interview. If you know of any industry-specific certifications required of you, be sure to address those in the discussion.", "\"I have taken Food Safety Level I, II and III. I see that you mention ABC and XYZ in your job posting. I do not have training in these areas; however, I am more than willing to take this training and become certified before my first shift.\"", "\"I am happy to take any food safety courses that you recommend. Because this would be my first position in the restaurant industry, I am new to these topics. With that said, I am very confident in my ability to quickly succeed. Are there any courses I could take to better prepare, while you make your hiring decision?\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Do you have experience in corrective discipline and terminations?", "answers": ["Terminations and corrective discipline measures can be very difficult to do but, with experience, they do get more comfortable. Talk to the interviewer about the extent of your experience with terminations and discipline. \n\nIf you do have the experience: \"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "\"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "If you do not have the experience: \"I have not been in a position to perform terminations or hold corrective discipline meetings; however, I would be willing to perform these types of tasks with a small amount of training and research.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of pride in the cleanliness of our restaurants. How important is cleanliness to you?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have an interest in keeping up their high standards of cleanliness. Give examples of times when you went over and above to meet cleanliness standards in your previous role(s).", "\"I am very concerned about cleanliness as it has everything to do with first impressions, and also the health of your customers. In my current position, I am always the first to notice anything out of place or in disorder. Rest assured, I would be proud to uphold the cleanliness standards at Company ABC.\"", "\"I appreciate that Company ABC has such a strong focus on cleanliness. I have taken some health and safety related courses and am confident that you will be more than satisfied with my standard when it comes to cleanliness.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I cannot recall the exact number, but I think it was around three days total. All absences were excused and with notice.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "How do you handle stress?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I have learned to embrace it.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"My verbal communication skills are strong; however, I would say that my written communication skills are not as strong. I don't have the experience when it comes to email communication, for example. For this reason, I would rate my communication skills as a 7/10.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "At Company ABC, our restaurants are open evenings and weekends. What are your preferred shifts? Do you have any limitations to your availability?", "answers": ["If you have any restrictions on your schedule, it is best to bring this up with the interviewer right away. The restaurant industry is fast-moving and nearly always open. When can the manager rely on you to be there?", "\"My schedule is very open except for Monday evenings. I am able and willing to work overtime, and weekends as well.\"", "\"I am a team player with very few limitations to my schedule. I do have classes on Monday and Tuesday evenings. Other than that, I am available.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "How do you respond to problems that require a quick solution?", "answers": ["When it comes to complex problem solving, decisions are not always readily reached. It takes practice, experience, and confidence to learn what sorts of decisions yield the best results. Walk the interviewer through your process when it comes to making quick decisions. Do you rely on past experiences? Perhaps you go with a gut feeling. Maybe you have read case studies that you lean on in these instances. \n\nProblems that require you to act quickly can be emergency situations such as knowing where the fire extinguisher is and grabbing it fast enough to put out a small grease fire in the company kitchen. Other quick decisions could be if you are asked to take on a new responsibility and are only given five minutes to decide if it's something you are prepared to take on. Going with your gut is a skill, and the more you learn to trust your intuition, the easier it becomes to make these types of decisions. Demonstrate that you are confident and able to react swiftly when the need arises.", "\"I thrive under pressure and always have, so when I'm given a time-sensitive situation to address, I light up and get down to business. I am more impactful and even more creative when I have little time to do much besides jump in and take charge. This ability to make fast decisions is especially helpful in my role as manager when there is an inventory, personnel, or customer issue.\"", "\"I respond well to emergency and fast-moving situations that require intuitive decisions. I was raised to trust my initial response so, I do just that! One recent example was when we had a kitchen fire in my previous place of employment. Many of the staff panicked, but I relied on my training, found the fire extinguisher, put the fire out, and made sure that everyone was okay and uninjured.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "We have some strong competition at Company ABC. What do you think makes us stand out?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know what attracts you to a role with Company ABC. Discuss how this position stands out to you over any others.", "\"I believe that Company ABC stands out above its competitors because it has an incredible reputation for quality food and strong customer service. I'd like to work for an organization that takes quality and service as seriously as you do.\"", "\"Through my research of Company ABC I have found that you stand out most by your great online reviews and unique brand marketing strategies on Instagram and Twitter.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "At Company ABC we put a great deal of value on customer service. How would you describe your customer service skills?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you can meet their customer service standards. Draw on your references or examples of a time when you went over and above for a customer.", "\"Your customer service standards are one of the reasons I was so attracted to your company. I am highly trained in hospitality and am a very attentive individual. When you call my references, they will attest to my great customer service skills.\"", "\"I would describe my customer service skills as consistent, positive, and energetic. As a customer of Company ABC in the past, I appreciate the value you put on customer service.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "At Company ABC we have gained a lot of momentum this year using social media marketing techniques. Do you follow us on Instagram, Facebook, or Twitter?", "answers": ["Before an interview, you should always thoroughly research the company's online presence and, if possible, follow them on social media. This research is also helpful because many companies will post their new openings using their social media platforms. The interviewer would like to know if you are authentically engaged in the Company ABC brand and product.", "\"I know that you have a great social media presence and I do follow your Instagram account. Of course, your posts always make me hungry!\"", "\"I am not involved with social media; however, I can only imagine that your posts are fun and mouthwatering. Should I end up on these social platforms, I will be sure to follow Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "At Company ABC we encourage education and training for our employees. If you could further your education, what path would you choose, and why?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about your education and training and discuss any areas where you would like to expand your knowledge. Keep your answer simple. If possible, keep your reply related to the career path for which you are interviewing. For instance: You want to avoid declaring your desire to be a dolphin trainer when you're applying for a regional sales manager role.", "\"If I could further my education in any way I would choose to expand my knowledge in food and wine pairings. I have always found wine culture to be interesting.\"", "\"I appreciate that Company ABC encourages continued education and training. That's so great to hear! If I could further my education in any way, I would choose to take courses in leadership and management. I would love to end up in a supervisory role later in my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "What do you know about the workplace culture at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you have researched the workplace culture at Company ABC. What do you enjoy about the culture, and how does it align with what you are seeking?", "\"I have spoken to a few people that have worked for Company ABC and they all have great things to say. I am seeking a workplace environment that is collaborative and positive and this role seems like a perfect fit.\"", "\"I have researched Company ABC a great deal, before coming in today. On your website, you mention that you have a collaborative culture with a primary focus on 'service-with-a-smile'. This culture is precisely the one that I am looking to work in.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "The casual dining industry is very competitive and turnover can be high. Why do you want to work for Company ABC over any of our competitors?", "answers": ["Casual dining has a higher turnover rate than many industries, and it's often to no fault of the company. Assure the interviewer that you see a longer-term fit with Company ABC.", "\"I have researched Company ABC and read a lot about your company culture and customer service philosophy. I would choose you over your competitors because your organization seems genuine, honest, and you do what you can to encourage growth in your employees.\"", "\"I want to work for Company ABC first, because you have a well-known reputation for strong management, growth opportunities, and fair pay. I would be thrilled to build a lucrative career with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "How do you manage difficult customers?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can professionally and tactfully handle demanding customers and challenging situations.", "\"I have handled very challenging customers in my previous roles and can remain professional through all situations. When I face a difficult customer, I find that it is usually due to a breakdown in communication. Because I am a strong communicator, I can diffuse most situations.\"", "\"When I have a difficult customer I will try to kill them with kindness. It's often difficult for a negative person to continue being negative when they have nothing feeding the fire in the first place.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Do you see long term career potential with Company ABC? If so, where would you like to see your position go in the next 2-3 years?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the ways that you would like to see your career grow with Company ABC. What type of role would you want to gain in the future?", "\"I would like to see my experience in leadership grow over the next few years. Company ABC has a strong reputation for developing and promoting their employees which is something that I am excited about.\"", "\"I would like to see a long-term fit with Company ABC. If I could grow with your company, I would like to see it turn into a management role that includes a component of human resources. I am currently earning my BA in Human Resources and would love to have an opportunity here when I graduate.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "At Company ABC we handle a lot of cash transactions throughout the day. Do you consider yourself responsible and trustworthy? Give me an example.", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are trustworthy and honest. Speak about times in your career that your employers have relied on you. You can also refer to any positive employment references.", "\"When I worked at Company ABC, I was responsible for balancing approximately 10K in cash every day. There was never a discrepancy. I have solid references who will speak to my honest and reliable character as well.\"", "\"I consider myself honest, trustworthy, and responsible. A great example of my honesty would be the written reference that I have from my most recent employer.  Here is a copy for you.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "When have you been asked to perform a function or complete a task in which you had little or no experience in doing?", "answers": ["Have you ever had to take on a task or a role that you felt was over your experience level? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have dealt with this type of situation. What was the outcome, and what did you learn?", "\"When my manager went on unexpected medical leave for three months last year I was asked to step into her position in the interim. I knew the basics but was certainly not trained on the specifics of the role. I was able to take it on successfully by leaning on my team, reading a lot of company manuals, and asking many questions. Once my manager returned she was very pleased with the progress that I made, and I was promoted.\"", "\"When I was a hostess in my last position, one of our servers called in sick at the last minute on a busy Saturday night. My boss put me into a server role with very little training. It was intimidating, but I felt a rush at the same time. The night was successful, and my tips were a great reward!\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "When you suffer a setback, how does that emotionally affect you and your work?", "answers": ["Everyone handles the stress and disappointment of setbacks differently. Discuss with the interviewer how you typically cope with delays in the workplace.", "\"Experiencing a setback is always disappointing, and can be a bit disheartening, but I understand that it happens from time to time. If I experience a major setback, I will take a few moments to debrief with my manager and discuss what I could have done differently. Then, I move on!\"", "\"I understand that setbacks happen from time to time. I don't enjoy setbacks, but I do take them as a learning experience.  If I face a setback in the workplace, I will often ask for help to recover the time, if a deadline is in front of me. If it's a difficult customer who shook me up, I will take a breather outside for a moment. There is always a healthy way to cope.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["Don't let this question catch you by surprise! After you do your research on the company, write down some questions that came up for you. Next, review the company website, watch videos and read articles and press releases to see if any of those questions can be answered through those resources. Interviewers love to hear intelligent questions about their company culture, the work environment, awards and community involvement. They like to be praised for the ways you are impressed by their innovation, reputation, and impact on their industry. Be strategic with your questions. If you still have uncertainties about the position that needs to be clarified, this is an opportunity to get those answers as well.", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\"", "Here are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in this industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?"]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Are you a leader or a follower?", "answers": ["A good leader takes the initiative, listens and communicates well with others. A good follower is good at following directions and working hard to accomplish tasks. Both have great qualities. Depending on the role, it may be more critical for you to instigate solving problems and creating innovative solutions, or it may be more important to get the work done. Share some of your strengths to show you have qualities in both categories.", "\"It depends on the situation. I am good at listening and following directions, but I am also great with people and working as a team to solve problems. I would say I have qualities of both, and I know I would rise to the occasion if given a leadership opportunity.\"", "\"I can be a follower when necessary; however, I am naturally a leader at heart. I like to mentor others and am a good example to new employees.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Do you think honesty is always the best policy?", "answers": ["Is honesty always the best policy? Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on honesty in the workplace.", "\"Sometimes full disclosure can damage someone's self-esteem, and reality isn't always best expressed in full and can be self-indulgent based on the person's intention. In those instances, honesty isn't always the best policy.\"", "\"I was always raised to be honest so yes - I do believe that honesty is the best policy. It's best, to be honest, and tell the truth whenever possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "We have had concerns with employee theft recently.  What would you do if you caught a co-worker stealing? \n co-worker stealing?", "answers": ["Some businesses have trouble with employee theft, and they need to make sure that they are hiring someone who is honest and trustworthy. Talk to the interviewer about the steps you would take if you caught a co-worker stealing at Company ABC.", "\"I am sure that you have an internal policy for employee theft so I can assure you that I would follow the required steps to report the theft. I am a trustworthy person with a strong track record of honesty with my previous employers.\"", "\"If I caught an employee stealing, I would report the incident immediately. As a previous manager, I understand the value of employee honesty.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Have you ever taken the fall for a situation, where it was really not your fault, in order to protect a coworker?", "answers": ["Taking the fall for a situation, to protect a co-worker, is a tricky situation. It can show teamwork, but it may not be the most honest thing to do. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on taking the fall for something you did not do.", "\"I do not believe in 'taking the fall' for people based on protecting them. Transparency is always a good idea, and if something went wrong, then it needs to be addressed to prevent it from happening again. When it comes to clients, I will apologize on behalf of the company for errors. In that case, I will do what it takes to protect the company's reputation.\"", "\"I have taken the heat for a situation that was not my fault. Honestly, it wasn't anyone's fault, and I understand that sometimes the blame needs to land somewhere when corporate is looking for answers.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "When have you spoken up for cause, knowing that it would directly look unfavorable on you, because it was the right thing to do?", "answers": ["Every manager wants a team player who will not resist company policy or argue about every detail of the workload. However; time may come when you need to speak up about something, and it may not look the best on you. Talk to the interviewer about a time that this may have happened to you on the job.", "\"For the most part, my company abides by all labor regulations. In the case of overtime, they did not abide by the regulations, and I had to speak up for my team. The company was not happy about it because it cost them a lot of money but, in the end, they realized that they were in error.\"", "\"I stuck up for an employee bullied in the workplace. They did not fit in, and perhaps their personality was a bit off-putting; however, nobody deserves treatment like that. My co-workers didn't like being called out, but eventually, they came around. All in all, it was worth it to speak up.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Tell me about a time when you had to lead a team. What was your biggest success factor?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to hear about a time that you led a team, with a positive outcome. The highlight for the interviewer the primary factors that made your leadership style a success. Your example could come from the workplace or perhaps a time when you led a group project during your post-secondary studies.", "\"Just last month I was asked to lead our day shift employees when my boss was away on sick leave. I took charge for two weeks, and the experience was quite positive! I believe the biggest success factor was that I tried to emulate his leadership style and did ask his help when I wasn't sure what to do. I feel this experience prepared me for a leadership role. I am excited to take on a team lead role again.\"", "\"Our company had a contest last month to see who could up-sell the most menu add-ons, and I was asked to be our team leader for the challenge. I enjoyed that responsibility, and we ended up winning the reward in the end because my team increased sales by the highest percentage.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Do you have reliable transportation?", "answers": ["Even if you're not expected to drive for the job, you will need to have some form of reliable transportation. If you take the bus or ride a bike, that works too! Share that you have the means to get to work consistently and on time.", "\"I have reliable transportation. My vehicle is in great condition, and I am comfortable with the amount of travel required to get to Company ABC every day.\"", "\"I take public transit; however, I find it to be very reliable. I was late to work only once last year, and that was due to a snowstorm which stalled all of our employee's commute - including those with personal vehicles. Rest assured, I am reliable and will always come to work on time.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "What do you enjoy doing in your free time?", "answers": ["If you are a part of any organizations, sports teams or clubs, talk about your involvement. Share the role you play and your contribution as well as what you enjoy about it. If you enjoy other activities like writing, hiking or spending time with friends, talk about those too. This question gives the interviewer a chance to get to know you. They are interested in learning about your personality and what motivates you. If any of your outside activities are related to this position, definitely share the skills you have learned and the similarities.", "\"I spend a lot of my free time volunteering at the local animal shelter. I think that it is important to give back to your community, whenever possible.\"", "\"I love to read in my free time and spend as much time as I can doing that. I can be found reading anything from a 19th-century piece of British literature to the latest dystopian fantasy novel. My absolute favorite thing to do is to travel and couple it with reading: on the beach, on the plane, or just read about the cool intricacies of the place I'm visiting.\""]}, {"topic": "Casual+Dining", "question": "Tell me about your experience in training and coaching others.", "answers": ["Coaching and training experience may not be a direct requirement for this role, but they are abilities that are always valued by an employer. Briefly explain the knowledge that you do have in training, and coaching, in the workplace.", "\"In my last position, I trained new hires on how to use our applicant tracking system. It was a very cool experience because it showed me that I love to teach and train. I am good at explaining how things work. It required a lot of patience, but it helped me to recognize my leadership potential.\"", "\"I have been a part of the interviewing and on-boarding team in numerous organizations. Whether I am training formally or not, I am always the go-to for shadowing and mentorship. It's something for which I am very passionate. I love to see others succeed and help them do so. I've done this in each company I've worked for and wouldn't have it any other way. \""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "At Company ABC, we are looking for reliable employees who come to work on time. Do you have reliable transportation?", "answers": ["Even if you're not expected to drive for the job, you will need to have some form of reliable transportation. If you take the bus or ride a bike, that works too! Share that you have the means to get to work consistently and on time.", "\"I have reliable transportation. My vehicle is well maintained, and I am comfortable with the amount of travel required to get to your office every day.\"", "\"I take public transit; however, I find it to be very reliable. I was late to work only once last year, and that was due to a snowstorm which stalled all of our employee's commute - including those with personal vehicles. Rest assured, I am reliable and will always come to work on time.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "At Company ABC, we believe that everyone has leadership capabilities. Do you see yourself a leader? When have you led a team?", "answers": ["Perhaps you have led a club at work, been a coach for a youth sports team, or were on the advisory board for a non-profit organization. You should always be prepared to show the interviewer that you have a natural ability to lead others. Whether you have led a group of 500 or a team of 2, you must display to the interviewer that you are capable of handling the responsibility that comes with being a leader and mentor. \n\nTalk about your desire to be a leader. Share with the interviewer that you strive to be a role model for others. Explain that you jump at the opportunity to lead groups, encourage your counterparts, and be a face of the organization when challenges arise.", "\"In my current position, I am the president of the social committee. I love that I have the opportunity to encourage employee engagement while being a positive influence on the workplace culture. I am a natural leader because I start with leading by example. As a leader, I make myself available to others who need mentor-ship, a bit of assistance in adjusting to their role, or just a listening ear when they've had a tough day. I am confident in my leadership abilities and look forward to joining your team in a leadership role.\"", "\"I see myself as a leader. Not only have I managed a team in two prior roles, but also I believe that leadership does not always equate to management. I am sure to lead at all times by providing the best model, enthusiasm, and work-ethic of the organization. I am open to new ideas and love to tackle a new project which, to me, embodies leadership.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Outside of work, what type of creative activities do you like to pursue?", "answers": ["A genuinely creative minded person will have outside activities aside from what's happening in the workplace. Tell the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you express your creativity.", "\"Outside of work I like to attend dance classes and I also attend the odd paint and sip wine nights at a local wine shop. I also enjoy reading as a way of nurturing my creative side.\"", "\"Outside of work I love to explore my creative side. I practice photography for fun and also hang out with friends. As an avid reader, I try to read one new book per week. I also explore writing.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8.5 because I consider myself a strong communicator. It is the foundation of all success in business. I am always striving to be a better communicator, so I leave the rest of the scale as an aspirational measure.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "As you know, we have a lot of competitors in this industry. Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Researching the company is an essential step before your interview. Part of that research is going to include learning who the competitors are, and why Company ABC stands apart from the rest. Keep your answer to the point, and positive.", "\"The culture at Company ABC is very desirable. You have a reputation for investing in your staff through continued education and incentives which seems to keep your employees engaged. I am also very impressed with the online reviews that I have read. You have a great reputation!\"", "\"I want to work for Company ABC because I have been a patron for many years. I have always been a loyal customer because of the high-quality food and beverages, as well as the friendly atmosphere.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you went above and beyond.", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you can do more than the bare minimum. Show that you can react when you see that your employer has a need that goes beyond your usual day-to-day expectations.", "\"Last week I noticed that my manager had not completed the schedule for the following week. Some of the staff were complaining that they didn't have their work schedule yet. Rather than going to my manager with the complaint, I offered to take on some of her workload so that she would have the time to complete the schedule. We worked together for a couple of overtime hours that day and were able to catch her up on everything. It felt good to help but also benefited me by way of organization.\"", "\"I often go above and beyond what is expected of me. Most recently, I agreed to cover for a co-worker who was on short-term medical leave. I worked 10 hour days for two weeks so that our shop did not suffer any setbacks.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Are you familiar with the types of products that we serve at Company ABC?", "answers": ["It is critical that you research Company ABC before your interview. Take note of their most popular products and any new, or seasonal, products that may have been released recently.", "\"From what I understand you have all of the basics including light, medium and full-bodied coffee's. Your specialty at Company ABC appears to be on hot and cold creations such as coffee and tea-based latte's. I am eager to try your new cold brew coffee this summer!\"", "\"I am familiar with your products! I am a dedicated customer and already know a good portion of the menu at Company ABC. I am very excited to work here!\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "At Company ABC we offer many corporate growth opportunities to our star employees. Where do you see your career with Company ABC taking you?", "answers": ["The coffee industry is booming, competitive, and it isn't going anywhere! Talk to the interviewer about how you see your career growth in this industry. Onboarding new employees is a time-consuming and expensive task. Be sure to express your genuine interest in working for Company ABC for the longer term!", "\"When I was on your website the other day I noticed that you offer store level and corporate level opportunities. I poked around a bit and thought that it would be cool to end up in a human resources type of opportunity down the road. I think your culture at Company ABC is great and I would love to grow a strong career here.\"", "\"This position is perfect for my schedule as I attend University for the next four years. Past my University graduation, I am not sure where I will end up; however, I would love to dedicate these next few years to Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "What characteristics do you feel a good barista will have?", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you have what it takes to be a great barista! First, you should fully understand the requirements to be a barista. You can research the career path as well as refer to the Company ABC website and job description. Keep your answer to the point, and positive.", "\"I see in your job description that you are seeking someone who can multitask, be friendly, and is reliable. In addition to these requirements, I feel that a good barista will be willing to learn new beverages, work well as part of a team, and provide top notch customer service. I do not know everything about specialty drinks but from what I understand - you provide excellent training at Company ABC.\"", "Here are some other skills a barista should have: \n\n- Outgoing personality \n- Ability to do basic math at a quick pace\n- Active listening skills for order taking\n- Strong customer service skills\n- The desire to be around groups of people all day\n- Memorization and strong recall abilities\n- Ability to work well with a team of varying personalities \n- Interest in the coffee shop culture\n- Interest in hygiene \n- Investment in health and safety protocols \n- Patience \n- Dispute resolution skills"]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Walk me through your industry related experience. Which role was your favorite, and why did you leave?", "answers": ["This question is a loaded one because the interviewer is trying to understand the attitude you bring with you to work and why you would choose to leave a position that makes you happy. Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your resume.", "\"I have worked in the customer service / restaurant industry for the past 3 years. My favorite role was with Company ABC because the culture was friendly and collaborative. I only left because I relocated to a different city. I am excited about the opportunity with Company ABC because the culture feels similar. I see a strong fit here.\"", "\"My favorite role was with Company XYZ and; although I enjoyed it, the time came for me to seek a position with a higher wage, and potential to become the manager.  There was minimal growth opportunity there, so I chose to move forward in my career. We parted on great terms and the owner is still an employment reference of mine.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Have you ever come to Company ABC as a customer?  Tell me about your experience.", "answers": ["The interviewer is genuinely interested in your experience as a customer. If you have been a customer at Company ABC, speak openly and positively about your experience. If your experience was not a positive one be sure to handle that tactfully and with substantial discretion. It is important to note that you should always be a patron before applying/interviewing. 'I have never come here' will never be an acceptable answer.", "\"I am a regular customer at Company ABC because your location is convenient, your customer service is always friendly, and your product is consistently fresh.\"", "\"I have not frequented this location often; however, the times that I have come here, I always leave impressed and well taken care of.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "At Company ABC we receive many applications on a daily basis. Why should we hire you?", "answers": ["When answering this question, you always want to refer to what you can do for Company ABC. This question is not about you and your needs/desires. What unique skills do you bring to the organization that other applicants may not?", "\"I understand that you receive many applications every day. I am a stand-out candidate because I have an impressive customer service record. Because I am well versed in the coffee industry, the time required to train me will be minimal. I am dedicated, come with strong references, and can start immediately.\"", "\"I am a stand out candidate because I offer an attitude that fits well with the customer-focused attitude at Company ABC. Also, I am bilingual and able to help your customers in English and Spanish fluently.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "From your understanding of our job posting, what do you feel your primary duties will be with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you fully understand the duties associated with this position. Have you read and absorbed the job description? Do you have a clear understanding of the tasks outlined by the hiring manager during the interview? Assure the interviewer that you will exceed their expectations.", "\"I understand that Company ABC puts their primary focus on personal customer service and quality products. From what I have researched, the primary duties of this role will be to represent Company ABC proudly through excellent service. This responsibility includes preparing beverages correctly the first time, ensuring that cleanliness is kept in the shop and keeping inventory levels accurate.\"", "\"I have read through the job posting in details and feel that my primary duties will be to prepare beverages, greet the customers, and handle transactions accurately. Are there other expectations, in this role not outlined in the job posting?\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "At Company ABC we want to be the best in the coffee industry. Where do you think we could improve?", "answers": ["The coffee industry is a competitive one, and the interviewer would like to know that you have put some thought into where Company ABC stands in comparison to their competitors. Perhaps you have a minor suggestion for improvement? It is excellent, to be honest; however, be sure to keep your answer light and end on a positive note.", "\"I am a coffee addict and have visited Company ABC many times! Your shop is truly one of my favorites. The only suggestion I would make is to increase your stock of breakfast pastries. Many times I will arrive around 10 AM, and you are sold out. It simply means that your product is great and sells out!\"", "\"I have seen a few local coffee shops use an app where customers can place their order ahead of time, even paying and tipping on the app, to avoid having to wait in line. I think it's a great idea for anyone in a hurry to get to work, or for someone with a large order. Something like that could be cool for Company ABC to create at some point.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "At Company ABC we have very high standards when it comes to food safety. Have you ever taken any food safety or hygiene related courses?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any related training that you may have had, whether it be a formal or on-the-job experience. If your training is listed on your resume, take the time to re-review it briefly. Assure the interviewer that you have an interest in helping them to uphold the high standards at Company ABC.", "\"In my previous role, I was trained on-the-job in regards to food health and safety. I was tested regularly as well. A few years ago I also completed my Food Safety Training Certificate from our local community college. I fully understand the importance of food safety and will uphold the strong standards at Company ABC, if hired.\"", "\"This would be my first position within the restaurant industry so at this time I am not trained or certified in food safety. If  you could provide me with some recommended courses, I would be happy to get a head start on my training!\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Thank you for spending your time interviewing with Company ABC. I realize I have asked you a lot of questions. Do you have any questions for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in this industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking! Yes, I do have a question for you. When we were speaking earlier about scheduling and my availability, I was wondering if your schedule stays the same from week to week or if you offer a range of shifts to all of your employees?\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "At Company ABC we have had previous concerns with employee theft. How would you handle it if you caught an employee stealing?", "answers": ["In a high-volume retail and customer service environment, it can be challenging to stay on top of inventory and cash. This question is a great time to ask the interviewer if Company ABC has a loss prevention program and protocols in place for employee theft. If you have experience with inventory management, staff management, or employee termination - this is a great time to discuss!", "\"If you could tell me more about your loss prevention efforts at Company ABC that would be great. In my current position, we have protocols in place for reporting employee theft. Our Corporate office has formally trained me on loss prevention. Since becoming a Manager in my current role I have dealt with one employee theft case which resulted in their termination.\"", "\"I am sure that you have an internal policy for employee theft so I can assure you that I would follow the required steps to report the theft. I am a trustworthy person with a strong track record of honesty with my previous employers.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "If a customer complained that you gave them incorrect change, what would you do?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have training in essential customer service and cash handling tasks. Most organizations will train you to confirm with the customer the bill amount they are handing you. Some businesses will also prepare their customer service representatives to leave the original cash amount visible to the customer until you complete the transaction. Assure the interviewer that you understand these loss prevention methods and that you can perform well in uncomfortable situations.", "\"In my current position I have been trained to avoid this situation entirely by leaving the cash visible (out of the till and on the counter close to me) until I have provided the customer with their change. I will also confirm with the customer the bill type they have given me. For instance; if they hand me a $20 bill, I will say out loud 'from twenty?'. They will then say yes - confirming that we are both on the same page. These methods help me to avoid customer issues surrounding cash discrepancies.\"", "\"I have not experienced an event like this; however, I do know that in cash based scenarios it is always best to leave the original bill outside of the till, visible to the customer, until the transaction is complete. This method also prevents employees from being scammed by fake customers demanding change for their $50 bill when, in fact, it was originally a $20.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "At Company ABC we are open 7 days a week. We may schedule you for early mornings, evenings, weekends, and holidays. Are you able to offer flexibility in your schedule, or do you have restrictions?", "answers": ["When you work in the customer service industry, you should expect to have different hours. If there are some restrictions on your schedule, this is the time to discuss with the interviewer. Be firm about your limitations but also offer some flex in return.", "\"I am happy to work the majority of shifts; however, I do take morning classes on Mondays, Wednesdays, and Fridays. I am available to work the later shift on those days.\"", "\"I have no restrictions on my schedule and am happy to be a team player by taking any shifts you need. I am also eager to work so I can take many overtime shifts and some holidays.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "When have you been asked to perform a function or complete a task in which you had little or no experience in doing?", "answers": ["Have you ever had to take on a task or a role that you felt was over your experience level? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have dealt with this type of situation. What was the outcome, and what did you learn?", "\"I am often asked to perform tasks outside of my wheelhouse. These tasks include customer dispute resolution and interviewing potential new employees. I am a diverse employee and am happy to take on additional functions.\"", "\"Because I am new to my career, I have not had much experience with this.  However, I am adaptable.  I will use all available resources and research possibilities to find out what I need to do and how to do it.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Where do you see yourself a year from now?", "answers": ["It's impossible to know where you will be in years to come, but assure the interviewer that, given all possible circumstances, you could see yourself as a long-term fit for their position.", "\"Ideally, one year from now, I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with Company ABC goals which help me to see a great long-term fit here.\"", "\"One year from now, I would like to be supervising or managing a team of my own. I feel like I am progressing at a rate that will make this a possibility.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "How does this position with Company ABC fit into your career goals?", "answers": ["Is this particular position a good fit? Is it a step up in your career or - a stagnant move that you are just complacent with taking until something better comes along? Assure the interviewer that this position will be challenging for you, is a step up in responsibilities, and that it fits with your overall career goals.", "\"My primary goal in my career, as a barista, is to eventually work my way into a position where I will train new staff. I feel that Company ABC offers a strong path towards that goals and I am excited about what this position has to offer.\"", "\"My primary career goal is to find a position where I can stay long term. Because Company ABC has such a strong reputation for workplace culture, it fits perfectly with my desires for a long-term fit.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Describe your leadership qualities.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know what you consider to be strong leadership qualities. When describing leadership qualities, try to avoid general terms and give some unique ideas. \n\nA great leader is someone who people naturally want to follow. They have exceptional interpersonal skills and the ability to build relationships with nearly any personality type. A respected leader will take ownership of their mistakes and will always lead their team by example. True leaders see the importance of motivating others and recognizing even the smallest achievements. With which of these qualities do you most identify?", "\"I have taken a handful of workshops and courses to improve my leadership skills this year. My leadership qualities are best summed as dedicated, attentive, and motivating. I like to recognize my employees' small wins because that motivates them to continue achieving.\"", "Here are some other leadership qualities: \n\n- Integrity\n- Passionate about success\n- Ability to inspire others \n- Strong focus\n- Honesty and transparency \n- Unwavering confidence\n- Willingness to present new ideas\n- Patience while training others\n- Authentic, friendly, and approachable"]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "How would you describe your personality?", "answers": ["Personality and character are two very different things. The interviewer is looking for more information on your traits vs. your integrity. These traits should include buzzwords such as introverted, energetic, and confident.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive. I believe that, if asked, my colleagues and supervisor would say the same about me.\"", "Here are some descriptive personality words: \n\n- Adventurous\n- Calm\n- Determined\n- Energetic\n-Flexible\n- Honest\n- Imaginative \n- Meticulous\n- Organized\n- Persuasive \n- Resourceful \n- Talkative"]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Days can sometimes be stressful at Company ABC. How do you handle stress on the job?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I cannot recall the exact number, but I think it was around three days total. All absences were excused and with notice.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "List the top 3 skills that you have acquired in your last role, that will help you in this position with Company ABC.", "answers": ["You have likely gained many valuable skills in your career. Share with the interviewer which skills you value the most. Be sure to include capabilities that will potentially benefit this potential new employer.", "\"In my last role, the top 3 skills that I acquired were customer service, stronger communication skills, and transaction handling.\"", "Here is a list of hard and soft skills that you may have acquired along the way:\n\n- Software or Hardware \n- Computer Programs\n- Languages\n- Listening Skills\n- Feedback Acceptance / Providing Feedback\n- Assertion \n- Negotiations\n- Decision Making \n- Diversity Awareness"]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "On a scale from 1 to 10, how honest are you?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you are a sincere person or do you have room for growth? This question could be a tricky one as nobody is always 100% honest. Answer to the best of your ability and back your reply by speaking about your ethics.", "\"I would love to give myself a 10/10 for honesty but truthfully - nobody is 100% honest all of the time. I will give myself an nine because I always do my best to be as honest as possible.\"", "\"I was brought up to be an honest individual, at all times, no matter the personal consequences. With that said, nobody is honest 100% of the time. For that reason, I would rate myself as a 9/10.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have their particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "\"I have felt dissatisfied on the job when I feel underpaid and overworked. I don't mind working hard at all, but I don't like to feel as though I'm being taken advantage of.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "Have you ever had to fire an employee? What were the reasons for their termination?", "answers": ["Terminating an employee is never a task that people like to do. Talk to the interviewer about how you go about employee terminations. What does that conversation usually look like?", "\"I have had to terminate employees in the past, yes. These terminations generally stemmed from missed targets or insubordination. I find it challenging to terminate employees because you do care about them and their well being. I have to remind myself that I did absolutely everything that I could to ensure their success but, I cannot carry the full weight.\"", "\"Unfortunately this is a part of wearing your management hat. I recently had to separate employment with someone who was under-performing.  We coached the employee in question, offered additional learning experiences and worked with them on a performance improvement plan. It was the right person in the wrong role, and we had to decide to move forward.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $25,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $29,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $12/hour with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "How would your favorite teacher or professor describe you?", "answers": ["Talking about yourself can be challenging, especially for your first interview. Your favorite teacher is someone who recognizes your hard work and your talents. They may be impressed with your writing and communication skills, how well you work in groups, and your enthusiasm. If you have spent any time one-on-one with your teacher and received feedback, share what you have learned from them. Talk about how they noticed your strengths and helped you to develop them. Your perseverance, kindness and hard working spirit are all great qualities to share in your interview.", "\"My favorite professor always said that I was very disciplined and attentive. I took that as a great compliment because he was a very focused personality as well.\"", "\"One of my professors gave me a huge compliment of asking me to research and edit his book after I graduated, as a contributor to his research project. So, not only does he think that I am a great writer, but he also trusts my project management skills, researching, and editing skills. He also knew this would be on top of my 9-to-5, so he knows that I can take on any task no matter what the obstacles may be.\""]}, {"topic": "Coffee+Shop", "question": "At Company ABC, we value accuracy and a job well done. Do you always double check or proofread your work?", "answers": ["Double checking and proofreading are essential parts of a job well done. Assure the interviewer that you are diligent when it comes to submitting good, clean, work.", "\"Spelling and grammatical errors are a pet peeve of mine. I will triple check my work if there is time! I feel that it is essential to submit error-free work.\"", "\"I try to, but in today's quick response age, I know that I send emails with typos on occasion.  I concentrate very well on reports and presentations, and I do ask other people to review important letters or emails before sending them.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Describe for me your ideal coworker.", "answers": ["Workplace culture is a critical factor for Company ABC to consider during their talent acquisition process. It is the responsibility of the hiring authority to ensure that your personality will be a good fit for their existing team. It is also your responsibility to ask questions to discover if their work environment meets your needs. \n\nDiscuss the personality traits that you admire, ensuring that your answer remains positive and focused on the characteristics that you enjoy seeing in your teammates. This question is not the time to be negative or list off the type of people you don't like. Remain positive!", "\"I have had the pleasure of speaking with a couple of people from Company ABC and so far everyone seems incredibly welcoming and friendly. My ideal coworker is helpful, knowledgable, and puts care into their work. I enjoy close collaboration and am the type to jump in and help when needed. I appreciate reciprocation when it's needed.\"", "\"I find it very motivating to be surrounded by people who are passionate about their job and their company. My ideal coworker is positive, eager to grow, willing to help, and engaged with their team.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "What types of products fall under the dairy category? Of these categories, where do you believe Company ABC is the strongest?", "answers": ["The hiring authority is checking to see what you know about Company ABC and their product lines. To answer this question correctly, you will have to do some research on their website and recall the information that you have read. Next, think about which of these product categories is a stand out for Company ABC, compared to their competitors.", "\"Dairy products include milk, cheese, ice cream, butter, yogurt, and any other foods produced from the milk of mammals. I believe that of the multitude of dairy categories, Company ABC stands out in the cheese department. Your selection is unique and affordable. For instance, I make sure to have Product A in my fridge at all times!\"", "\"For a product to be considered dairy, it must be produced from the milk of mammals such as cows and goats, or even camels! I consider yogurt, milk, cheese, butter, and ice cream to be the most commonly purchased dairy items. Where Company ABC stands out the most is in your ice cream line. You have unique flavors and use organic cows milk, which is highly enticing to a health-conscious consumer like me.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Walk me through a significant decision you made at work, and the impact of that decision. Was there a positive outcome?", "answers": ["Think to a time when you were asked to take the lead in your job. How did it feel to be the decision-maker? Were you successful and able to help out your team or company by making the right call? The interviewer wants to see that you can take on decision making with confidence. \n\nIf you come from a management position, this question will be easier to answer than if you are not in a management role. With that said, it's important to remember that even non-formal leadership positions do require leadership action now and then.", "\"In my current position, I was asked to source new potential shipping partners. I performed a lot of solid research, considering a multitude of factors such as quality of service, pricing, and reputation. Once my management team chose a shipping partner from the shortlist that I provided, we actively tracked financial savings and customer satisfaction. After six months, we saw that the change gained us many more 5-star customer reviews, and saved us around 20,000 in fees.\"", "\"When my manager is not around, it is up to me to make customer-service based decisions such as accepting returns and giving refunds or further mark-downs. I am sure to be calculated, keeping excellent customer service delivery top of mind while also noting that the decision cannot be harmful to my company's bottom-line. I am skilled at taking a disgruntled customer and turning their refund request into a simple exchange; saving my company a lot of money.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Who are Company ABC largest competitors? Have you applied to any of these companies?", "answers": ["You must understand the landscape of the dairy industry and the competitors of Company ABC before going into your interview. The more research you perform, the better you show the hiring authority that you are engaged in the interview process and keen on their specific industry. \n\nMention two to three of their largest competitors, and if you have taken an interest in applying for any open positions. This question is an excellent opportunity for you to solidify precisely why you are choosing to apply for a job with Company ABC.", "\"From the research I have done, I believe that the biggest competitors of Company ABC are (A), (B), and (C). Company A, in particular, has many similar products; however, they have fewer plants across the country. In this marketplace, Company ABC stood out the strongest because of your high employee satisfaction scores and your commitment to the health of your customers.\"", "\"As an animal lover and health enthusiast, it is crucial to me that I join a company whose core values align with mine. Your organization has a strong history of due diligence, respect for animals, and putting out products with only the finest ingredients. Your biggest competitors, Company A, and Company B are also esteemed organizations; however, I am much more impressed with the corporate commitments made by Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "How have dairy alternatives impacted the dairy industry over the past few years?", "answers": ["Plant-based dairy alternatives are continuing to grow in demand and selection. The interviewer wants to see insight into these trends, and how you believe Company ABC can best guard against the potential of lost profits.", "\"Plant-based diets are increasing, and more consumers are coming out with sensitivity to lactose-based products. It's more important than ever to meet the needs of those diet requirements. I read in a recent report by the USDA that Americans drank 247 pounds of milk in 1975 to just 149 pounds per capita, today. I believe the best effort to combat this is for every major dairy company to invest in a milk alternative. It's important to bring variety and participate versus ignoring the trends and hoping for the best.\"", "\"With the introduction of milk alternatives, milk went from the only healthy choice to the unhealthy alternative very quickly. To combat this, many dairy companies are purchasing smaller non-dairy milk producers and joining in on the competition. I believe there will always be people who want real milk, and it's important to focus on delivering the best possible options for those consumers.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "There are trends to follow in every category of food production. What do you believe is the latest trend in dairy?", "answers": ["Every food category has trends that come and go, and the hiring authority would like to know which trends you believe are up and coming in the dairy industry. The way that you answer this question will show the interviewer if you have done your research on their industry before your interview. If you come from the dairy industry, your response will show the interviewer your depth of knowledge.", "\"Hands down, the biggest trend that I have noticed this year has been in flavor experimentation. Flavors are beginning to answer the demands of adventurous customers, and are better reflecting the multiculturalism in our country. We now see alcohol-infused flavors such as rum ice cream, and merlot-infused cheeses. I believe this trend will continue for some time to come.\"", "\"Reducing sugars, without leaning on artificial sweeteners is one exciting trend that I have noticed lately. Consumers want dairy products that offer exceptional taste without the guilt. More consumers are becoming health-conscious and trends such as the keto lifestyle and leading the way of these demands.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "What concerns do you have working in the dairy industry, or for Company ABC?", "answers": ["You must keep any concern somewhat light. If you have grave concerns about working for Company ABC or in the dairy industry, chances are, this is not the right place for you. It's essential to have a question, or two prepared, such as: \n\n- What was the biggest struggle for the previous person in this role?\n- What do you expect to be the biggest hurdle for me, if hired?\n- What do you expect to be the biggest challenge forCompany ABC in the next three years? \n\nThese inquiries are thoughtful without being negative.", "\"I am interested in learning what you foresee as the biggest challenge in this role, in the first six months. I want to start on the right foot, completely prepared for the challenges that come with starting a new career in a complex industry.\"", "\"I am hoping you could share with me the struggles that the dairy industry is facing this year? Be it regulation changes or product shortages; I would like to come prepared for all challenges in this role.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "List for me some of the sub-brands under the Company ABC name.", "answers": ["The answer to this question is not complicated, but it will take some research. Many large food companies have smaller brands that offer more niche products. Do some online research on Company ABC to see what you can uncover. You may find that they have sub-brands available in other countries, or brands that are available in discount stores versus premium grocery retailers. Keep your answer to the point and brief. If you have tried any products under a different Company ABC brand, be sure to mention this!", "\"Research tells me that your business manufactures a variety of brands such as (A), (B), and (C). I have tried a couple of flavors of yogurt from (C) and found them to be unique and delicious. I understand that this organization has a range of profit-driving brands, and I am excited to learn more throughout this interview process.\"", "\"I was surprised to see the number of brands and products from :company! It's great to see that your product lines are so diverse. I have tried milk products, yogurts, and cheese from a variety of your brands without even realizing it.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "How do you prioritize when everything seems to be equally urgent?", "answers": ["Have you ever had one of those days when it seems that every task is taking your attention? Perhaps sometimes you feel frozen; unable to know what steps to take next? Prioritizing may seem simple, but it's a difficult skill that takes practice to master.  \n\nWhen prioritizing your work, it's important to mark down every task that needs attention. You may want to rank each task from 1-5 as far as urgency, deadline, or stakeholders. Others choose to list each job based on the due date, estimated value, or amount of time needed from start to completion. \n\nShow the interviewer that you have a thoughtful system in place to help you better prioritize, making you a highly valuable and productive member of Company ABC.", "\"I am always asking myself what is next, and keeping lists of tasks ranked by their financial impact and the amount of time they will take to complete. I started to utilize 'Wrike,' a project management software that helps me to categorize tasks and track what stage of completion they are in, adding timestamps to my work. The system also alerts me when milestones are approaching.\"", "\"I organize my work based on the overall urgency and time required for the project. This information often comes with guidance from my management team. I keep a 'to-do' list of what I need to accomplish before the end of the day, and I never leave until I have checked off every item on my list. It's important to me that I never begin my day feeling behind the 8-ball, so to speak.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "The dairy industry has many stages, including producing, processing, transportation, packing, and merchandising. Which stage of our business interests you the most?", "answers": ["No matter the role to which you are applying, the interviewer would like to know which aspect of Company ABC interests you the most. Dairy production, processing, and distribution are multi-faceted, and there is a lot to learn. The more you know about the company's overall operations, the more successful you will be in your position. If you had the opportunity, which stage of their process would you want to learn?", "\"I find food production and manufacturing fascinating and would like to learn all of it, over time. If I had to choose just one area of focus, I would pick production. A lot of the questions that I get from customers and retailers in my current role is related to how we produce our products. The more I know, the better.\"", "\"My education background is in transportation and logistics so, of course, I would first want to learn everything that I can about how Company ABC operates product transport. Your volume is significant, and it's important to me that I understand the logistics that go into getting your products out on time and efficiently.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Tell me about a time you went above and beyond your job description. What did you do, and what was the impact?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are the type of person who will readily go above your job description for the benefit of Company ABC. Employees who say, 'That's not my job' or 'That's above my pay scale' are rarely successful long term, and often fail to achieve promotions or significant career growth. \n\nThink back to a time when you readily exceeded expectations. Maybe you helped a coworker accomplish a goal. Perhaps you stayed late to meet a deadline. Or, maybe you filled in for a co-worker when they were away unexpectedly. Be prepared with a brief story that spotlights your excellent attitude!", "\"We introduced a new SAP system this year, and many of my coworkers were struggling with the change. I am tech-savvy and also love to teach others how to embrace new technology in the workplace. I offered to hold a series of lunch and learns over four weeks, helping to address common questions and concerns regarding the new system. I am still the go-to person on the floor when it comes to questions on the system. I believe this help has made us more productive, ensuring that our documentation is up-to-date and that our less tech-savvy employees still feel supported.\"", "\"I go above and beyond to make all of our new hires feel comfortable. It can be scary to walk into a new office, and a friendly face can make a big difference in employee retention during the first three months. Just recently, I noticed a new production worker looking lost and uncomfortable. I sat down with her and asked her if she had any questions. We had lunch together for a few days until I saw that she was feeling more at home. I believe she would have quit the job if she went too long without making a personal connection with someone.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "What will Company ABC be able to offer you that your current organization cannot?", "answers": ["If you are currently employed, your reason for leaving will be valuable information for the interviewer to uncover. A careful hiring authority will be sure that they can fulfill your career needs before extending a job offer. The most common reasons for someone to quit their job include feeling a lack of autonomy, lack of recognition, little respect, few opportunities for growth, and being underpaid. \n\nWhen explaining your reasons for moving on, you mustn't bash your employer or speak poorly of your coworkers. Be less emotional and more factual, keeping your answer to the point. Explain, in a positive tone, what you hope to gain in your next position.", "\"My current employer is a small family-owned business, and I have come as far as I can without buying into the company. I am ready to work for a larger organization such as Company ABC where there are opportunities in a variety of departments in multiple locations. I feel that I could truly tap into my potential at Company ABC and that excites me.\"", "\"My current position has been great for me; however, they are not able to offer me more than part-time hours for the time being. I started as an intern and am very thankful for the opportunity they awarded me right out of university. With that said, I am ready for a full-time opportunity where I can be paid fairly and have the opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "What qualities will make you successful in this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["This question is another way of asking 'Why should we hire you?' or 'Why are you the best candidate for Company ABC?' Think about the skills listed in the job description or job posting, and which of those skills best match with your experience, personality, and characteristics. Then, mention around three qualities that Company ABC is looking for, that describe you very well.", "\"In the job posting for this role, Company ABC mentions giving preference to candidates with formal education in business, customer service experience, and someone who can thrive in a highly diverse work environment. I have my Bachelor's degree in Business Administration and have been in a customer-facing position for the past five years. I have built excellent relationships with my client base over the years. My client base and my work environment both offer challenging situations where I must readily embrace diversity to succeed. These qualities and many others will ensure my success in this role with Company ABC.\"", "\"You mentioned during our telephone interview that finding reliable employees s a common pain point in the food industry. My work history and tenure speak to my level of loyalty and dedication. You will not be disappointed in my work ethic. I hope that my dedication would influence my teammates along the way. Over time, as I earn my way into a leadership role, I could influence my team members to work hard and strive for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "List for me a few of the products made available by Company ABC.", "answers": ["This question is pretty straightforward as the interviewer is asking for you to list a few of the products they offer. You can perform this basic research by reviewing the Company ABC website, or doing a quick online search. If you have used any of the products that you mention, be sure to share which ones are your favorite!", "\"My favorite food is cheese, cheese, and more cheese! I know that Company ABC has a multitude of dairy products including your broad line of mozzarella. I have tried many of your specialty cheeses, such as ricotta, provolone, blue, parmesan, goat cheese, and romano.\"", "\"From my research, it seems that your top-ranking products include your line of American-style cheeses, organic butter, and your broad range of cows milk. I purchase your organic, lactose-free milk on a regular basis. It is my absolutely favorite.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "How would you leverage your skills to improve operations at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Of course, Company ABC is already a well-oiled machine when it comes to their everyday operations. This question is another form of asking what your most significant strength is, and how it would benefit Company ABC should they hire you. Take the time to comb through the job posting or job description. Which skills do you possess that are a strong match to the needs of their organization?", "\"I understand that your biggest goal for this position is to maintain the quality standards that your customers have come to expect from Company ABC products. I am a highly detailed individual with formal education in product quality analysis and compliance. I am also skilled in quality control technologies, ensuring that I can quickly repair quality issues and also see potential issues before they occur.\"", "\"I am a fast learner who can take the training information given to me and apply it effectively. I will leverage this skill to learn my job faster than expected, ensuring that I am a productive member of the Company ABC team very quickly.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "What sets Company ABC apart from other dairy product producers, marketers, and distributors?", "answers": ["This question is similar to, 'Why do you want to work for us?' The hiring authority wants to hear a unique answer that is well thought out. Typical responses such as 'I like your workplace culture' will not do here! Show that you have done specific research on what it means to work for Company ABC. You can refer to their company core values and mission statement or some employee reviews that you have read online.", "\"I have researched Company ABC and your competitors extensively. I understand that you have a further reach into health-based products. I appreciate that a lot of your research goes into topics such as diary and pediatrics, gut health, and the benefits of milk enzymes on cognitive function. I want to join a company that is more than just a producer, but also a thought leader in the dairy industry.\"", "\"I researched Company ABC and your top four global competitors before making my application. The employee reviews for your organization are second to none. You have the highest employee satisfaction rates on Glassdoor. In addition to this, you also have the widest product range and happiest customers. I would be very proud to say that I work for Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Product quality is of utmost importance to Company ABC. How will you contribute to our strict quality control standards?", "answers": ["Company ABC has a firm commitment to quality, and this commitment drives their global success. To achieve the highest quality standards, all of their employees need to bring 100% dedication to the cause. Every stage of food manufacturing and distribution comes with strict compliance standards and GMPs (Good Manufacturing Practices). Talk to the interviewer about how you will ensure that you exceed these standards.", "\"I believe it's essential to have a robust quality assurance program. In my current position, I was part of the quality assurance team that contributed to the re-writing of our QA program and policies. My part included completing sections on the thorough inspection of incoming materials, more frequent inspections, and analytics that everyone could understand. When the entire team can understand corporate goals, the quality of a final product will always be better.\"", "\"I will contribute to Company ABC quality control standards by fully understanding your GMPs and learning how to exceed these standard protocols. I will readily take feedback from the QA team and comply with all SOPs provided to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "How important is the dairy industry for our country's agriculture sector?", "answers": ["Milk is produced in all 50 states and is one of the most significant contributors to the agriculture landscape in the United States. In other countries, dairy is a huge producer, contributing to jobs all around the world. \n\nDairy is more than just milk, too! Dairy products include milk beverages, cheese, butter, ice cream, yogurt, dry milk products, condensed milk, and even whey products. Think about how vast the dairy sections are when you enter your favorite grocery store. The interviewer would like to see that you have an idea of how significant the dairy industry is and that you understand the full potential that could come from working for Company ABC.", "\"The dairy industry is worth billions of dollars in the United States. Dairy production occurs in every single one of the 50 states. I believe that dairy is an unstoppable force and an incredible contributor to the country's agriculture sector. I am thrilled to be interviewing with Company ABC because the thought of working for such an esteemed name in the dairy industry means a lot for my career.\"", "\"Is it vital for our economy that the US dairy industry remains strong. As of now, we see dairy production across the entire country, and the industry itself contributes billions of dollars to our economy. You will find dairy products in nearly every US household; from milk to butter, ice cream, yogurt, and more. The dairy industry and its success is a critical arm of US agriculture.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "How can Company ABC improve the quality of our dairy products?", "answers": ["Company ABC is not looking for you to reinvent the wheel. The interviewer wants to see that you have keen attention to detail and that you care about the quality of product delivered to every customer. Provide your recommendation tactfully. Perhaps you have an idea to improve packaging, boost the visibility of product in-stores, or a new flavor of ice cream to add to their product line.", "\"Company ABC produces some of my favorite dairy products. I am always happy with the quality of my purchase. My only suggestion would be to expand the flavors of ice cream that you offer. For instance, I would love to see some throwback flavors from my childhood, such as cherries jubilee, tiger tiger, and bubble gum!\"", "\"My suggestion has more to do with the packaging of some of your cheese products. I would love to see Company ABC embrace the movement away from plastic, and into compostable packaging for your shredded cheese line. I believe that better packaging offers the appearance of a more premium product while also attracting the attention of consumers who are eco-conscious.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "What is the PMO, and how do they impact dairy operations in the United States?", "answers": ["PMO is short for Pasteurized Milk Ordinance. In the United States, the PMO governs the rules and regulations around milk. The purpose of the Pasteurized Milk Ordinance is to ensure that no milk-bourne diseases break out. 46 of the 50 states have adopted the national standards of the PMO. These standards cover issues related to production, processing, and packaging of milk and milk products. Briefly explain what you understand the PMO to be, showing the interviewer that you have an understanding of regulations in the dairy industry.", "\"PMO is short for Pasteurized Milk Ordinance. The PMO makes and enforces rules surrounding the production and sales of milk products. Their involvement is crucial in the USA because it prevents milk-borne disease and outbreaks.\"", "\"I was recently reading about the PMO and their important involvement in the milk industry within the United States. PMO is short for Pasteurized Milk Ordinance. At this point in time, around 46 of the 50 states fall under the rules and regulations set by the PMO. The remaining states have their own governing bodies.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "How do you successfully interact with challenging customers or coworkers?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how you interact with customers or coworkers who may have challenging personalities or significant demands. Think back to a client whom you can never seem to please fully. Maybe you have a coworker who is incredibly brief in their communication. Showcase your ability to work harmoniously with people who may have different communication styles from yourself. This question is not the time to speak poorly of a boss, coworker, or client. Focus your answer more on what you do to turn a challenging situation into a positive one.", "\"I am very flexible in my approach when I face a challenging individual. The most difficult person I ever worked with was my boss a few years back. She was not receptive to new ideas; however, she did have a lot of approaches that were tried and true. I tried to make recommendations but quickly realized that she would only listen when she saw an element of what she knew included in the pitch. I started to pitch ideas that piggy-backed on our old way of doing things. This approach was an excellent workaround, and we collaborated well for many years.\"", "\"If I come across a challenging customer or coworker, I continue to be my genuine self. People often come around when they feel the warmth and acceptance from the other person. If someone is especially difficult, I will approach them about the situation and ask how they feel we could better collaborate.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "This role with Company ABC requires flexible work hours. Are you willing to work overtime, if needed?", "answers": ["In many regions, an employer cannot demand that you work more than 44 hours per week. However, in some industries and job titles, you may be required to be on-call, work evenings, weekends, holidays, and overtime. This requirement is especially true in a production or logistics environment. \n\nBefore answering scheduling questions, make sure you are crystal clear on the expectations in this role. You can ask to see a sample schedule, or you can ask the hiring authority to outline the hours for you. If you can get the schedule expectations in writing, even better. \n\nIf you cannot work overtime as often as Company ABC would like, rather than saying you cannot meet their needs, focus on what you can do. It's much better to discuss your abilities upfront rather than committing to a schedule that won't work for your lifestyle and other commitments.", "\"I understand that roles within food production and distribution can have long hours, and I am ready to be a team player. I am looking to retain my current schedule of 8-5pm Monday through Friday, and every other weekend. Of course, should an emergency come up, I am more than willing to be a team player. Could you share with me more about the scheduling expectations at Company ABC?\"", "\"I'm accustomed to working overtime, evenings, weekends, and even some holidays. I am flexible and dedicated to being a reliable team member. My current company offers overtime and holiday pay. Do you offer these incentives at Company ABC as well?\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Tell me about your experience working in a cross-functional or cross-departmental environment.", "answers": ["Company ABC has many different business units and many more job functions. In your role, you will be required to collaborate with and work alongside a variety of people with unique working styles and priorities. If you have worked for a larger organization in the past, you may bring a fair amount of cross-functional or cross-departmental experience. Your ability to work harmoniously across the board will be a great asset to Company ABC. \n\nIf you are newer to your career, try discussing a time when you had to collaborate on a group school project. You could also talk about a volunteer experience where you worked well with others towards one common goal.", "\"I have worked in a cross-functional setting for many years. In my current position, I often collaborate with human resources, finance, and marketing. I speak with at least five different stakeholders every single day. When operating in this type of environment, the most important factors are timely communication, clarity on expectations, and mutual respect.\"", "\"My current company is family-owned and operates pretty flat for the most part. I have worked in team environments while attending university. Group projects were always a welcome challenge because I enjoyed learning about everyone's strengths and then leveraging those to ensure smooth project delivery. I am prepared and ready to expand my career into a more diverse work environment that includes communication with a variety of stakeholders.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "How would you react if a customer asked you about a Company ABC product and you were unsure of the answer?", "answers": ["You will not always have the answer to every single product-related question at Company ABC. The interviewer wants to see that you are willing to find out what you need to while admitting when you don't have the correct response on-hand. \n\nShow that you are an independent and confident thinker, able to find answers to questions on your own. Explain that you would take the time to find a solution, rather than saying 'I don't know.' You can also show the hiring authority that you are not too proud to ask questions of your co-workers when needed.", "\"When a customer has a question that I cannot answer, my response is always, 'I am happy to find out!' In the food industry, factors such as ingredients and product offerings are always changing. I will research the answer, or ask a more tenured coworker before I give out incorrect information. I do embrace the opportunity to learn, and I like it when customers ask challenging questions of me.\"", "\"If a customer asked a question that I was unsure of, I would be transparent and let them know that I would have to do some research and find out. I would make the customer feel great by reinforcing the fact that their question was in-depth and insightful. I would also thank them for asking a complex question and challenging me as a Company ABC ambassador. I have no trouble admitting when I don't know something. I would source the answer as quickly as possible by utilizing resources provided to me or asking a more experienced coworker.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Tell me the most valuable lesson you have learned this year.", "answers": ["As a curious and effective problem solver, you must seek out opportunities to learn and grow. When you see problems as lessons, rather than roadblocks, you can succeed in the workplace where others may not. Show the hiring authority that you are an excellent fit for Company ABC by being a proactive professional who is eager to learn and grow. Keep your example work-related.", "\"Product development is constantly shifting, especially in the food production industry. The most valuable lesson that I have learned this year is to never rely on one product to be your big money maker. In the food industry, consumers are always seeking out the next great thing, so we have to be doing the same. Success never stops trying, and it is the key to leave your consumers saying, WOW every time.\"", "\"I had a customer who was upset about their product delivery. To quickly fix the relationship, I failed to listen to their grievances actively. As a result, I misunderstood what the customer wanted to see as a solution. The lesson I learned is to slow down, ask questions, and never assume what someone else is thinking.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "What interests you, outside of work?", "answers": ["It's essential to Company ABC that they hire people who will fit with their culture, and share the same core values. One way to assess 'fit' is to ask what you're all about! Your hobbies and interests outside of work say a lot about you. Your response will show the interviewer that you can maintain a healthy balance between your personal life and your career.", "\"I thoroughly enjoy being in the kitchen and trying my creative hand at new baking recipes. My son and I keep a list of recipes that we want to try and then tackle a new one every weekend. This past week we made churros, which were more challenging than I thought they would be. I also enjoy reading, biking, and going to music festivals.\"", "\"I am a very social person, and I like to remain physically active. I belong to a kickboxing gym and just started learning Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu. I also have a passion for the outdoors. Getting fresh air in the evenings and weekends ensures that I come to work with a clear head every Monday!\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Talk to me about your level of reliability. How often are you late for work, or unexpectedly absent?", "answers": ["The interviewer needs assurance they are hiring a reliable team member able to meet the needs of their busy organization. An essential part of being a diligent employee is arriving to work on time and being present when expected. Talk to the hiring authority about your record of being a reliable team player.", "\"I was raised under the adage, 'If you aren't 10 minutes early, you are late.' I show up to work when I am scheduled and rarely take a sick day. When you call my current place of employment for a reference, you will hear from them that I have taken just two sick days in three years. I am very dedicated to my employer and my fellow teammates.\"", "\"I have taken one sick day this year, which came with a physicians' note. Even then, I did what I could from home on my laptop to prevent my work from falling onto my coworkers. I have reliable transportation and aim to be at least 10 minutes early for every shift.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Tell me about your formal customer service training.", "answers": ["Company ABC is customer-service centric in everything that they do; ensuring happy customers receive what they expect. Talk to the interviewer about any formal customer service training you have received. This training could be in the form of an onboarding plan, on-the-job training, coursework, or even books that you have read or podcasts you have tuned into. Show that you are keen on delivering exceptional service to Company ABC customers.", "\"Over the years I have given and received extensive customer service training. Currently, I train the basics of customer service excellence to our new hires. Additional coursework has included a few Dale Carnegie courses including 'How to Win Friends and Influence People in Business' and 'Attitudes for Service.'\"", "\"I have not yet received formal customer service training; however, I have read many books and articles, and listen to a lot of podcasts geared to developing the right attitude for top-notch customer service. I have learned how to exude a friendly willingness in every customer interaction. This self-led learning has taught me about self-awareness and how to ask the right questions.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Working in a customer-driven environment requires a great deal of patience. Do you consider yourself a patient person?", "answers": ["Working for Company ABC; whether in a customer-facing role or not still requires a solid understanding of the customer journey, and patience with that journey. If you are patient, you will be thoughtful in your words, and be observant by nature. You are slower to react on impulse, and you make calculations before responding in emotionally challenging or heated situations. Show the interviewer that you can stay professional and patient in any situation.", "\"Any times when I have felt impatience creeping up is due to frustration with my performance. For instance, if I am finishing a project slower than I think I should be. I am highly professional and have never lost patience with a customer or even a co-worker. Everyone is entitled to their opinion, and I am happy to entertain a variety of needs and viewpoints.\"", "\"One of my favorite books is 'The Power of Patience' by M.J, Ryan. I learned a lot from this book, including how being patient can accelerate our success in business while also adding feelings of personal fulfillment. Of course, I am always a work in progress, but overall, I do consider myself to be patient with my customers, coworkers, and management.\""]}, {"topic": "Dairy", "question": "Are you stronger with verbal or written communication?", "answers": ["Your communication style and strengths will be an essential factor when considering your fit for this position and with Company ABC, overall. Be sure to exude confidence in both your verbal and written communication efforts. Your ability to communicate shows maturity, professionalism, and career competence. Try to give a balanced answer and include a bit on what you are doing to improve your verbal and written communication skills.", "\"I recently joined Toastmasters to improve my verbal communication skills and ability to present to groups of people with confidence. My writing has always been solid, and I understand business etiquette best practices for formal writing such as RFPs and informal writing such as emails.\"", "\"I am pretty balanced when it comes to verbal and written communication. Both forms of communication are equally important. Choosing just one, I would say that written communication is my preference because it is easy to choose your words carefully, and I can look back at written communication for reference.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of pride in the cleanliness of our restaurants. How important is cleanliness to you?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have an interest in keeping up their high standards of cleanliness. Give examples of times when you went over and above to meet cleanliness standards in your previous role(s).", "\"I am very concerned about cleanliness as it has everything to do with first impressions, and also the health of your customers. In my current position, I am always the first to notice anything out of place or in disorder. Rest assured, I would be proud to uphold the cleanliness standards at Company ABC.\"", "\"I appreciate that Company ABC has such a strong focus on cleanliness. I have taken some health and safety related courses and am confident that you will be more than satisfied with my standard when it comes to cleanliness.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Choose a dessert from our menu and sell it to me.", "answers": ["This question serves two purposes. One, the interviewer is looking to see if you have researched their menu before your interview. Two, the interviewer is checking to see if you have the ability to upsell and romanticize the menu items enough to have a customer choose a dessert before asking for their bill.", "\"Your cannoli are to die for, so I would have no problem selling them to you. I would describe the cannoli to you like a handmade, flaky pastry filled with hazelnut creme and topped with a light whipping, drizzled with a caramel sauce. Mouthwatering.\"", "\"When presenting the dessert menu, I always say to my table, 'You can never leave dinner without something sweet.' It entices them to at least take a look and see if anything catches their eye. On the Company ABC menu, your seasonal cheesecake has never let me down, so I would sell the cheesecake to you by describing its flavors and letting you know that it's as good as Grandma makes.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "How do you feel about promoting a new menu item, or upselling, during every customer interaction?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you would be comfortable taking a customers' order and turning it into an opportunity to add on menu items or upgraded beverages. If you have a specific example of a time when you made this happen, this is an excellent addition to your reply. Be sure to mention any training that you have in sales, upselling, or a similar skill.", "\"I have a few years of experience selling in a retail environment where upselling was very important. I am fully comfortable putting in some extra time to turn a customer order into a bigger sale. For instance, I could recommend a larger drink or an additional side dish.\"", "I believe that each customer service interaction should be considered an opportunity to upsell or turn an order into a larger one. I am very comfortable doing so when I can stand behind the quality of the food items that I represent.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "How do you handle a rude, picky or upset customer?", "answers": ["In the restaurant industry, you will come across customers who are rude from time to time. This is par for the course for any service based job. Are you able to brush it off when a customer is extra picky, or do you take it personally? Assure the interviewer that you can keep your composure when it comes to demanding customers.", "\"I have spent the past few months working in a retail environment. I no longer take it personally when a customer is picky or difficult. I will do my best to make them happy, but I fully understand that you cannot please everyone, all the time.\"", "\"I handle an extra-choosy customer with utmost care! I listen, and do my best to deliver above their expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "What is your favorite menu item at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking to see how well you have researched the menu at Company ABC before coming into your interview. Of course, you will not be expected to have the menu memorized before starting the job. It is crucial that you take some time to get to know the food offerings. This knowledge will show the interviewer that you are engaged and interested in working for them. If you have dined at Company ABC before, tall the interviewer which dish is your favorite. If you have not eaten there before, then discuss which item seemed the most mouth-watering to you.", "\"My favorite item from the menu is your Braised Beef Bolognese. It's the perfect comfort food and reminds me of my grandmothers' recipe. I order it nearly everytime I come to eat at Company ABC.\"", "\"There are many great meals available at Company ABC. If I had to choose one, I would pick the Five Cheese Ziti al Forno. It sounds cheesy and delicious. I look forward to trying it!\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "How much money do you think this role should pay?", "answers": ["This question is a less abrupt way for an interviewer to ask about your earning expectations. There can be a wide range of earnings among employees in the family restaurant industry; perhaps because of minimum wage expectations differing between regions, but also because some people are excellent at tipping, while other guests may not tip at all. On the odd occasion, a restaurant may also have a no-tipping policy in place. When asked about your earnings, you can give an example of what you are currently earning, or provide a minimum baseline of what you would accept.", "\"I am currently paid $11.10 per hour plus tips, earning an average of $19 per hour. This amount is okay for me; however, I am looking for a role with greater earning potential - whether that be more shifts, a higher hourly rate, or both.\"", "\"I often see that high-performing servers can feel undervalued when it comes to tip outs. In my current role, my customers' tips range from 10-15%. I am seeking a role in a family restaurant with an elevated ambiance and customer base, that will allow for a higher earning potential.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "What do you know about the workplace culture at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have researched their organization before your interview. Company culture and fit is a critical factor when considering a career move. Assure the interviewer that you have put thought, research, and consideration into how the culture at Company ABC will work for you.", "\"I know that Company ABC has a great reputation for hiring and supporting local university students while they work their way through school. I have a friend who worked at your York location last year, and she said it was one of the best service positions she had ever held. I look forward to learning more about the culture here.\"", "\"Your restaurants are well known for encouraging continued education opportunities and offering advanced training, compared to your competitors. I appreciate your focus on employee development and cannot wait to learn more!\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Company ABC values our customers. Do you agree with the phrase 'The customer is always right'?", "answers": ["'The customer is always right' has been a long-standing mantra for service-based organizations. Do you agree with this mantra? Why, or why not? The interviewer would like to see you respond positively. If possible, take a look at the company website to see what their mantra or customer service statement is.", "\"Although I believe that the customer is not always right - it's important to treat them as though they are. Within the limitations of health and safety, etc.; I believe it's best to accommodate the customer within reason.\"", "\"Some customers are quite impossible to please so I would not go so far to say that the customer is always right. With that said, I do treat every customer with the utmost respect and do put their needs first in all reasonable situations.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Have you ever volunteered?", "answers": ["Did you know that, according to LinkedIn research, 1 in 5 hiring managers prefers to hire candidates with volunteer experience? This question is an excellent opportunity to discuss how you are involved in your community and that you commit time to help others. If you have volunteer experience, you have a leg-up on other candidates. \n\nMany non-profit organizations have a long onboarding process with background checks and references required so if you need to gain volunteer experience pronto, here are some options for a quick turnaround: \n\n- Raise money for a cause, like the Red Cross\n- Donate blood on a regular rotation or organize a blood drive \n- Have a craft or bake sale to raise funds for a charity close to your heart\n- Run in a charity race where financial pledges are required\n- Advise high-school and University students on a crowd-sourced advice platform like CareerVillage\n- Write articles for non-profit organizations, for free\n- Sponsor a business owner in a third world country using a platform like Kiva.org\n- Volunteer at your church camp\n- Clean up a local park\n- Volunteer to tutor a student \n- Foster animals for a rescue society", "\"I currently volunteer every Saturday at the local animal shelter. I help to organize adoption applications and also screen the applicants. It feels great to help out, and it melts my heart when we make a perfect pet-parent match.\"", "\"I saw on the Company ABC website that you have a few community events, where you serve hot meals to the less fortunate. I am very interested in becoming involved in these efforts. I agree that volunteer work is vital to my growth as a professional and as a person.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "How would you respond to a customer who wanted to send their food back?", "answers": ["Oh, the woes of working in the service industry! Whether you work at an upscale restaurant or a fast food establishment, you will come across customers now and then, who are difficult to please or take advantage of you or your restaurants' hospitality. Company ABC will likely have procedures in place for situations such as this. You can refer to previous training you received, and discuss with the interviewer how you would react. This question is not the opportunity to go on a tangent about terrible customers. Keep your answer to the point and present your solution.", "\"I come from the school of thought that the guest is always right. This philosophy means that no matter how far into their meal they are - they can send it back. Now, with that said, if the person is a repeat offender I may approach the situation differently. Do you have a policy in place for this type of situation?\"", "\"If the kitchen did not prepare a guests' meal correctly, I want to know. I believe the only way to get better is to learn from constructive criticism, no matter how frustrating it may be in the moment. The customer is always right, but I will ask questions so that I can repair the situation rather than just put a band-aid on it.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "During slow times in the restaurant, what would you do to keep yourself busy?", "answers": ["It's essential that you can keep yourself busy, even during downtime. Restaurants will almost always have ebbs and flows when it comes to the volume of dining traffic. Peak times for most restaurants will be the hours surrounding breakfast, lunch, and dinner. Some of the tasks you could take on, during the slower times include: \n\n- Ensuring glassware is clean\n- Polishing silverware \n- Making utensil rollups \n- Offering to take inventory\n- Wiping down sticky menus \n- Working on your menu knowledge \n- Check the bathrooms for cleanliness or potential issues \n\nShow the interviewer that you are resourceful and motivated to work!", "\"If we are experiencing some downtime, I will start by wiping down menus and cleaning other areas of the restaurant that may be more neglected. I will offer to help a co-worker with a task or will memorize more of the menu. It's important to me that I always keep busy on the job.\"", "\"It's essential to me that I keep myself on the go and useful. If the restaurant is experiencing a slower time, I will make utensil rollups, and polish silverware. I will also do additional cleaning or ask the bartender if I can assist with cleaning glasses or cutting the drink garnishes.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "The family restaurant industry is highly competitive. What do you think makes Company ABC stand out?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know what attracted you to this role, to begin with, and what prompted you to apply. Perhaps you prefer their menu, the ambiance, the clientele, or even the location. Your reason could also include their flexibility in hours, or that you heard their servers earn better tips that most of their competitors. Discuss how this position stands out to you over any others, and exactly why you want to work for Company ABC.", "\"I believe that Company ABC stands out above its competitors because it has an incredible reputation for quality food and strong customer service. I'd like to work for an organization that takes quality and service as seriously as you do.\"", "\"Through my research of Company ABC I have found that you stand out most by your great online reviews and unique brand marketing strategies on Instagram and Twitter. I understand that you are planning to launch ten more locations in our city over the next couple of years. I could learn a lot when it comes to rapid growth, which is also enticing to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["With many options in the family restaurant industry for employment, why do you want to work for Company ABC? Talk to the interviewer about your preference for their company. Dig deep when it comes to your response, bringing up specifics related to their menu, the shifts available, employment awards they have won, or their company mission.", "\"Since I am a university student, it is important to me that I join a company that will be flexible around my hours, and support my goal to finish my degree. Also, I have read a lot on your tuition reimbursement program for top performers, and it intrigued me. I look forward to joining an organization that supports its employees wholeheartedly.\"", "\"I especially want to work for Company ABC because I have friends who have worked here previously, providing me with positive feedback on their experiences. I am looking for a positive work environment where I can stay for a long time to come. Also, your menu is delicious so it's food and quality that I can easily get behind!\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "We offer great training at Company ABC. Which areas do you feel you need the most training?", "answers": ["Chances are, Company ABC is well aware they will need to train you before you are a great performer. What the interviewer would like to know is where you feel you are the weakest, and where they will need to jump in the most when it comes to your training. Talk to the interviewer about any job-related areas that you feel you may be lacking.", "\"If I could choose an aspect of training I would like to learn more about health and food safety. My end goal is to gain a leadership position with Company ABC so some training as a team lead would be valuable as well.\"", "\"When it comes to training in the restaurant industry, I feel that I could use more training in the operation of the point of sale systems. I like to fully understand the software programs and platforms that I work with, to ensure efficiency and faster service for my tables.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Delivering excellent customer service is of utmost importance at Company ABC. How would you describe your customer service skills?", "answers": ["To deliver excellent customer service you need first to recognize the skills that you have and play off of those. If you are naturally not a smiley person who give hugs, then being a smiley person may come off as fake. Think about your natural personality and how you can use those characteristics to deliver stellar service on the job.\n\nSome skills you may have are:\n\n- Patience\n- Empathy\n- Adaptability \n- Knowledge \n- Thick skin\n- Networking", "\"As a server, and former retail sales associate, I believe in the importance of having thick skin. I come across a huge range of clients with varying needs in a day. Some are polite, and others are not.  My ability to resist stress is one of the reasons why I excel in the area of customer service and dispute resolution. I can put my feelings aside and get down to the basics of what my customers need from me to be satisfied.\"", "\"Your customer service standards are one of the reasons I was so attracted to your company. I am highly trained in hospitality and am a very attentive individual. I would describe my customer service skills as genuine, friendly, and always a step ahead. When you call my references, they will attest to my great customer service skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Company ABC has gained a lot of momentum using social media marketing techniques. Do you follow us on Instagram, Facebook, or Twitter?", "answers": ["Before an interview, you should always thoroughly research the company's online presence and, if possible, follow them on social media. This research is also helpful because many companies will post their new openings using their social media platforms. The interviewer would like to know if you are authentically engaged in the Company ABC brand and product.", "\"I know that you have a great social media presence and I do follow your Instagram account. Of course, your posts always make me hungry!\"", "\"I am not highly involved with social media; however, I can only imagine that your posts are fun and mouthwatering. Should I end up on these social platforms, I will be sure to follow Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "In this role, you will be responsible for cash transactions. Do you consider yourself a trustworthy and honest person?", "answers": ["In the restaurant industry, you could be completing dozens of transactions per day, many of them being cash exchanges. Can you be trusted with money when it comes to counting correctly, giving the right change, or making bank deposits after your shift? Draw on the strength of your references and assure the interviewer that you are a trustworthy and honest employee.", "\"One of my greatest strengths as an employee is my level of honesty and trustworthiness. I have multiple references who will attest to the fact that I am competent and honest. I have experience handling large amounts of cash and credit card transactions, without a single discrepancy.\"", "\"I see myself and trustworthy and always honest. My integrity has never been in question, and my most recent manager will be happy to give you a solid reference regarding my reliability and transparent approach in the workplace; whether that be with a high volume of cash transactions or a large bank deposit at the end of the day.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Tell me about the last customer service skill you learned.", "answers": ["It is essential to a hiring company that you are someone who is willing to learn new skills. Being eager to add to your professional repertoire is an excellent way to stand out from the competition. Some new skills related to customer service can range from linguistic to communication, to software capabilities. If there is a skill that you want to learn, and have not yet taken advantage of, you can mention your interest.", "\"The last customer service skill that I learned included a course on dispute resolution management. I feel this course helped me a great deal when it comes to my confidence level, and working with disgruntled customers. I would like to take the advanced level of this course, as a follow-up.\"", "\"I recently took a 'Communication for Managers' workshop and am thrilled with the outcome, and everything that I learned. Not only did I pick up some new customer resolution skills but I have added to my talent retention capabilities as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Referring to the job description, what will be your least favorite part of this job?", "answers": ["This question is an opportunity for you to discuss a little more in depth about how you might handle some of the challenging aspects of the role. All jobs can have frustrating moments. To show you have some knowledge of the difficulties you may encounter, share one hesitation you may have, related to the job posting or job description. If this is your first time in the workforce, you might not know all of the different problems to anticipate in the restaurant industry. If you're not sure, ask.", "\"I believe that working on satisfying unhappy customers will be the most challenging aspect of this role. My experience in customer service has helped me understand how to listen, empathize and deal with conflict. I feel confident I can do the same in this role.\"", "\"I would never want to enter into a job thinking that there are things I would dislike. However, as a realist - I understand that there may be situations that I don't particularly enjoy. If I had to choose a particular part of the role that I may dislike it would probably be the customer dispute resolution. I am confident in my abilities with dispute resolution, but I don't particularly love it.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Are you a leader or a follower?", "answers": ["You may not have held a significant leadership role in the past; however, the interviewer is referring to your character and nature as a leader vs. practical experience. Robin Sharma says 'Leadership is not about a title or designation. It's about impact, influence, and inspiration. Impact involves getting results; influence is about spreading the passion you have for your work.'\n\nWith that said, keep in mind that it is not a negative thing to be a follower. You may not be the person to take charge of a situation or command a room, and that is okay! A good follower is good at following directions and working hard to accomplish tasks. Rodger Adair says, 'A follower shares in an influence relationship among leaders and other followers with their intent to support leaders who reflect their mutual purposes.' A follower is an incredibly vital role to play. \n\nBoth have great qualities. Depending on the role, it may be more critical for you to instigate solving problems and creating innovative solutions, or it may be more important to get the work done. Share some of your strengths to show you have qualities in both categories.", "\"My role as a leader or follower depends on the situation. I am good at listening and following directions, but I am also great with people and working as a team to solve problems. I would say I have qualities of both, and I know I would rise to the occasion if given a leadership opportunity.\"", "\"At this point in my career, being just out of high school, I would say that I follow the lead more often than I take the lead. I am a sponge and ready to learn from those more experienced than I. With that said, I can be a leader when the time is right.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "How many tables are you able to manage at one time?", "answers": ["Depending on the size of the restaurant, you may handle anywhere from 4 to 8 tables, an average of 16-32 guests. If you have previous restaurant experience, discuss the average amount of tables or people that you are accustomed to serving at one time. If you do not have any restaurant experience, you can ask the interviewer questions regarding how they train and prepare their new servers to handle peak volumes.", "\"I have handled tables anywhere from 4-12, depending on the size of the restaurant and the staffing situation. Could you share with me the average section size at Company ABC?\"", "\"I can commit to excellent customer service, and efficiency, up to approximately 30 guests. In my current role, that is around 6-8 tables. How large are the sections that you assign to your servers?\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "All employees must abide by our dress code. How do you feel about the Company ABC uniform?", "answers": ["Before your interview, you should have an idea of what the dress code or uniform looks like at :company.: You may have questions such as, if you are expected to purchase your outfit, or if it will be provided to you. Also, footwear is an essential factor as well. Will you be allowed to wear comfortable and healthy shoes, or does the restaurant expect you to wear heels, for instance. It is okay to ask questions regarding the uniform. The interviewer will want to hear; however, that you will comply with the dress code.", "\"I am happy to comply with your dress code. I have seen the uniforms, and they look professional yet easy to work in. Will I be expected to purchase my uniform, or will it be provided to me?\"", "\"I have worn a uniform in my previous roles and am certainly willing to comply with your dress code requirements. Is the uniform provided to me, or will I be asked to purchase it?\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "How often should you ask a guest if they have a food allergy?", "answers": ["You will learn a lot about managing potential food allergies in your training with Company ABC; however, the interviewer would like to see that you have enough common sense to know that asking about food allergies is a critical step when it comes to responsible food service. Show the interviewer that you understand this to be important.", "\"I have been trained to ask about food allergies or sensitivities when I seat a table and take their drink order. Then, I again ask about food allergies and sensitivities when they order their food. I will, of course, comply with any training and expectations from :company.\"", "\"Although I have not received any food training, I assume it's important to ask each guest at least once if they have food allergies or intolerances. Is this correct? I look forward to receiving further training from Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "How would you react if your friends came in to eat and asked for a discount on their bill?", "answers": ["The restaurant industry often falls victim to a loss of revenue due to employee dishonesty and unapproved discounts. Assure the interviewer that you are trustworthy and would not succumb to peer pressure.", "\"The food and beverage offered at Company ABC is not mine to discount or give away. I would only give a discount once my manager approves. I believe that discounts should be offered when a situation needs to be repaired.\"", "\"Friends who expect to come into my work and receive a discount are probably not great friends! I understand that there are rules and expectations surrounding discounted items. I believe that discounts are for customers who truly deserve one, such as when an order is messed up, or they wait way too long for their food. I would never discount a bill without expressed permission from my boss.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Do you have any preferred shifts?", "answers": ["When working in the restaurant industry, you may be asked to take a wide range of hours. Many family restaurants are open from morning to night, seven days per week. Talk to the interviewer about your availability. If you are not available on particular days, take the time to better outline your schedule with the interviewer.", "\"I am a university student, so my preferred shifts are evenings and weekends. Once school is out in June, I can take any shift available.\"", "\"My hours are wide open right now. I would be happy to take a range of shifts, and work with your needs here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "This position requires you to work around children. Will you agree to a full criminal background check?", "answers": ["Pre-employment background checks are very reasonable requests in the family restaurant industry. A responsible employer will take the time to properly vet you for a role where you are working around children. Assure the interviewer that you can pass a criminal record check. If you have a criminal record, this is the time to disclose it.", "\"I am happy to participate in a full criminal background check. I have a clean record.\"", "If you do have a mark on your record: \"I will disclose to you that I received a DUI in 2014 but do not have any other marks on my criminal record.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Company ABC likes to hire individuals who want to grow with us. Where do you see yourself in 2-5 years?", "answers": ["Interviewing, hiring, and onboarding is an expensive and time-consuming endeavor for any company, but the restaurant industry has an exceptionally high turnover rate compared to many industries. The interviewer wants to know that, if engaged, you will see this as a longer-term fit. Discuss your career plans, goals, and how those fit with what Company ABC is offering. Describe your passion for this opportunity, and what you like about the company for which you are applying.", "\"You can see in my resume that I have strong loyalty and tenure. My career plans include growing with Company ABC in a management based role as I prove my skills. I would be happy to find a long-term fit here.\"", "\"2-5 years from now, I would like to be supervising or managing a team of my own. I feel like I am progressing at a rate that will make this a possibility, and your training program will help to accelerate my professional growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Do you have reliable transportation?", "answers": ["Even if you're not expected to drive for the job, you will need to have some form of reliable transportation. If you take the bus or ride a bike, that works too! Merely share that you have the means to get to work consistently and on time.", "\"I have reliable transportation. I have a well-maintained vehicle, and I am comfortable with the amount of travel required to get to your office every day.\"", "\"I take public transit; however, I find it to be very reliable. I was late to work only once last year, and that was due to a snowstorm which stalled all of our employee's commute - including those with personal vehicles. Rest assured, I am reliable and will always come to work on time.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "Tell me about your experience with Point of Sale systems.", "answers": ["The point of sale (POS) systems that you have experience in may, or may not be listed on your resume. The interviewer is looking for an idea of the systems and programs that you have used before.\n\nSome common POS systems include: \n\n- Toast POS\n- Square POS\n- Lightspeed Restaurant \n- TouchBistro \n- NCR Silver", "\"I have approximately eight months' experience with Square POS. I picked up the system very quickly and believe that I could learn your system quickly.\"", "\"The bulk of my POS experience is with Lightspeed Restaurant systems and TouchBistro. I can learn how to use any system that you require.\""]}, {"topic": "Family+Restaurants", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the queries you have are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers for from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in this industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What does your training schedule look like, should I be the successful candidate? Also, when are you hoping to make a decision?\"", "\"I would like to ask if there is anything in my background on which you need clarification? Also, after discussing everything today, is there any particular reason why I would not be the best fit for this shift manager role?\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are being noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "\"I am motivated by knowing something about the end customer and being able to relate to them as a person. A personal touch is always helpful for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "How would you handle an issue with a policy or procedure?", "answers": ["Being adaptable to the food and beverage industry is essential. Company ABC strives to keep up with their customers by improving their products, making changes in policies or procedures inevitable. This means policies can change quickly and you will be expected to adapt. The interviewer wants to hear how you will respond when you disagree with the way something is handled or executed.", "\"I would first talk with my manager to make sure I understood the expectation correctly. It could be that I was interpreting it wrong or that there was some miscommunication. If I still had an issue, I would take some time to think about how I can deal with it. I've learned to pick my battles and to be adaptable as much as I can.\"", "\"I know well enough at this point in my career that policies and procedures are in place for a reason. If I truly don't understand the reasoning behind the policy, I will ask for further clarification in a respectful and open-minded way.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "It's important for shift changes to go smoothly at Company ABC to maintain productivity. How do you make sure transitions are seamless?", "answers": ["Shift work can be tricky in the food and beverage industry. If someone leaves a mess or if they leave their work half finished and you don't know where to begin, you can waste valuable time scrambling to pick up the pieces. Company ABC doesn't want to waste any time during shift changes, because time is money. Give an example that demonstrates that you are mindful of the transitions.", "\"When I worked as a merchandiser, I was part-time and shared the responsibilities with a team of four people. I took time to explain what I was working on to my co-workers whenever I had to end my shift in the middle of a project. I also left notes that were easy to understand and kept my workspace tidy.\"", "\"Strong scheduling is the most important factor in ensuring transitions are seamless. In addition to solid scheduling, is everyone's willingness to jump in and help when volumes are higher than average or when staff is shorter than expected.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "What challenges do you anticipate in this new role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Interviewers at Company ABC want to hear that you understand the job description and are capable of navigating challenges at work. To build their confidence in your ability, talk about the challenges you expect based on your knowledge of the position and your experience. Then offer up an example of how you have dealt with problems in the past.", "\"I am looking forward to using my experience as a sales associate to help increase product visibility and exceed sales quotas at Company ABC. I am motivated by the challenge of meeting strict deadlines for client demands. When I was working for my previous company, I prioritized listening to customer needs and making sure I was clear on client expectations. I was so meticulous about details, checking my numbers at the end of every week and ensuring my clients were fully stocked with all of the products they needed.\"", "\"Because this is a new industry for me, I am expecting that the biggest challenge will be in learning the industry lingo, behaviors, and complex needs. I am excited to learn and have already started studying up on industry-related topics.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "What are some of the challenges that the food and beverage industry face today?", "answers": ["With the increase in food allergies and the increase in knowledge of things like hydrogenated oils are bad for your health, the food and beverage industry faces the pressures of keeping the public happy while staying true to their products. Do your research before the interview to make sure you are aware of some of the challenges within the industry. You may want to review press releases or news articles about Company ABC to learn about any recent events or challenging situations they are facing.", "\"I am impressed by the way your company has adapted ABC product for individuals with gluten intolerance. I know that the increasing awareness of these types of allergies and auto-immune diseases is taking a toll on the sales for some companies because people are becoming so health conscious. It's great to hear that you are so competitive within the industry, always taking an innovative approach to making changes to ABC product.\"", "\"I believe that the biggest challenge that the food and beverage industry faces today is the fast-changing trends in food and beverage. Everyone is working so hard to come up with the latest and greatest thing that it's very challenging to remain a trailblazer in the market.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "How would your co-workers describe you?", "answers": ["This question gives you an opportunity to show off your best qualities. Take a moment to reflect on your relationships with your co-workers. Company ABC is looking for individuals who are strong communicators and innovative leaders. Think about how your work ethic had a positive effect on everyone on your team.", "\"My co-workers respect me for my ability to navigate obstacles and solve problems. When I am working on ABC project, I always pay close attention to detail, double checking my work for any mistakes. My co-workers appreciate that I think about the big picture, being considerate of how my work will affect their jobs. I am highly collaborative with a great attitude.\"", "\"All of the colleagues I have worked with have shared a very respectful relationship with me. We have shared the goals and knowledge required to accomplish our projects the best we can. I believe that my current co-workers would best describe me as collaborative and creative.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "Tell me about a time when your actions resulted in greater efficiencies of your team.", "answers": ["Teamwork is essential when working in the food and beverage industry. To ensure that products meet quality standards at Company ABC, teams within every department must cooperate and communicate effectively. The goal is always to keep customers happy. Share a time when you made a difference on your team.", "\"When I was working as a brand ambassador for a local snack company, I moved quickly to unload and organize the products. I noticed that by keeping products organized, we were able to save some time preparing and setting up for events. I made a point to keep all products to make the distribution process go much more smoothly.\"", "\"I am a very organized individual so when I was asked to help with the team schedule; I was very excited to make a difference! I was able to reduce a significant amount of overtime, and eliminated split shifts all-together.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "What is your greatest strength? How will it help you make a difference at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer at Company ABC would like to know your stand-out skills and where you put the most value when it comes to your offerings as a candidate. Think of the traits that have helped you succeed in the past. You can draw from your experiences in school or activities if you lack in work experience.", "\"I have great people skills, and I make a point to be positive to help boost morale when other people on my team are struggling. I'm a good listener, and I work hard to manage conflict with grace and ease whenever an issue arises with a client or a co-worker. All of my skills will help increase productivity by keeping the work environment positive. I am focused on providing the best quality in my work, which rubs off on my co-workers because my work ethic motivates them.\"", "Some great strengths you may have: \n\n- Person of Accountability \n- Invested in Culture\n- Positive Mindset \n- Perceptive\n- Approachable \n- Empathetic\n- Honest\n- Patient\n- Decisive"]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "What goals would you like to accomplish while working for Company ABC?", "answers": ["If you are looking for opportunities to advance your career, Company ABC is a great place to start!  They are interested in hearing about how you want to grow within the company. You may be taking the next step in your career or starting out fresh out of college. It's important to do your company research before interviewing and identify how they will help you reach your goals.", "\"After looking through your careers I was excited to find out that your mission is very much in line with my career goals. Your leadership development program is exactly what I need to improve my management and team building skills. I want to grow my career in merchandising, eventually moving into a management role. I feel confident that working for you will help me to cultivate my skills so that I can take my career to that next step.\"", "\"My primary career goal is to find a position where I can stay long term while making an impact on the company's profitability. Because Company ABC has such a strong reputation for workplace culture, it fits perfectly with my desires for a long-term fit.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "Describe your typical work week.", "answers": ["Think about your typical day-to-day in your current or most recent role. Reflect on how your work ethic helped you to stay organized and tackle challenging projects. Connect your past experiences to what you expect to experience while working for Company ABC.", "\"I like to take time to prepare for the week by organizing my schedule every Monday morning. I make sure all of my meetings are marked on my calendar and set reminders about important deadlines. I understand that changes can interrupt my daily flow, and I can adapt and stay calm when those shifts occur throughout the week. I am efficient, getting my work done within 40 hours each week. I have also proven myself to be flexible to stay late when I need to finish a project or if one of my co-workers needs assistance.\"", "\"My typical work week is always non-typical! My days range from making client phone calls, site visits, and answering questions and concerns via email. Client management is the key to what I do.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "What interests you about Company ABC?", "answers": ["It is essential that you do your homework before an interview! Company ABC wants individuals who are reliable and also those who are willing to work hard to get the job done right. You want them to know that you fit the profile of the type of candidate for which they are looking.\n\nBut first, you want to impress them with your company knowledge. After a little research, you will learn about their mission to create new products and services to meet the needs of their customers. \n\nReview the website and then consider checking out what people are saying about them on glassdoor.com. Company ABC wants to hear about the good things future employees are looking forward to experiencing! It will show them that you are not looking for just any job.", "\"I'm excited to work for a company who cares about their impact on the environment. I'm excited to join a team that shares the same values as me. Your mission stood out to me because I also value providing the best service to customers and creating innovative solutions to problems. Your reputation for meeting your customer's needs, by making changes to your products, and listening to them is impressive!\"", "\"I have been passively seeking a new position for quite some time and haven't jumped on anything yet because I want to make sure it's the right fit. I feel that this job is right for me, at this point in my career, because it offers an opportunity for me to utilize my recent education in hospitality while giving me an opportunity to advance in my management skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "What is your greatest weakness?", "answers": ["Perhaps you are watching TED talks to gain skills in a particular area, reading the latest-and-greatest book on the subject, or maybe you are taking a seminar at a nearby community center. We are all human with our own weaknesses, so don't be afraid to share yours!", "\"I believe I could improve on some technical skills including Excel and PowerPoint. Currently I am at a beginner to intermediate level; however, I would be more comfortable at an advanced level. I have enrolled myself in an evening/weekend workshop for the next six weeks. We will see how stellar my skills are after that course!\"", "\"Sometimes I have difficulty asking for help from co-workers. I like having control over my daily tasks and taking on new projects, but I'm not always willing to admit when I have taken on too much. When I made a mistake because I was juggling too many projects, I learned that it's okay to ask for help. I'm learning how to organize myself better and communicate what I need from my team. This skill has helped me be more effective at my job, and it's helped my team work together even better than before!\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "The work environment at Company ABC can be fast-paced at times. How do you handle stress?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear that you can keep up in an ever-changing, fast-moving environment. They want to hear that you will be able to handle the pressure and that you have experience dealing with this type of work environment. Share a few tips that have helped you in the past.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "At Company ABC we understand that conflict can arise when you're working closely with others on a team. Give me an example of a time when you had to deal with an issue while working with others.", "answers": ["Responding to a conflict can be tough, especially in a team environment where you want to be sensitive not to step on any toes. Share an example of a conflict that occurred within your department or between you and a co-worker that you effectively resolved. Explain the situation and how your actions resulted in a resolution or a compromise.", "\"My coworker was a great salesman but horrible at the administrative side. He made so many mistakes and didn't seem to care. It bothered me because I take such pride in the quality of my work. I decided to talk with him and found out that he wasn't very clear on expectations or how to do some of the basic aspects of the paperwork for each sale. He ended up getting some additional training to get on the same page as the rest of the team.\"", "\"In my current position there has been a concern with workplace bullying, and there are a particular group of individuals who 'lead the pack,' so to speak. The situation became out of control a few months ago, and I had to involve human resources as well as conduct a few exit interviews. It is never easy having to terminate employees; however, if they are causing conflict, it is always the best choice in the end.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "What is your greatest professional achievement so far?", "answers": ["Company ABC is looking for individuals who are motivated. Whether your accomplishment is related to school, work or volunteer experience, you can give an example that demonstrates your determination and ability to overcome obstacles. Often an achievement is honored through receiving high praise from a manager or an award. Numbers speak volumes! Whenever you are able, tangibly explain the results, offering up a concrete example of what your achievement looked like to help the interviewer at Company ABC get a much clearer picture of your success.", "\"I was the top sales leader when at my most recent company. I think the reason I did so well was my consistency in following up with customers. I checked in with them daily, also checking to make sure I was meeting my own personal sales goals on a weekly basis. My contribution helped them increase sales that year by 25%!\"", "\"The greatest accomplishment in my career was graduating University as an honors student while still working full time in a related field. I was top of my class, and working full time. This achievement showed me that I could dedicate myself to my career, and reach the goals that I set for myself. It felt great to accomplish so much and be recognized for my dedication.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "Why are you leaving your current job?", "answers": ["Be honest about your situation using discretion with what you share. If you are leaving because you had issues with your manager, talk about it professionally. Company ABC wants to hear that you are interested in growth opportunities or broadening your skills. Be specific about how this new position will help you take your career to the next level.", "\"I decided to look for other jobs because I have already been promoted twice and there is no more room for growth. This position at Company ABC will give me more experience as a manager and help me to cultivate my leadership skills.\"", "\"I am passively looking for a new opportunity that will offer continued education and growth opportunities.  Also, I am looking for compensation advancement as I have hit the peak of my earnings in my current company.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "What do you think you will enjoy most about working in the food and beverage industry?", "answers": ["In our consumer culture, the food and beverage industry continues to thrive on a national and a global level. There are endless opportunities for growth at Company ABC because business is thriving and the demand for their products is on the rise. Do your research on the company to find out how they compare to their competition. If you are new to the industry, you may want to take some time to learn more about how your position will relate to the bigger picture of manufacturing, sales or marketing of the products.", "\"I am excited to work in the food and beverage industry because there is an opportunity for growth. When I worked at a food processing company, I started out working in the warehouse and was promoted within six months to a delivery driver. When I found out about the delivery supervisor position with Company ABC I was immediately interested. It is so motivating to work within an industry that recognizes my potential and my abilities, giving me ample opportunity to grow my career.\"", "\"When it comes to the food and beverage industry I love that it is so innovative and ever-changing! There are always new products being introduced which keep things interesting. I enjoy learning, so this is certainly the industry for me to be in.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "Can you tell me a little bit about yourself?", "answers": ["This question can trip some people up because it is open-ended. Open-ended questions like this give you the chance to tell a story. When you talk about yourself, you want to share information that the interviewer at Company ABC will find exciting and relevant to the position. Engage the interviewer by telling your story with enthusiasm! Consider sharing a skill you developed that will be useful for this position.", "\"I graduated with a Bachelor of Arts degree with a major in Communications and Marketing from UBC in 2009. Since then, I have been actively making my way to a leadership role in social media marketing within the hotel and hospitality industry. I am an energetic and positive person, ready to make a difference in a growing organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "Tell me about an idea you implemented in the past that made an impact.", "answers": ["Coming up with ideas to increase productivity, efficiency and save time and energy is a great way to make an impact on your coworkers and the company.  Having the ability to see problems as opportunities is a skill that can make you an essential asset to Company ABC. Think of a time you had a chance to make a difference by making a change in a process or procedure.", "\"Since customers are so much more concerned about their long-term health, I helped my current company come up with a marketing campaign for ABC product to appeal to the health concerns of the public. I conducted market research, using surveys to identify the specific health concerns of individuals who buy our products. By promoting our new health-conscious recipe, we were able to increase sales by 15% that year!\"", "\"In my previous role I was fortunate enough to introduce my company to the idea of a gold level service where, in addition to our general customer service, we added additional options. Our customer base responded very positively, and we kept the program running for a few years.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "Do you have experience training others?", "answers": ["Because Company ABC is growing at such a rapid pace, as they hire new staff, your manager may ask you to train new employees. If you have experience, talk about how you used your strengths and skills to teach others. If you don't have experience with training, you can share how you will demonstrate, listen and observe others throughout the training process.", "\"Yes, I trained two individuals on XYZ skill in my previous job. First I had them shadow me so that they could see what I was doing. I made myself very approachable by making sure they felt comfortable asking questions, speaking slowly and demonstrating. I asked them if they wanted to try while I shadowed them. This was a very effective way to train, and I enjoyed it very much!\"", "\"I have not been in a role senior enough to train others in the past, but I believe that I will be a strong trainer and mentor in the future. I care about the progress of my colleagues and am a patient teacher.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "How do you handle customer complaints?", "answers": ["If you are interviewing for a customer facing role at Company ABC, you want to show off your ability to deal with conflict and nurture those professional relationships. Give an example of a time you helped resolve a customer's issue.", "\"A customer called me very frustrated about a problem with a shipment. I listened and told them I would be happy to help. I asked more questions to understand the problem and then suggested once I had a better idea of what might solve it. The customer was very relieved and grateful that I took the time to listen and make sense of the issue.\"", "\"If I have a customer complaint, I have been trained to actively listen, do not interrupt, and repeat back to the client in their own words. This technique prevents further misunderstanding and helps the client to feel they are listened to and cared for.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "How do you handle situations that could cause you to be tardy or absent?", "answers": ["The food and beverage industry requires people and processes to operate promptly. Remember, you are a part of a much larger operation. If you are running behind, you could slow down production. Give an example that will show Company ABC that you plan and take a proactive approach to these types of situations.", "\"I always arrive to work at least 15 minutes before I am expected to be there, to give me extra time in case something happens. I also make sure I have the numbers of my co-workers and boss so that I can call to let them know if I'm stuck or might be running late.\"", "\"I was raised to be early, at all times. I am well-scheduled and understand the negative impact that my tardiness can cause. If I am to be late, I am sure to call my manager, or whoever will be affected by the situation. I will also put in extra hours when necessary.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "At Company ABC we value individuals who take initiative. Can you give me an example of a time you did something without being asked?", "answers": ["Taking the initiative demonstrates leadership ability. Even if you are working as a delivery driver, there is always an opportunity to be proactive in the way you approach your work. Company ABC wants to hire individuals who demonstrate leadership qualities, because they invest in their employees and often promote from within. Impress the interviewer by showing how you manage your workload and take action before anyone has the chance to ask you first.", "\"I noticed the numbers were off on a shipment I was delivering to a customer. They had ordered 30 cases, and we were only delivering 25. When I made the delivery, I let the customer know we would deliver the additional cases the next day and I called my manager to find out what went wrong. My manager and the client appreciated my sense of urgency and my ability to take action after making that observation.\"", "\"I often find myself taking the initiative without being asked. This will include situations like training staff members on a new procedure, calling customers to follow up on their orders, or taking random inventory counts.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "There may be times when you are asked to stay late, work weekends or overtime, due to fluctuations in the schedule and shift changes at Company ABC. What is your availability?", "answers": ["The hours you would be expected to work at Company ABC largely depends on which department you will be working in. If you're working in production or delivery, you will most likely be required to do shift work, possibly working on weekends. If you work in the corporate office, you may be salary, which often means working long hours. If you're not sure what to expect from the schedule, now is the time to ask!", "\"I am excited about the opportunity to work for Company ABC and I am available to work whatever hours are required to get the job done. Can you tell me more about what I can expect from the schedule? I am flexible, and I am comfortable with working long hours.\"", "\"The only restriction that I currently have on my schedule is Thursday evenings as I take my son to tutoring those evenings. Other than this, I am flexible with my availability. Having a family, I do ask for reasonable notice to schedule changes.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "We strive to help our employees create a healthy work/life balance at Company ABC. How do you balance life and work?", "answers": ["Company ABC cares about their employees working hard to build connections with their customers and create a sense of community within the workplace. Even in healthy work culture, it can be challenging to balance your work with the rest of your life. Explain how you balance your life in your current or past roles.", "\"I am methodical about my work and my schedule. I set reminders on my calendar to stay organized and on-time, relying on my google calendar and my to-do list. I make sure I can make it to soccer practice each week so that I can play in the games on the weekends.\"", "\"I find that with the right company, it's pretty simple to balance life and work. When I enjoy what I do, the work doesn't feel like a chore. I am always sure that when at home, my family gets my attention first. I take time on the weekends to do things for myself and ensure that I regenerate before the work week begins.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "How do you believe your coworkers would describe you?", "answers": ["You may be carefree and fun-loving with your friends on the weekends, but at work, you are focused and professional. The interviewer is interested in your personality and how you will fit with the team. As you prepare for this question, picture a few scenarios that have occurred in your current or previous position. Maybe you are encouraging and motivating to your coworkers when they are having a bad day. \n\nIf you have proven yourself reliable, and people can depend on you to be on time, share it! Think about some of the qualities you enjoy in a coworker and share how you think you embodied some of those qualities.", "\"I believe that my coworkers would describe me as curious, confident, and creative! I put a lot of effort into my work and always want my clients to be happy with their end product. I conduct a great deal of research into new marketing trends to ensure that I am delivering the best, most up-to-date solutions to my client projects.\"", "\"I believe my coworkers would describe me as dedicated, trustworthy and kind. When you call my references, I strongly believe that they will say the same things about me. I am a proud employee and promise to be a great brand ambassador for your company.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "When have you had to think outside of the box to solve a problem?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about a time that you solved a problem, creatively. Were you happy with the outcome? What were the steps that you took to ensure your success?", "\"In my current position we saw a decrease in clients due to a local economic downturn. I recommended to our head office that we begin to generate business outside of our region for the first time in many years. They agreed, and the idea turned things around for us that fiscal year.\"", "\"I once had to deal with a space issue in our warehouse. We arranged and re-arranged several times and could not make it work. I thought outside the box and rented some outside pod storage until we were back to normal inventory levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+and+Beverages", "question": "Company ABC is asking for 8 years of industry experience and you have just 5. Why do you think you are qualified for this position?", "answers": ["To many employers, the number of years' experience is flexible - so long as you have the results to show for the years that you do have. Talk to the interviewer about your major career successes. This question is the time to sell yourself. Make no apologies for your lack of years!", "\"Although I have five years' experience vs. eight years' experience I can do this job well. In my previous role, I was outperforming colleagues who had 12  years of experience. To me, it's all about drive and ability to be a quick study. I have all of these qualities and more.\"", "\"Along with my five years working in this industry, I have worked in related industries my entire career. Also, I hope that my graduate degree gives me a little boost in experience over the required undergraduate degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "In your opinion, what is the biggest food trend right now? Which is your favorite?", "answers": ["The culinary and food service world is always evolving, with the hottest trends changing on a regular basis. The interviewer would like to see that you have a genuine interest in keeping up with these changes. Discuss the resources that you use for keeping up-to-date in the culinary world. You can also ask the interviewer what their favorite trend is, at the moment. By doing so, you are creating an opportunity for a memorable conversation.", "\"For myself, chef-driven fast-casual concepts are the most interesting topic for me. This concept offers the best of many worlds by combining fast food concepts yet still offering a desirable and delicious meal to guests. Gourmet taco shops are an excellent example. Do you have any specific favorites at the moment?\"", "\"There are many great food trends right now, with my absolute favorite being farm to table. The environment and our local economic status are important topics to me, and I believe they go hand in hand. In my current role, I will source meats and poultry from local farms, and vegetables from growers no further than 50 miles from our city.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "What other back of house or kitchen roles have you held in the past?", "answers": ["Most foodservice professionals have worked their way up through the ranks, advancing their career as opportunities come up, and training opportunities occur. The interviewer would like to see that you have a sense of what it takes to succeed in a variety of roles. Generally, in a kitchen setting, the hierarchy works from the dishwasher, kitchen porter, line cook, sous chef, head chef, and executive chef. There are many other roles also which include fry chef, grill chef, pastry chef, and more. These will depend on the complexity of the kitchen where you are working. \n\nBriefly take the interviewer through the roles that you have held, expressing that you can mentor and guide those junior to you, while also showing a willingness to learn from those senior to you.", "\"My food service experience began when I was just 16 years old, as a dishwasher in a commercial kitchen. From there, I gained a role as a kitchen porter, and then an apprentice. I have been a sous chef for two years now and take every opportunity to guide and mentor those junior to me. I want to see people with a passion for food, grow in their career, so I will do what it takes to help them move up the ranks.\"", "\"I have been given great opportunities in the foodservice industry, from my start as a dishwasher and porter. The chefs that I have worked under over the past seven years have been very dedicated to stoking my passion for food. I look forward to helping those in return, as we all work up the ranks, earning roles that we desire and growing in our careers.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "How do you prevent cross-contamination?", "answers": ["Cross-contamination occurs when bacteria is unintentionally transferred from one food to another, often causing an ill effect such as food poisoning. The biggest culprits for cross-contamination include:  \n\n- Employees failing to wash their hands often enough \n- Using the same cutting board for meat and poultry, as you do fruits and veggies\n- Storing food at an incorrect temperature\n- Failing to sanitize equipment fully\n\nShow the interviewer that you understand how vital it is to adhere to strict food handling and safety procedures. Discuss what you do to play your part when it comes to food safety.", "\"I prevent cross-contamination by ensuring that I wash my hands way more than the expected minimum. I am also careful to cut meat and poultry only on the designated cutting boards, then fully sanitizing any equipment once I am done my task.\"", "\"Cross-contamination can be prevented through thorough sanitation and handwashing. I am very firm with my kitchen team when it comes to safety and health practices, and I have never had an issue come up from dangerous cross-contamination.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "When were you able to resolve a problem within work?", "answers": ["Problem-solving and dispute resolution are fundamental skills to possess, especially in the food service industry where you serve customers every day and are often customer facing in your tasks. Show the interviewer that you are capable of problem-solving within the workplace, and making good judgement calls under pressure. Show that you can be a team player, even in the face of conflict.", "\"My current employer recently catered a large wedding where we underestimated the amount of glassware that we needed. We were close to being short, so I called a fellow caterer from our network and asked if we could lean on them to provide the additional glassware. They charged us a rental fee and urgent order surcharge; however, that was a much better option than disappointing a client. My boss appreciated my quick thinking and willingness to reach out to our network.\"", "\"We recently had a concern surrounding employee theft. As the wholesale food manager, I needed to get to the bottom of the situation before the issue escalated. I called the corporate head office to collaborate on a plan that followed the HR guidelines. I implemented the plan, which included additional security cameras, and we caught the employee on camera shortly after.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "What is your favorite cooking technique?", "answers": ["There are many cooking techniques, and depending on the current menu at Company ABC, you may be asked to use a variety of them on any given day. Some of the most popular cooking techniques include searing, braising, deglazing, blanching, infusing, and emulsifying. There is no right or wrong answer to this question; however, the interviewer would like to see that you have a passion for your craft and the ability to apply a variety of methodologies in the kitchen.", "\"My favorite method of cooking at the moment, is infusing. As a former bartender, I have a deep interest in taking the aromas and flavors from unexpected sources such as flowers and herbs, to make a drink or sauce, feel more complex and decadent.\"", "\"I have trained in a variety of cooking techniques; however, at the moment, my favorite is emulsifying. To bring unexpected ingredients together to create a delicious flavor is more of a science than some people expect. For instance, to create a house-made mayonnaise, you need to suspend oil in water and lemon juice which works only with the use of an emulsifier such as egg yolk.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Is compensation the most important factor for you when taking a new job?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how much emphasis you put on pay when considering a new position. In addition to compensation, there are many other factors to a fulfilling career. These other factors may include:\n\n- work/life balance\n- amount of travel involved in the role\n- overall medical and health benefits\n- additional perks such as car allowance, cell allowance, spending account\n- the industry you will be working in\n- amount of vacation time\n- the type of clients you would be working with\n- the location of the company\n- career growth opportunity\n- the size of your new team\n- the company's reputation\n- overall workplace culture. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about other factors that are important to you when considering a new job. If you are not sure on details for this role, you can ask!", "\"Salary is important to me because I know that I am skilled and well educated. With that said, I do look at the full picture which includes factors such as benefits and the amount of paid vacation time.\"", "\"Several factors are important to me when taking a job. Compensation is a driving component but so is the company mission, culture, benefits, and location. I am looking to have an easier commute than I currently experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "What would you do if you caught a co-worker violating food safety standards?", "answers": ["Violations of food safety standards can include:\n\n- Foregoing gloves when they have cuts, scrapes, or rashes\n- Failing to wash hands before handling food, utensils, or kitchen equipment \n- Food storage at improper temperatures\n- Serving expired food knowingly, even if it 'looks good'\n- Buying food from unapproved or unlicensed vendors\n- Preparing food without hot water or other required resources\n\nTalk to the interviewer about how you would react if you witnessed a violation in the workplace. Be sure to mention that you would follow any procedures put in place by Company ABC. If you have come across this situation before, you can refer to the scenario and how you dealt with it.", "\"If I caught a co-worker violating food safety standards, I would report it immediately, according to the Company ABC standards and protocol. I have had this situation happen in the past, where an employee was not storing food properly. I wrote a report, submitted it, and retrained the employee on proper standards. That type of behavior is unacceptable, and I assure you that I take food safety very seriously.\"", "\"Food safety violations are a serious matter. I would report the incident immediately, and then correct the offense if possible. For instance, if an employee were not washing their hands properly or frequently enough, I would let them know that I noticed the behavior and ask them to correct it. Rest assured, I will do what it takes to uphold the safety standards of Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Tell me about a time when you went above and beyond for customer service.", "answers": ["The foodservice industry is competitive, and it's essential that you can help Company ABC deliver the best in customer service so that they can remain a top choice for discerning customers. The interviewer is looking for a specific answer that showcases your ability to deliver excellent customer service. You need to go beyond 'service with a smile' when answering this question. Make your reply memorable! This question offers you an excellent opportunity to be a stand-out candidate.", "\"Customer inquiries come through my desk at a rapid rate whether it be through email, voicemail, or social media. I make it my aim to never leave for the day until every inquiry has a response. This commitment may mean staying late an extra hour sometimes, but my valued customers are worth the added effort.\"", "\"I used to work the front desk in a hotel where we were given a budget specifically to use for making a customers' experience better. I recall one couple in specific who left their phone and laptop chargers in the room after they checked out. I same-day couriered the items to them with a friendly note. It felt great to deliver that added touch.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "How do you show your co-workers the importance of communication in the workplace?", "answers": ["Clear communication is vital, at all times, in the foodservice industry. Breakdown of communication in a foodservice setting can have dire effects on the profitability of an organization and its reputation. This effect is why it is essential to understand that 'telling,' and 'showing' are two very different things when it comes to proper communication. The interviewer would like to know that you lead by example when it comes to communication in the workplace. Give examples of how you put dialogue into action in the workplace.", "\"I show my co-workers the importance of communication in the workplace simply from leading by example. I set the tone and expectations for how we should communicate by utilizing all forms of written, verbal and interpersonal communications to a tee.\"", "\"In foodservice, we have to communicate every small detail of our projects and the clients' expectations. I encourage this with my team by asking everyone to use Trello, a project management app that tracks our progress and needs, every step of the way. It's like web-based sticky notes!\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "What would you do in the event of a grease fire, or other kitchen emergency?", "answers": ["How you react in an emergency situation can make a world of difference when it comes to the safety of those in your kitchen, or the event which you are catering. Walk the interviewer through how you would react when it comes to a kitchen related emergency. Be sure to show that you know how to remain calm, make smart decisions under pressure, and keep your team's safety front of mind. \n\nIn the foodservice industry, your new employee orientation should include locating the emergency exits, first aid supplies, and fire extinguishers. You should be trained on evacuation procedures and muster points as well as receive orientation on any potential on-site hazards.", "\"In the event of a grease fire, I would pull the alarm, locate the nearest fire extinguisher and, recalling my training, deploy the extinguisher. I would order my team to evacuate the kitchen as well. One can never be too careful in a situation such as that, and it's important to act fast, yet with control.\"", "\"I have been trained, if a grease fire occurs, to turn off the heat source and cover the flame with a metal lid if possible, preventing the flame from growing. Then, I would pour salt or baking soda on the flame, to extinguish it. Although it is instinct, the last thing that should be done is dousing the flame with water. I react well in emergency situations, and am sure to remain calm and in control.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "How do you get along with others at work?", "answers": ["In the foodservice industry, you may work closely with a wide range of personalities, in a close-knit or high-stress environment. The interviewer wants to gauge if you can maintain healthy relationships in the workplace. They want to know more about the dynamics with your coworkers. Think about what you enjoyed about some of your relationships with past coworkers. Excellent communication, sense of humor, and support are all great qualities that make co-worker relationships healthy and harmonious.", "\"I have never had an issue when it comes to getting along with others at work. I am a conscious communicator and am sure always to express myself in a kind and professional manner. A positive attitude is a must when working in such a fast paced role.\"", "\"I enjoy the people I work with and can get along with anyone. I have made some of my closest friends from different workplaces, and I know how important relationships in the office are for not only camaraderie but also for accomplishing tasks within your team.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "What decisions did you routinely make in your last position?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of decisions you are accustomed to making in the workplace. The way you answer this questions will give them a good idea of your level of experience, seniority, and ability to handle the decision-making requirements in this position with Company ABC. \n\nIf the job you are interviewing for requires you to be decisive and quick on your feet, you will need to be able to provide examples of how you have done these things in the past. If you worked in food prep, you faced problems that you needed to find solutions for on a regular basis. If you worked as a sales rep, you might have required knowing how to negotiate and make decisions on customer pricing. You may have faced decisions that became so routine you didn't think twice! Refer to these types of decisions and be sure to highlight how these types of decisions have prepared you for a role like this one.", "\"In my previous position I was quite often required to make decisions on staff scheduling as well as hiring and terminating. I feel that role prepared me quite well for a position like this one. I have well-honed decision-making skills and my intuition, when it comes to hiring, has been elevated.\"", "\"On a day-to-day level, I chose the city of focus, prioritization of prospects, and delegation of tasks. The higher-level decisions I made were regarding the hiring and assignment of new hires. I also had a large influence on the employee terminations. I feel that these two sets of responsibilities have positioned me well for this role and I look forward to continuing to leveraging my experience while learning from the more seasoned members of the staff.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "How would you handle a rude customer?", "answers": ["The service industry can present significantly challenging customers. Seeing as it's unavoidable, the interviewer wants to know that you can handle such a situation with professionalism. Give an example of a time that you had to deal with a challenging customer situation. Be sure to include the positive outcome. \n\nSome ways that you can efficiently handle a rude customer:\n\n- Remain kind, polite, and pleasant\n- Actively listen to their grievances \n- Apologize for the situation \n- Maintain a neutral tone of voice\n- Avoid taking anything they say, personally", "\"When I was working as a bartender, I handled many rude customers who were also intoxicated, which always adds a challenging twist! I made sure to let anything rude they said to slide off my back like it was nothing. I just kept smiling, and doing my job! I still handle rude customers this way. Smile, and move on, disallowing any hurt feelings.\"", "\"Rude customers are a given in the retail industry, and I have faced my fair share of them. I will outright ask a customer if there is anything I can do to make them more comfortable, happier, or how I can deliver their expectations this time around. When the customer is aware that I am willing to rectify the situation they are much more likely to level with me.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Would your former boss describe you as a worker who gladly goes the extra mile to complete their tasks?", "answers": ["You can say that you will go the extra mile, but it's best to give a real-life example to the interviewer about a time when you did just that. Offer up your references as well and discuss with the interviewer what you feel your most recent employer would say about you. Give examples of how you go the extra mile in the workplace. \n\nHere are some ways that employees will go the extra mile:\n\n- Starting on an upcoming project ahead of time, without being asked.\n- Taking action on any feedback, they receive from their manager. Taking action means attending a class to improve a required skill or reading a self-development book to help with communication skills at work. \n- Coming to meetings ready to brainstorm or, better yet, with ideas already jotted down\n- Creating new ways for themselves or their team to maximize efficiency\n- Going out of their way to make their customers happy", "\"My boss would describe me as an employee who goes the extra mile. In my most recent position, I was always available on my email, and many of my service clients had my cell phone number just in case of an after-hours emergency. When you call my reference he will be happy to expand on that for you, I am sure.\"", "\"I sure hope so! I have always put my best foot forward, and I very much dislike being bored. I go the extra mile whenever possible because that's what great employees do! I have received very positive feedback from all of my previous employers.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "What is your first reaction when you do something wrong at work?", "answers": ["How you react to an error made will tell the interviewer a great deal about you and your honesty level. Perhaps the mistake is one that could land you in a lot of trouble. Would you try to hide the incident, or would you tell a supervisor right away, and have the situation rectified?", "\"My first reaction when I do something wrong at work is to own it. How can anything be repaired if nobody even has a chance to fix it on time? That would be my line of thinking if a mistake were to occur.\"", "\"It is embarrassing to make mistakes but things happen, and I am a fan of getting things out of the way. I would tell someone about the situation in hopes that a resolution is made as soon as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job. \n\nHere are some ways that an employer may try to motivate you. \nWhich ones resonate most with you? \n\n- Incentive programs where points are earned\n- Showing complete trust in your work and performance\n- Setting smaller, more achievable goals\n- Helping you to find your higher career purpose\n- Being a positive example to you \n- Maintaining an open and transparent workplace\n- Personalized incentives vs. Team driven incentives \n- Getting to know you on a personal level\n- Positive feedback based rewards system\n- Offering a stable work/life balance by encouraging time off\n- Letting you know your voice matters\n- Allowing you to take the lead on projects that excite you \n- Handing out big-picture projects, so you feel that you are contributing to the company's future\n- Public recognition", "\"My current manager motivates me by reminding me that she has full faith in my work. Those words give me a boost of confidence and feed my fire, especially on more challenging events or projects.\"", "\"I especially enjoy sales competitions and challenges to earn bonus' and gifts. In my current role, the sales associate with the most sales at the end of the week receives a $100 Visa gift card.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "How would you rate your performance in this interview so far?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you are satisfied with your interview performance. If your interview were a flop, you would know, and it's much better to address outright your performance than try to sweep it under the rug. \n\nIf you feel that your performance in the interview is going well: 'I believe that this interview has been quite informative and I am happy with my performance. Is there anything that I can clarify for you from this conversation?'\n\nIf you feel that your performance in the interview is not going well: \"I am not sure if I have been able to portray myself 100% accurately in this interview; although, I am trying my best. If there is anything more I can clarify for you, I would be happy to do so.\"", "\"I am not sure if I have been able to portray myself 100% accurately in this interview; although, I am trying my best. If there is anything more I can clarify for you, I would be happy to do so.\"", "\"I would rate my performance to 90% of my ability. When you asked about my customer service experience, I feel that missed expressing some of my experience in dispute resolution. If you have time, I would like to cover that question further.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Why should we hire you?", "answers": ["Interviewers want to hear about that one unique skill that sets you apart from the other candidates applying for this job. Think of your answer as your 'elevator pitch' or your qualifying statement. If you can't think of ways that you are unique, ask a few friends or family members what they feel sets you apart from other people. Their observations may help you understand how you are perceived.\n\nPerhaps you already know what sets you apart! This skill could include any industry accolades, exceptional achievements, additional industry related training, a second language, or how involved you are in the community. Don't be afraid to brag about yourself a bit. In an interview, you are your most influential advocate.", "\"I have over a dozen years of experience in the foodservice industry at one of your largest competitors. I have a proven track record of successes there and will bring that knowledge with me. I also offer creative solutions on how to elevate your business to the next level. Having been a part of the service industry for nearly half of my life, I have seen a ton of change and have adapted to every change or innovation with ease and excitement, and I look forward to doing that at Company ABC as well.\"", "\"You should hire me because I am unlike anyone else you have interviewed before. When I started at my current company, I was the youngest food rep they had ever hired. That didn't stop me from becoming the #1 sales person in the company within six months. I am dedicated to my craft and engaged in the foodservice industry to the point where I commit myself to take at least one business development or leadership related workshop every business quarter. I am a competitive achiever. You won't be disappointed when you hire me.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "There are many options for you in the foodservice industry. Why do you specifically want to work with Company ABC?", "answers": ["With many options in the foodservice industry for employment, why do you want to work for Company ABC? Talk to the interviewer about your preference for their company. Dig deep when it comes to your response, bringing up specifics related to their products and services, clientele, awards they have won, or their company mission.", "\"I am careful to be employed with a company that holds a strong industry reputation. I want to work for Company ABC because your training programs are above the foodservice industry standard and you have a reputation for treating your employees very well.\"", "\"I especially want to work for Company ABC because I have friends who have worked here previously, providing me with positive feedback on their experiences. I am looking for a positive work environment where I can stay for a long time to come. Also, I am passionate when it comes to customer service, and your standards are second to none.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Do you agree with the phrase 'The customer is always right'?", "answers": ["'The customer is always right' has been a long-standing mantra for service-based organizations. Do you agree with this mantra? Why, or why not? The interviewer would like to see you respond positively. If possible, take a look at the company website to see what their mantra or customer service statement is.", "\"Although I believe that the customer is not always right - it's important to treat them as though they are. Within the limitations of health and safety, etc.; I believe it's best to accommodate the customer within reason.\"", "\"Some customers are quite impossible to please so I would not go so far to say that the customer is always right. With that said, I do treat every customer with the utmost respect and do put their needs first in all reasonable situations.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Name for me the three most, and three least common food allergies.", "answers": ["Food allergies will be a top concern when working in the foodservice industry, where you may be preparing, packaging, or serving food. Show the interviewer you are aware of food allergies beyond the typical culprits such as peanuts. You can keep your answer brief, and to the point. If you have taken courses on food safety, this is a great time to mention that.", "\"I recently took Food Safety Level II through my employer and understand that the three most common food allergies are cow's milk, eggs, and tree nuts. We did not touch a lot on the least common, but I believe they would be particular fruits, anything sesame based, and highly processed foods such as hot dogs or marshmallows.\"", "\"I think that the most common food allergies would be nuts, shellfish, and wheat. For least common, I have reactions to avocados which is rare. Also, I think corn and dried fruits are likely on the lower end of the allergens list, but probably important ones to note. I do understand how vital it is to be aware of cross-contamination when it comes to serving and preparing foods.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Tell me about your food safety training or related certifications.", "answers": ["Health and safety is the main priority for all food service organization. Walk the interviewer through any related training. If you have any physical cards or certifications to show, be sure to bring those into the interview. If some of your certifications are close to expiration, be sure to disclose that.", "\"I have had training in my past three roles in regards to health and safety, and well as proper food handling. If there is additional training that you require me to participate in, I am happy to do so.\"", "\"I am new to the workforce and, having just graduated from university; I do not have formal training in health or safety. If you have any required coursework related to this position with Company ABC, I am happy to get a head start on that training.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Are you available to work evenings and weekends, and attend special events?", "answers": ["In the foodservice industry, you may often be required to work late nights, holidays, special events, and weekends. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of offering flexibility to Company ABC and their needs. If you have any restrictions in your schedule such as an evening course, another job, a family requirement, or volunteer commitment, it's crucial that you bring this up at this time in your interview. Show that you have enthusiasm for the role, and express your willingness to be as flexible as possible to meet their needs.", "\"I can offer you a significant amount of flexibility in my schedule except for the next 12 Tuesday nights. On those evenings, I take a culinary course. After this coursework is complete, my schedule will be wide open.\"", "\"I understand that this role may require a commitment from me on weekends and evenings or even holidays. I am willing to offer flexibility in my schedule. At this time, there are no restrictions except for a family holiday I have booked from January 12 to 18th.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Tell me about your culinary education. What was your primary educational focus?", "answers": ["Walk the interviewer through your education, being sure to highlight any special recognition or accolades you received along the way. Focus also on your best courses, what your favorite methods were, and what your certification major is.", "\"I attended the Culinary Institute of Virginia College and was focused primarily on Pastry Arts. I did achieve a Diploma in Pastry Arts as well as an additional Certificate in Culinary Arts. My favorite courses included Artisan Breads and Viennoiserie.\"", "\"My Degree is in Food Science and Nutrition. I have a keen interest in how we can use food creatively to nourish our bodies and create incredible sensory experiences. If I could return to school, I would take an additional certificate in Culinary Entrepreneurship and Food Service Retail Management.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Who do you admire most in the culinary world, and why?", "answers": ["There are many amazing trailblazers in the culinary world, both past, and present. This question is more of a special interest inquiry which means there is no right or wrong reply. Show the interviewer that you have a genuine passion for the foodservice industry by giving a well thought out and researched response.", "\"Eug?nie Brazier initially sparked my interest in the culinary world, the first female chef to ever earn 3 Michelin Stars. She was incredibly inspired and helped to shape what we know as Lyonnaise cuisine, the traditional cooking practices of the Lyon region.\"", "\"There are many people to admire in the culinary world. The person that comes top of mind for me is Anthony Bourdain. I love how he combined food, travel, and culture in everything that he did. His show, Parts Unknown, truly sparked the desire in me to explore flavors from all over the world.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Give an example of a fall-time menu that you would prepare.", "answers": ["Menu's change with the season, primarily if you work for an organization interested in working with the best seasonal ingredients, and sourcing local products. The interviewer would like to know that you have a keen interest in menu planning with a creative and exciting flair. Before your interview, you should visit the Company ABC website to see if you can gain any clues related to the type of flavors they enjoy. Lean on that as a basis for your creativity.", "\"Some of my favorite fall ingredients include pumpkin, beets, pomegranate, and persimmons. If I were to create a 4-course fall menu, I would begin with a squash ribbon salad with a zesty orange and chile sauce. Next, an oven roasted polenta dish with mushrooms and thyme. The main could be lamb shanks braised in mint and burnt orange sauce. For dessert, I would create a pumpkin cheesecake with bourbon sauce. I have many great ideas when it comes to fall culinary.\"", "\"Fall offers rich and comforting flavors. It's one of my favorite seasons to cook! If I were to create a fall time menu, I would start with a warming soup such as Pumpkin Chipotle. Next, I would create a beetroot, chevre, and walnut salad with a warm vinaigrette. For the main, I would offer a dish of cider-braised chicken breasts with marinated pears and root vegetables. For dessert, a warm chocolate cake with pumpkin spiced ice cream, house-made, of course, topped with vanilla bean.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "Tell me your involvement with budgets and food planning.", "answers": ["Food planning and budgeting are essential skills to have when looking to grow in your foodservice career. You can take courses on these topics such as Food & Beverage cost controls, often available through local colleges and culinary schools. You likely know that costs have to be recovered through sales, so it's easy to remember this calculation: sales = labor + overhead + food costs. If you do not have formal education or on the job training related to budgets and food costs, you can find essential formulas and calculators online. Show the interviewer that you understand the importance of being aware of expenses and the advantages of food planning.", "\"I have a certificate in Food & Beverage Cost Controls with ten years' experience building food budgets and menu planning. My current food costs are below 22%, a record low for the company where I work. I do not sacrifice when it comes to quality, but I do understand that it's important to prevent waste by overbuying.\"", "\"I have excellent math skills, buying insight, and the ability to use many ingredients in multiple ways, to avoid waste and high costs. In my current role, I assist the executive chef with food planning and budgeting. I am not an expert in these areas; however, I would rate myself an intermediate level.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "If you were asked to lower your food costs, where would you start?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for common sense knowledge when it comes to your ability to see where you can save money, lower waste, and increase profits. Some of the ways that you can lower food costs include: \n\n- Eliminating menu items that do not sell well \n- Create a menu where some ingredients can be used multiple ways\n- Enforce a strict anti-theft policy to reduce food theft\n- Work with your suppliers to buy in bulk and receive discounts\n- Improve the quality of your staff, so less food is wasted from poor culinary performance", "\"If I needed to lower food costs, the first place I would look is what is being thrown out most often, and which menu items the ingredient is being used. I would tweak the menu in a way that we could eliminate or cut back on that ingredient. Also, having efficient and talented staff in the kitchen is an undeniable way of eliminating waste. Great staff will burn dishes less often, for instance, and will be able to keep an eye out for food waste as well.\"", "\"Food costs are vital to a company's success and profitability. If I were asked to lower food costs, I would begin by working with my suppliers to lower costs. I could ask about ordering in bulk but still receive multiple shipments so that storage is not an issue. In my current role, I reevaluate the menu every six weeks and will tweak or eliminate menu items that are not selling.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "What is the largest amount of people you have prepared food service for?", "answers": ["The interviewer will be able to gauge better the amount of volume and responsibility they can pass onto you when they have an idea of your past and current responsibility level. Share with the interviewer some of the more significant responsibilities you have had. \n\nPerhaps you were the team lead for a 500 person catered wedding, or maybe you helped to run a restaurant that was a hot-spot but only 60 seats. Each position you have will come with its unique challenges. Share those with the interviewer and assure them that you can handle the complexity of this role with Company ABC.", "\"In my current role, we have reservations booked out approximately three weeks in advance. Our main dining area seats 200 guests, and the lounge, another 300 guests. Because we are such a hot place to be right now, there is a minimal amount of reprieve. I would say, on average, with table turnarounds, we see 600 guests per evening.\"", "\"I have led foodservice for a wide range of groups, from 50 to 1,000. I can handle vast amounts of guests, and am ready to bring my best to Company ABC for every event.\""]}, {"topic": "Food+Service", "question": "How do you test the quality of your ingredients?", "answers": ["Guests, customers, and consumers are extra discerning these days, and it's essential to Company ABC that they are known for delivering quality in everything they do. Testing the quality of your ingredients can happen a few ways. For fruits and vegetables, for instance, it can mean being seasonally aware of what is best used different months of the year. When it comes to meat and poultry, sourcing from local rangers could eliminate the need for flash freezing and transportation, making a world of difference in your dish. Discuss with the interviewer the ways that you ensure quality is always top of mind.", "\"I rely on my senses and seasonal awareness when it comes to choosing the best quality, freshest ingredients. I read a lot about food quality and know a fair amount about agriculture as well. You can rest assured that I will bring only the highest quality of work and ingredients to Company ABC.\"", "\"My sense of smell, and knowledge on what a particular ingredient looks like at it's freshest, is a significant factor in delivering high-quality ingredients.  I have trusted vendors and suppliers, and also spend a good deal of time researching cuts of meat, the feel of certain fruits, and other important tips on freshness, that every chef should know.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "What are the most critical consumer insights to measure, and how would you apply consumer data to help you in this role?", "answers": ["Consumer insights refer to the trends in products and services, based on human (or, consumer) behavior. When working in a consumer-based industry such as meat production, you are at the mercy of trends, preferred tastes, and overall customer preferences. Consumer insights give you the insight needed to make decisions such as where to take your company's marketing, what to launch next, or how to recover from a wrong product decision. Critical insights could include what is trending, what customers are complaining about, what is receiving praise, product momentum, and consumer churn rate.", "\"It would be essential for Company ABC to understand what customers are verbally requesting. One great way to do this is to have alerts and hashtags set up for your company brand. When people @ your company, what are they saying? It's important to take a look at what these consumers are suggesting and pivot from there. For instance, if consumers are complaining about excessive packaging, this shows you that it's time to take a look at introducing more eco-friendly packaging. Could you share with me the most helpful approach to gaining consumer insight here at Company ABC?\"", "\"My background in marketing applies to many industries and sectors. When it comes to critical consumer insights into the food industry, I will focus on discovering upcoming trends in flavors, convenience, and packaging. I will look at customer demographics such as age and gender, how and where they use our product the most. Lastly, another insight that I would pursue would be how they feel about alternative products. This information would help me to craft a stronger marketing strategy. It would also help a great deal in research and development efforts.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "It takes patience and tenacity to work in a consumer-driven industry. Would you say that you are one to persevere? Support your response with an example.", "answers": ["No matter the role you are applying for within Company ABC; you will be required to deliver excellent to their consumers every single day. This means being a part of the customer journey, and having patience when it comes to buying decisions, or even product complaints and suggestions. Give the interviewer an example of a time when your drive or patience was tested. Discuss how you persevered in this situation.", "\"I have done some personal and professional development over the past year. I have learned a lot about tenacity and patience in the process. I understand that being patient with customers, teammates, and other stakeholders will increase our chance of success professionally and boosts morale within the company. One example of this is when a customer frustrates me; I do not announce my frustration to the entire team. I do not want to suck the positive energy out of the room!\"", "\"I consider myself a work in progress but also someone who is tenacious and driven when it comes to achieving my professional goals and the goals of my corporation. I am patient with customers, my teammates, management, and other stakeholders that I work alongside regularly.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "What is the difference between an internal and external supply chain activities?", "answers": ["Both internal and external supply chain efforts are critical factors to a business' success. The interviewer wants to know that you understand the importance of each. \n\nInternal supply chain refers to the activities happening within a company. These activities could include production and sales, for instance. \n\nExternal supply chain refers to the activities outside of a company, such as transportation. An external supply chain partner will help your business to deliver your product to your customer, on time successfully, and within applicable laws and regulation. \n\nAs you can see, the relationship between internal and external supply chain is critical to nurture. Show the interviewer that you understand the difference between the two. If you have developed a relationship with an external supply chain partner in the past, be sure to talk about this experience.", "\"Internal supply chain activities are what we do within our company such as the production and sales activities. External supply chain refers to the business partners who help us to meet customer demands through outside services. In the supply chain, logistics, and food production industries, it is critical that internal and external partners communication harmoniously and with exceptionally clear communication styles.\"", "\"From my understanding, internal supply chain activities are everything that happens inside of Company ABC to get the product out to your customers. Your external supply chain activities refer to third party organizations that you bring in to help you fulfill these deliveries as smoothly as possible. Is this correct? I am eager to learn more about your internal and external supply chain efforts.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "If given a yearly goal, how would you go about organizing your activities to ensure you remained on target?", "answers": ["The way you respond to this question will show the interviewer how you go about organizing your time, and splitting up your tasks. The meat production industry is busy, with many moving parts. The more organized you are, and the better you understand which activities need to be taking up your time, the better you will perform at Company ABC. If you use any specific tools or software to organize your day, be sure to mention them. Be specific about the ways that you maintain order in your workday. If you are new to your career, you can specify how you remained organized in school, whether that be high school or university.", "\"I am very goal-oriented and like to know the expectations on me on a yearly, quarterly, monthly, weekly, and daily basis. I will take the goals given to me and first organize them in order of importance. Then, I will break these tasks down, starting with the most urgent, figuring out what I need to accomplish daily to exceed these goals. In my current role, I use helpful tools such as Monday and Trello to keep myself and my team on track.\"", "\"When I first started university, I found that I quickly became disorganized. I was flustered when it came to deadlines, meetings, and my extracurricular schedule. I began to lean on tools such as my iCal, and an app called Evernote, which helped me to capture and prioritize my ideas, projects, and to-do lists. Now, nothing falls through the cracks! I plan to approach my work deadlines in the same manner.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "The FDA and other health organizations heavily regulate our products. How do you contribute to our history of compliance?", "answers": ["It is imperative in the meat production industry that rules and regulations are followed. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on meat production regulation. Be sure to remain positive and avoid going on a rant if there are regulations with which you do not agree. A significant part of the success of Company ABC is due to their willingness to be compliant with the primary food regulatory bodies.", "\"I know, without a doubt, that the FDA and other regulatory bodies have public safety in mind. As a consumer of meat products, I am happy to know that there are regulations in place to ensure that my family and I receive only the best and safest products. I have researched and see that Company ABC has a strong reputation for food safety and compliance with no known breaches or fines in the past ten years. I will contribute to this trend by fully complying with every health and safety policy presented to me.\"", "\"Firm food regulations are a must for the protection of everyone. I wholeheartedly agree with most meat product regulations, and look forward to contributing by complying with your processes in every way possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "What can you tell me about the work environment at Company ABC", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know what you have done to research Company ABC and their workplace offering. If you know someone who works for Company ABC it's a great idea to have a quick informational meeting with them on the phone or in person. Have a few specific questions prepared for them regarding everyday life with the organization. \n\nYou can also check out employee review sites. Be sure to read a variety of reviews so that you can begin to recognize any patterns in the employee feedback. \n\nMost of all, be sure to focus your response on the positive things that you have heard. If there is consistent negative feedback, be sure to ask the interviewer to comment on what you have observed.", "\"I have done a lot of research on Company ABC. After reviewing the feedback on Glassdoor, I also reached out to a couple of people in my LinkedIn network who work here. Overall, the comments have been very positive; that you offer excellent balance, great training, and many opportunities for growth. I look forward to learning even more about the culture here.\"", "\"Your website is very informative when it comes to outlining the full offering at Company ABC. I see there are many perks to working here. I am most excited about the extensive health benefits, employee discounts, and incentives.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "How would you approach selling Company ABC product to a new retail customers?", "answers": ["Meat products, just like any other CPG product, must be positioned and sold in a way that has an impact. Company ABC wants to know that you will be a great representation of their product, whether you will be in a sales role or not. \n\nWhen approaching new retails customers, as a producer of a food product, it's essential to lead with the benefits, including precise information on the production, health facts, sales numbers, and profit margins. Talk to the interviewer about how you would approach selling Company ABC product. Remember, the more research you have performed on the company and their products, the better your response will be!", "\"If I were to approach a new retail prospect with Company ABC products, I would begin by discussing the strong history of your company. This information would include your commitment to excellence in everything that you produce. I would build trust and then compare the markets top products with those available from Company ABC. I know all retailers are about the bottom line so I would be sure to show how strong profit margins on the products, especially compared to competitors.\"", "\"I find the Company ABC mission, goals, and product to be clearly laid out and very transparent. I learned in business school that the best way to approach a new prospect is with a clear qualifying statement and value proposition. I would first identify the products that this particular retailer would need. Then, I would clearly outline how these products would benefit their business. Next, I would mention the retailer's pain points and position your products as a solution.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Company ABC is seeking employees with an understanding of logistics. What is Fill Rate, OTD, and Lead Time?", "answers": ["In any role with Company ABC it will be helpful for you to understand how their logistics department operates. Logistics refers to the careful coordination of product, people, and processes. When it comes to producing and moving product, terms such as Fill Rate, OTD, and Lead Time are essential. \n\n- Fill Rate: The percent of customer demand that is met through immediate stock availability.\n- OTD: On-Time Delivery. How many of your customers are receiving their orders or shipments when expected? \n- Lead Time: The time between when an order is placed and when it's received/delivered or fulfilled. \n\nIf you are joining Company ABC in a logistics function, be sure to ask about their metrics on factors such as fill rate, OTD, and lead time. These numbers directly impact customer and overall employee satisfaction. Show your understanding of these critical terms and show an interest in how Company ABC ensures their logistical operations are on point.", "\"When it comes to the movement of meat products, this can be incredibly time-sensitive. I am well aware of the many moving parts involved in the logistics within the food industry. In my current role, I have increased our Fill Rate from 89% to 98%, which I am incredibly proud to say. Could you share with me more about your most important metrics and what you are doing to exceed expectations?\"", "\"I am eager to learn more about logistics and supply chain, and the important factors that go into moving Company ABC product. I understand Fill Rate to be the rate at which we can supply orders without dipping into backorders, for instance. OTD is short for on-time delivery which is a great metric to know when it comes to customer service and exceeding expectations. The lead time metric I am not as familiar with; however, I am ready to expand my knowledge.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Do you have cross-departmental experience with customer service, purchasing, manufacturing, or logistics?", "answers": ["Depending on your role with Company ABC you may be asked to communicate with various business units. Collaborating with others in different job functions is an important skill to master. If you have worked for a larger organization, you might have experience working in a cross-functional or cross-departmental environment. If you are newer to your career, think back to a time when you collaborated in a team sport, a volunteer role or group project.", "\"I collaborate with procurement, the HR department when it comes to managing our temporary employees, and also sales so that we have an idea of upcoming order volumes. I  have worked in a cross-functional setting for many years. I email or talk to around six different departments in any given week. What works best for me, to flourish in this environment, is to lead with respectful communication, be clear on needs, and also to have a solid understanding of others' job function. This approach allows me to know who to approach on certain subjects.\"", "\"My internship was with a smaller company that ran flat; however, I did work alongside a variety of job functions, including procurement, logistics, and customer service. I gained a lot of exposure to team environments while obtaining my degree. I enjoyed group projects because they allowed me to let my strengths shine while also learning about and respecting the strengths of others. I look forward to learning more about cross-departmental collaboration in my time with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Company ABC cares about environmental responsibility. What do you think of our sustainability efforts?", "answers": ["To understand the sustainability efforts at Company ABC, you will need to do in-depth research into their operations. You can do this on their website, or through an online search. Environmental sustainability is a hot topic in the meat production industry today, so you must show an understanding of how important these efforts are.", "\"I have read through your promise to your customers when it comes to food safety and sustainability efforts. I appreciate the action you are taking when it comes to streamlining your product packaging as well as the reduction of water use in your production facilities. Our environment is a matter that everyone should care about, and I am happy to see the great strides that Company ABC is making to be an industry leader in these efforts.\"", "\"I wish that every company was as eco-conscious and responsible as Company ABC. I read through your whitepaper online and was thrilled to see that you are making strides to reduce carbon emissions and water use in all of your facilities.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Are you applying to any Company ABC competitors?", "answers": ["There are a few reasons why an interviewer would like to know more about your other job applications. The primary goal is to understand what stage you are in, with other companies who are entertaining you for employment. Other reasons include a desire to understand better the roles that are of interest to you, and which companies you see value in joining. \n\nYou are certainly not obligated to disclose every detail of your job search. You should, however, give a helpful answer that will let the interviewer gauge the kind of timeline you are working with before accepting a job offer.", "\"I have a keen interest in joining this industry, and for that reason, have applied to the top three most esteemed companies in meat production. Next week, I have a telephone interview booked with Company ABC and a second interview booked with Company XYZ. With that said, I am most excited about this opportunity with Company ABC because your team seems the most professional, welcoming, and informative.\"", "\"I have not applied to any direct competitors of Company ABC; however, I have applied to a variety of food production roles in dairy, poultry, and confections. It's important to me that I begin my career with a company that is responsible and has a reputation for excellent product quality.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Who do you believe to be the key customers of Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have researched who they serve. Many companies will list their key customers or accounts on their website. Check out the Company ABC website and do some digging online to see what you can find. What is most important is for you to be able to understand who their target customer is. If you do not know, this is an excellent time to ask some insightful questions!", "\"I believe the key customers of your organization to be grocery retailers of all sizes in the region of A, B, and C. Your meat is produced humanely, and hormone-free. For this reason, I think that your organization has a solid approach with retailers whose customers are eco and ethically conscious. Is this accurate to say?\"", "\"After researching Company ABC online, I learned that your top customers are A, B, and C. I was able to read a few customer testimonials on your website which were all very helpful and positive. I look forward to working at Company ABC, helping you to nurture and grow these important client relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "What is the primary factor that separates Company ABC products from other meat producers?", "answers": ["You may hear this question in a few forms, such as: \n\n- Why do you want to work at Company ABC? \n- Why work for Company ABC as opposed to our competitors? \n- What does Company ABC do better than anyone else?\n\nThe hiring authority wants to hear a genuine and well-researched answer. Interviewers too often hear bland answers that are general and non-specific. You are a stand-out candidate, and it's time that you show off the considerable research you have performed on their organization. Dig deep to figure out what it really would mean to you to work for Company ABC versus their competitors. You can focus on their product quality, their core values, or their employee happiness and tenure for starters.", "\"I want to join a company for the long term. This desire is why I did a lot of research on Company ABC and your competitors before applying. What I appreciate most is the care and research that you put into your products before introducing them to consumers. This approach has resulted in fewer recalls and better consumer reviews overall. I am seeking out an organization that acts as more than just a meat producer, but also an industry leader.\"", "\"Before applying to Company ABC I performed extensive research on the organization as well as your three largest competitors worldwide. Your employee reviews are solid, and on Glassdoor, the CEO approval rating is higher than anyone else. These results show me that your culture is healthy and this starts from the top. The trickle-down impact means happy customers which is another significant factor for me as I consider my next career move.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "What does CPG stand for? Do you have experience working in the CPG industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer is checking for your understanding of simple terms related to the meat production and food industry.  CPG stands for Consumer Packaged Goods. Various items fall into the CPG category, but for the most part, we reserve the term for things that consumers use regularly. CPG products can include food, beverage, even clothing, and household products. Determine how Company ABC falls into the CPG category and then be prepared to explain what you understand CPG to mean. Next, take a few moments to walk the interviewer through your experience in the CPG industry. Outline the products you have worked with, and inside of which companies. If you are new to your career, be sure to show a solid understanding of the industry while expressing your keen interest in learning more about CPG at Company ABC.", "\"CPG stands for Consumer Packaged Goods and refers to many items that consumers use daily. I have worked in the CPG industry for the past eight years, first within the clothing and textiles industry with Company ABC and then moving into food and beverage with Company XYZ. I much prefer working within the food and beverage industry because of the fast pace and exciting food trends that I get to be a part of.\"", "\"I have researched CPG before interviewing at Company ABC today, knowing that knowledge of Consumer Packaged Goods industry would be helpful in the interview process. I have worked in a retail environment surrounded by CPGs, such as my time with ABC Grocery and XYZ Clothing. I understand consumer packaged goods to be items that people use every day, such as food, clothing, and personal care items.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "How would you grow an existing account to include more Company ABC product?", "answers": ["This question will test your knowledge of selling based on value. This question will also help the interviewer to see your depth of understanding when it comes to their business. Whether you are interviewing for a sales role or not, it's essential to show an understanding of how their company operates. \n\nThe best way to grow an existing account is first to identify which products they are not currently purchasing. Then, you will want to get to know the client so that you can make educated recommendations. Being an advocate for your company and its brand(s) is another incredibly important factor in upselling existing accounts. Show the interviewer at Company ABC that you are excited about their products and that you will pass this excitement on to their existing customer base.", "\"If given the opportunity to grow existing accounts at Company ABC, I would begin by combing through your CRM and uncovering which companies purchase only a couple of your meat products. I would discover which ones they have not yet been introduced to, and then determine if the addition of this product could make sense for their business. It would be important that, before approaching the account, that I had a full understanding of how their business operates. I would also be sure to approach the account with full enthusiasm and robust product knowledge.\"", "\"Although my sales experience is limited, I have a great instinct when it comes to recommending products and determining need. If given an existing account to grow, I would check in and build a relationship based on the Company ABC products that they already purchase and enjoy. From that point, I could make more educated recommendations. I would be prepared with numbers so that I could show margins and other important factors that clients would need to make a decision.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Name your favorite Company ABC product, and discuss why it is your favorite.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see your investment when it comes to earning a position at Company ABC. Part of being an engaged candidate is being aware of the product range offered at Company ABC and trying their range of products whenever possible. Show that you have taken the time to get to know their variety of meat products. Which ones do you find to be the most innovative, delicious, or convenient?", "\"Company ABC offers so many premier meat products, but I believe that the best thing you offer your customers is Product ABC. This product has been my favorite because it's satisfying, ethically sourced, and full of flavor. I also appreciate, as an eco-conscious consumer, that you do not overpackage your products.\"", "\"It seems that Company ABC genuinely cares when it comes to the quality that families have come to expect from its brand. My favorite product from Company ABC is your ABC Product. The offering is consistent, full of flavor, and always fresh.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Tell me about your food-related health and safety training. Are there any gaps in your knowledge that we should address?", "answers": ["When working in the meat production industry, you may need to learn how to safely work around products such as animals, chemicals, raw ingredients, and more. \n\nTake the interviewer through any formal health and safety training that you have received either on-the-job or during your post-secondary education. If you are newer to your career, ask the interviewer what you can do to prepare yourself for success in this role.", "\"When it comes to health and safety training, I have certification in Safety Hygiene, Food Quality, and Food Audits. I have also taken various OHS courses through my past two employers. Although my training is extensive, this will be my first role in a dedicated meat production environment. If you have recommendations on additional courses to prepare myself, I am happy to get started.\"", "\"My training consists of a small amount of OHS training during my internship at ABC Meats. Is there a particular course I can begin before starting this role with Company ABC? I aim to have a perfect safety record in my career, and put hygiene and proper product handling first in everything that I do.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Walk me through your education in supply chain or logistics.", "answers": ["Many roles at Company ABC require you to have higher education in supply chain or logistics. This education may include Lean & Six Sigma training, a certificate in Supply Chain, all the way to an MBA with a focus on supply chain management. Discuss any training and education you have that will apply to this role. Don't forget to mention any self-led coursework you have taken, or on the job certifications that you may have received. If you do not possess the education basics requested by Company ABC this is the time to sell your candidacy by leaning on transferable skills and on-the-job experiences.", "\"I have a Bachelor's Degree in Logistics & Supply Chain Management. In addition to this degree, I also hold a CPSM designation, which refers to Certified Professional in Supply  Management. Continued education is important to me. I am considering further education to include an MBA with a focus on finance, allowing me to better approach budgeting and the financial needs of the food production industry.\"", "\"Everything that I have achieved in the food production industry comes from on-the-job training and close mentorship from my superiors along the way. I have nine years of experience in a meat production environment with a certificate in Occupational Health & Safety.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Are you willing and able to meet the scheduling demands at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Depending on your region, your employer may not be able to demand that you work more than 44 hours per week. However, inside industries like meat production, you may be required to be on-call, work evenings, weekends, holidays, and overtime. This requirement may be especially true if the operation runs 24/7. Feel free to ask for a sample schedule before committing. You don't want to commit to a work schedule that you cannot fulfill. Focus your answer on what you CAN do, ensuring that you give the interviewer a positive impression versus a 'can't do' attitude.", "\"I understand that Company ABC production runs long hours, and I am ready to deliver on your needs. I can be on call as scheduled, and begin with evening shifts. Are day shifts given based on tenure and seniority? I want to learn more about how your scheduling works.\"", "\"I am prepared to work overtime, evenings, weekends, and even some holidays. I am flexible and dedicated to gaining momentum in my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Have you ever held any inventory management responsibilities? If so, what tools did you use to manage your inventory?", "answers": ["It's time to show the interviewer that you can handle the responsibilities associated with this role! In the food production industry, you must understand how critical inventory is. Products move fast and Company ABC must always be ready to meet consumer demands. At the same time, it's necessary never to produce too much, causing financial loss due to overproduction. \n\nSome standard terms in inventory management include fill rate, sales ratio, and days-on-hand inventory (DOH). Take time to learn about stock and logistics if you are new to the industry. Tools commonly used for inventory management and general management in the food industry include Sage, Vicinity, MRPeasy, Prodsmart, and more. Show the interviewer that you are familiar with the importance of proper inventory management.", "\"In my current role, I hold a great deal of inventory management responsibility. Using Sage100, I track the financials and supply chain regularly. From this system, I perform all reporting and analysis tasks. This system helps me to find errors and discrepancies, document corrections, and reconcile inventory levels when needed. It's critical for organizations like Company ABC to carefully track all of these factors. This way, you can remain on schedule, reduce waste, and be ready to distribute your product based on demand.\"", "\"Although my experience in managing, or being responsible for inventory is limited, I have a full understanding of how critical the need is for an organization like Company ABC. I read in your job posting that you use Vicinity software for activities such as batch ticketing, lot traceability and recall, production planning, quality control, and compliance reporting. I look forward to becoming an expert in this critical area of business.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "In addition to this role, which Company ABC department are you most interested in learning?", "answers": ["To be successful in your career, it's crucial that you understand the ins and outs of Company ABC business, from the perspective of more than just your position. \n\nYour targeted job title aside, where would you want to gain knowledge when it comes to the overall operations at Company ABC? Some department options may be marketing, HR, data and analytics, finance, or even research and development. \n\nTo learn more about their departments, check out the Company ABC careers site and take a look at how they organize their job openings.", "\"I have always worked in sales and marketing, and my success is directly related to my product knowledge. For that reason, I would choose to learn about the product development process at Company ABC. I would love to learn how Company ABC makes decisions when it comes to product launches, flavor choices, and more.\"", "\"My degree is in Agriculture, and for that reason, I have a lot of knowledge in animal science. To complement this knowledge, I would like to get to know the R&D process at Company ABC. I believe an opportunity in research could give me the full-circle knowledge needed to succeed in this role.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "How do you plan to drive Company ABC sales performance in your first three months?", "answers": ["Before your interview, you should have a good idea of the actions you will take to ensure a great start to your employment. This question is more appropriate if you are joining the organization in a sales or customer service based position. \n\nThink about the simple ways that you can contribute to the performance of Company ABC brands and products during your first 90 days. Your ideas do not need to be complicated. The interviewer simply wants to see that you are already making plans to be successful in this position.", "\"To begin, I will be highly dedicated to my training, taking my work home, and gaining stealth product knowledge as fast as possible. Once fully trained, I will take the time to comb through your CRM and create touch-points with customers who have stopped ordering or have significantly reduced their orders over the past twelve months. I will get to know their buying habits and reach out with product-based solutions.\"", "\"My plan in my first three months at Company ABC is to call on my client list and make in-person appointments whenever possible. Relationships are important to me, and if I start with a great initial meeting, I will be more confident to upsell down the road. I also plan to open four new accounts in my first month, after my training is complete. I like to exceed expectations and will aim to do so as soon as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "What are some challenges the meat industry will face over the next couple of years?", "answers": ["Understanding challenges in the meat industry will help you to give stronger responses during your interviews. The more you know, the more you show the interviewer that you are engaged in the interview process. Your knowledge will build confidence in the decision-maker that you are the top choice for Company ABC. \n\nSome obstacles in the meat or animal production industry include global trade, constant regulation changes, taxation, tight profit margins, and social issues related to meat consumption. Talk about an article you recently read or statistics that you found interesting, as it relates to the meat industry.", "\"I believe that ever-changing diet trends can be a significant pain point for any company in the animal-based protein industry. One day, meat-based diets such as paleo and keto are popular, and the next day, everyone decides that a plant-based diet is the way to go. These trends can impact sales significantly, and can also affect the type of products that a meat producer chooses to push out.\"", "\"From my research, I believe that government regulations can greatly impact the meat production industry. This year we have already begun to see significant changes in trade law, and less animal-based products exported as a result. Would you agree that this topic has been significant for Company ABC this year?\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals who are passionate about the meat production industry. What do you do to stay on top of industry news and trends?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants assurance that you have a keen and genuine interest in their industry. Be prepared to speak briefly about the ways you stay up to date on new trends and hot topics in the industry.  If you are new to your career, you can ask the interviewer how they stay up to date, asking for recommendations and showing a willingness to learn.", "\"I am very interested in responsible meat production, and also trends in animal protein consumption. Recently I took on the challenge of learning how to smoke meat and make my own jerky. I find this is a fun way to learn how different proteins respond to various cooking applications. I follow sources such as Meat Science, the USDA journal, and a few food science podcasts to stay in-the-know on trends and changes in this industry.\"", "\"I just began learning about the meat production industry and have found resources such as the Company ABC blog to be beneficial. I am open to suggestions outside of this resource if you would like to point me in the right direction.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Consumer happiness is our number one priority at Company ABC. What are some ways we can ensure consumer satisfaction?", "answers": ["When it comes to food production, consumer satisfaction means everything. The interviewer would like to know how you feel they can ensure consumer satisfaction in each product produced and released by Company ABC. Show that you have a firm idea of what it takes to deliver high-quality, consumable consumer product.", "\"There are endless opportunities to ensure consumer satisfaction in the food industry. I have found, through my years of industry experience, its best to listen to what consumers are asking for. I also recommend transparency when it comes to ingredients and production process. It's also essential to remain ethical when it comes to the treatment of animals in animal-derived products. Company ABC does all of this very well, which is why I am thrilled to have the opportunity to work here.\"", "\"Consumers are happiest when they feel they are getting a high-quality product at a good price. Today, it's all about a mix of responsibility, value, and ethics; all things that I have seen Company ABC deliver for many years.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "Do you have any concerns related to working in the meat production industry, or for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Meat production can come with controversy and, depending on the role you are looking to land with Company ABC you may be closer to this controversy than others. Try to keep your concerns light and manageable for any interviewer. It's important to remember that if you have big red flags about the meat production industry or Company ABC themselves, this may not be the right position for you. \n\nHave a question or two prepared, and make them as conversational as possible. Consider asking what the biggest hurdle is for Company ABC this year, or what types of roadblocks the last person in this role encountered. Your inquiries should come across as thoughtful rather than criticism.", "\"At this point, I do not have concerns about Company ABC or the meat production industry. With that said, I am hoping you could shed more light on the biggest challenges the meat production industry is currently facing? Whether it be regulation changes or trade concerns; I want to come prepared for all challenges in this role.\"", "\"Company ABC looks like an excellent place to work with highly valued employees and strong attention to safety. Could you share with me the biggest challenge in this role, in the first 90 days? I plan to be completely prepared for the challenges that come with starting a new career in a complex industry like meat production.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "What would you do if a customer asked you about a Company ABC product and you were unsure of the answer?", "answers": ["Depending on how many SKU's or product varieties are available from Company ABC, you may not be able to know every product inside and out. At least not right away! Talk to the interviewer about your reaction when you do not have the answer to a customers' questions. Be sure to express your willingness to seek out the right answer by utilizing the resources you have at hand, or leaning on a team member senior to you. You will want to express your ability to be confident and independent in your thinking!", "\"I will always take the time to find a solution, using the resources provided to me by my company. Rather than saying 'I don't know' to a customer, I would much rather say 'I will find out.' If I cannot find an answer using company resources and manuals, I will ask my supervisor or a more knowledgable coworker.\"", "\"I enjoy a good challenge, so bring on the questions! The more I have to research and learn, the faster I will be able to help Company ABC customers fully. I think it is important that I am honest with the customer and let them know that I need to find the right answer for them. I would thank them for asking their question and challenging me as a Company ABC ambassador.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "What do you know about meat alternatives and the impact they have made on the meat production industry?", "answers": ["Meat alternatives or meat substitutes such as produces made from soy, peas, beans, and legumes are on the rise as more people adopt a vegetarian or vegan diet. Products such as 'Beyond Meat' are taking the meat industry by storm; however, there remains considerable controversy on whether or not these products are healthier in the long run. Discuss what you know about meat alternatives and how you believe they have impacted the meat production industry lately.", "\"The rise of meatless products is certainly a factor that the meat production industry should notice. However, I do not feel that we are in danger of losing a ton of market share. Products such as veggie burgers and tofu dogs have been around for a very long time. In any industry, there will be a product that shakes things up for a while. I am not concerned that things like a 'Beyond Meat' burger will take over a real beef burger anytime soon. It's only around 3.2% of the US population who identify as vegetarian and an even smaller .5% who identify as vegan. Meat products will remain king for good, I believe.\"", "\"I understand that meat alternatives are on the rise, so the meat production industry needs to remain steadfast in our marketing. It's a tiny percentage of people in North America who are vegan or vegetarian, and many are not aware of the negative impact that soy-based alternatives can have on their health. I know some products have made a big splash lately; however, I do not feel any of them are strong enough to take away a significant and consistent market share from the meat industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "How would you approach getting along with a difficult supervisor, coworker, or client?", "answers": ["How you interact with difficult people says a great deal about you. Think back to a time when you had a strained relationship with a supervisor, coworker, or client. Maybe it took you a while to warm them up to the point where they were friendly towards you. You must show the interviewer your ability to persevere even in uncomfortable situations. Highlight your ability to work alongside a variety of personalities while remaining productive and positive. Avoid speaking poorly of anyone in your past roles, as this would only reflect negatively on you. Be sure to end your response on a positive note!", "\"I once had a client who was very demanding and aggressive on the phone. Nobody in our department wanted to answer the phone when he called. I took it upon myself to become the clients' main point of contact since I seem to have the thickest skin in these situations. When he would call, I was very to-the-point, didn't waste his time with small talk, but was of course very cordial. After a few successful calls, I started to add in comments such as 'I appreciate that you are so organized!' and 'When you call knowing what you need, it makes my job so much easier!' These compliments on his efficiency warmed him up a bit. Now, he calls asking for me, and we are on a friendly basis.\"", "\"I understand from my internship that the food production industry attracts a large variety of personalities. I am friendly and, during my internship, found it a touch challenging to connect with my supervisor, who was more 'matter-of-fact.' I did some online research on how to best communicate with her personality type and adapted. This relationship during my three-week internship wasn't the deepest, but I made it work. This situation will occur throughout my career, and I will choose to do the same; educate myself and adapt.\""]}, {"topic": "Meat+Producer", "question": "How do you cope in a situation where rules and regulations are unclear?", "answers": ["When instructions are not explicit, are you the type of person who can adapt and find the answers on your own, or do you feel lost without clear direction? Many of us are a bit of both; not completely independent but still able to manage on our own when push comes to shove. Talk to the interviewer how you go about achieving goals independently. Offer up an example of a time when you had to cope with very few guidelines, showcasing your ability to do your job and do what's right.", "\"Through my career, I have joined a couple of organizations where guidelines and procedures were a touch muddled. I had to do a lot of independent research and also followed my instinct when it came to doing what I felt was right for the company and our customer. I found a middle ground that kept me productive while still appeasing stakeholders. I am comfortable in situations where I need to figure things out but always appreciate having a baseline from which to begin.\"", "\"As a recent graduate, I do appreciate clear guidelines and expectations. When joining Company ABC in this new role, hope that my team will use their training, knowledge, and intuition to help me along the way. As I become better versed in the role, I will, of course, be able to fill in the blanks by myself more and more.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "At Company ABC we focus on hiring individuals who want to grow with us. Where do you see yourself in the next 2-5 years?", "answers": ["Hiring new team members is an expensive endeavor. Assure the interviewer that their investment in you would be worth it. Refer to your previous tenure and talk about your company loyalty. How does Company ABC fit in with your future career plans?", "\"You can see in my resume that I have strong loyalty and tenure. My career plans include growing with Company ABC in a management based role as I prove my skills. I would be happy to find a long-term fit with your company.\"", "\"2-5 years from now, I would like to be supervising or managing a team of my own. I feel like I am progressing at a rate that will make this a possibility.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $30,000 per year plus tips.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "What do you feel is the most important characteristic in order to be successful with Company ABC?", "answers": ["It is essential to research Company ABC before your interview. In your research try to find information on their company values and other areas of focus. Tie in those company values with your characteristics.", "\"Through my research on Company ABC I saw a theme surrounding honesty and diligence. I agree that these characteristics are fundamental. In addition to these, I would add a positive attitude and strong listening skills.\"", "Here are some other essential characteristics that you can draw on: \n\n- Disciplined \n- Intuitive \n- Takes Initiative \n- Responsible \n- Positive Attitude\n- Solid Communicator"]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answers": ["When an interviewer asks an open-ended question like this, it can be difficult to know where to begin...and end! This question haunts many individuals who may have accidentally gone a little too in-depth into their personal lives. It happens. Keep your reply light, and work relevant. Share how you became interested in this career path and what you enjoy about it. This question offers an excellent opportunity to describe yourself by discussing the strengths and qualities that you bring.", "\"I am a competitive individual who is driven and likes to win. In addition to my successful sales career, I also spend time playing competitive sports. I give back by volunteering at the local animal shelter and working for a variety of annual fundraisers in our community.\"", "\"A bit about me - I love to travel, read, and conduct research. I am a recent grad from Columbia University and have spent the past 12 months traveling the world. It was the best experience that I could have given myself as I was able to learn so much from seeing how the rest of the world lives. I returned to the US just last month and have been actively looking for work the past couple of weeks. I am looking forward to getting into the routine of a career again.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Are you of legal age to serve alcoholic beverages to our patrons?", "answers": ["Most establishments based in recreation, restaurant, resort, or hotel will serve alcoholic beverages. In most states, it is not legal for a hiring manager to ask the age of the interviewer but they do need to ensure that you are legally able to serve alcoholic beverages. Do not feel pressured to disclose your age. A simple yes or no answer is sufficient.", "\"I am not yet of legal age to serve alcohol but assure you that I am capable in every other area of the position.\"", "\"I am of legal age to serve alcohol, yes. I did bring ID with me to this interview if you need a copy.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "If you had a co-worker call in sick and you were asked to take over their project requiring overtime from you, how would you react? Where do you draw the line when it comes to being a team player?", "answers": ["Show your confidence to your interviewer by explaining your willingness to be part of the team and not being afraid to pick up the slack when needed, but make sure you don't allow someone to take advantage of you.", "\"I will always choose to be a team player. If I had a co-worker call in sick, I would take over what I was capable. The only time I would draw the line would be if I felt I was being taken advantage of. For example, if they were purposefully being inefficient and expecting me to pick up the slack. For the sake of the company, I am always willing to go above and beyond what is expected of me.\"", "\"When it comes to being a team player, I draw the line when my co-workers are uncooperative or taking advantage of my kindness. I am always happy to help but will not be walked on.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the biggest change in this industry over the past 3 years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Yes, I would like to know what is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months?\"", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "What do you enjoy doing in your free time?", "answers": ["If you are a part of any organizations, sports teams or clubs, talk about your involvement. Share the role you play and your contribution as well as what you enjoy about it. If you enjoy other activities like writing, hiking or spending time with friends, talk about those too. This question gives the interviewer a chance to get to know you. They are interested in learning about your personality and what motivates you. If any of your outside activities related to this position, definitely share the skills you have learned and the similarities.", "\"My absolute favorite thing to do is to travel. So far, my favorite destination has been Barbados. The beaches are incredible. I also play basketball with my brother most weekends.\"", "\"I love to read in my free time and spend as much time as I can doing that. I can be found reading anything from a 19th-century piece of British literature to the latest dystopian fantasy novel.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Do you have any food safety training or health and safety related certifications?", "answers": ["Health and safety is the main priority for most recreation, hotel, and restaurant based organizations. Walk the interviewer through any related training.", "\"I have had training in my past three roles in regards to health and safety, and well as proper food handling. If there is additional training that you require me to participate in, I am happy to do so.\"", "\"I am new to the workforce and, having just graduated from High School; I do not have additional training in health or safety. If you have any required coursework related to this position with Company ABC, I am happy to get a head start on that training.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Do you feel that you are currently paid what you are worth?", "answers": ["Many employees will look for new work if they feel that they are underpaid and underappreciated. Talk to the interviewer about your current compensation and whether or not you think it is fair. \n\nIf you feel you are currently paid what you are worth: 'I feel that my current employer pays me fairly; however, I would like to see an increase in pay with an increase in responsibilities.' \n\nIf you do not feel you are currently paid what you are worth: 'I know that I am underpaid compared to my industry colleagues. My company is small, and they do what they can, but this is part of why I am seeking a new position.'", "\"Yes, I believe I am paid accurately by my current company. They are not as reputable in the industry and therefore, pay less for their employees. That is why I am looking elsewhere for a job, to promote myself.\"", "\"Yes, I am always striving to add value to an organization. I feel this is the best way to ensure that I receive fair compensation.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "As an employee with Company ABC you will be required to handle cash and other types of customer transactions. Do you consider yourself a trustworthy and honest person?", "answers": ["Can you be trusted with company money, and company product? Draw on the strength of your references and assure the interviewer that you are a trustworthy and honest employee.", "\"One of my greatest strengths as an employee is my level of honesty and trustworthiness. I have multiple references who will attest to the fact that I am competent and honest. I have experience handling large amounts of cash and have never had a discrepancy.\"", "\"I see myself and trustworthy and honest! My integrity has never been questioned, and my most recent supervisor will be happy to give you a solid reference regarding my reliability and transparent approach in the workplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Why did you leave your last job?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know why you chose to move on from your most recent position.\n\nAn excellent response would be to say, =I was ready to take on a new challenge,\" or \"there was no room for growth in that position.\" \n\nIt's always best to draw attention to what you are moving onto rather than focusing on what was wrong with what you left. It's understandable to want a new challenge or to desire to learn new things. So share what you're interested in getting out of this unique opportunity! \n\nIf you left involuntarily, explain why and be willing to admit fault. Show what you learned from the situation and how you want to prevent that issue from happening again.", "\"Unfortunately I was laid off from my last position because the location where I was based, was shut down. It was one of the quieter locations in the city. I was offered the opportunity to work at the Northern location; however, transportation deemed too difficult.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Have you received any formal industry training in your previous roles?", "answers": ["Many restaurants, hotel, and leisure based companies will have an internal employee training program. Talk to the interviewer about any specialized training you have received in your career.", "\"With Company ABC and Company XYZ I received two-week in-house training which included topics on best-practices, health and safety, and up-selling. They were beneficial training programs. Can you tell me a bit more about your training program here at Company ABC?\"", "\"I am new to the workforce and have not experienced a lot in the way of industry training. I do have my food safety certificate and look forward to gaining even more training through this role with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "In our industry you will come across some difficult customers. How do you handle an upset customer?", "answers": ["Are you able to brush it off when a customer is rude to you, or do you take it personally? Assure the interviewer that you can keep professional composure when it comes to rude or demanding customers.", "\"I have spent many years working in the restaurant, hotel, and other customer service based industries. I do not take it personally anymore when a customer is rude or difficult. I will do my best to make them happy, but I fully understand that you cannot appease everyone.\"", "\"I handle an upset customer with utmost care! I listen, and do my best to help fix whatever issue they feel is upsetting them.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "There are many job options for you in this industry. Why do you specifically want to work with Company ABC?", "answers": ["With many options in the industry for employment, why do you want to work for Company ABC? Talk to the interviewer about your preference for their company.", "\"I am careful to be employed with a company that holds a strong industry reputation. I'd like to work for Company ABC because your training programs are above the industry standard and you have a reputation for treating your employees very well.\"", "\"I especially want to work for Company ABC because I have friends who have worked here before with really positive feedback on their experiences. I am looking for a positive work environment where I can stay for a long time to come.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "At Company ABC we value our customers and always put them first. Do you agree with the phrase 'The customer is always right'?", "answers": ["'The customer is always right' has been a long-standing mantra for most customer-service based industries like restaurants, hotels, and recreation-based organizations. Do you agree with this mantra? Why, or why not?", "\"Although I believe that the customer is not always right - it's important to treat them as though they are. Within the limitations of health and safety, etc.; I believe it's best to accommodate the customer within reason.\"", "\"Some customers are quite impossible to please so I would not go so far to say that the customer is always right. With that said, I do treat every customer with the utmost respect and do put their needs first in all reasonable situations.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "This position requires you to work around children. Is there any reason why you would not agree to a full criminal background check?", "answers": ["For many recreational, hotel, resort, and restaurant based organizations you will need to be vetted before gaining the position. Assure the interviewer that you can pass a criminal record check. If you have a criminal record, this is the time to disclose it.", "\"I am happy to participate in a full criminal background check. I have a clean record.\"", "\"I will disclose to you that I received a DUI in 2014 but do not have any other marks on my criminal record.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Some positions with Company ABC require you to be available on weekends, evenings, and holidays. Is there anything in your schedule preventing you from being available?", "answers": ["Being in this particular industry will require you to be flexible in your availability. Assure the interviewer that you can handle the schedule associated with this role.", "\"I am accustomed to working a wide range of shifts that include evenings, weekends, holidays and a large amount of voluntary overtime. I enjoy working and am happy to work whenever required.\"", "\"I am very flexible with my schedule except for Wednesday evenings, when I attend my night courses. Other than that evening, I am willing to accommodate any of your scheduling needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of focus on grooming our star players into leadership roles. Do you have any interest in a management role with us down the road?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you have an interest in being groomed into a leadership role down the road. What potential do you see for yourself with Company ABC?", "\"After researching the culture at Company ABC I am very interested in forging a career in management with you. I feel that I am a natural leader and would be proud to grow my career with your company.\"", "\"I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career goals align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long-term fit here.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "At Company ABC we invest a lot of time into our loss prevention program. What would you do if you caught a co-worker stealing?", "answers": ["Most professional organizations have a loss prevention program in place. Assure the interviewer that you are willing to be an active participant when it comes to preventing theft within their organization.", "\"If I caught a co-worker stealing, I would report the incident immediately. I am sure that Company ABC has loss prevention steps in place and I would be sensitive to those procedures before reacting to the perceived theft.\"", "\"I am sure that you have an internal policy for employee theft so I can assure you that I would follow the required steps to report the theft. I am a trustworthy person with a strong track record of honesty with my previous employers.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Do you consider yourself a team player?", "answers": ["The answer to this question should always be, yes! No matter where you work, you need to be a team player, to help your company achieve its goals. Be prepared with an energetic and enthusiastic, 'Yes, I am!'\n\nExpand on this answer by sharing your philosophy on the importance of teamwork and being an active part of a team. Show the interviewer you understand that it takes a group of people for a company to achieve its goals, and you recognize that each person is a piece of the puzzle.", "\"I recognize that there may be days where I need to perform duties outside of my usual job description to help out. For instance, in my current role, I may occasionally need to spend additional time mentoring and coaching new employees to ensure they fit in with the team. This responsibility creates a tighter timeline for my other important deadlines; however, I see that the end goal is to create a well-oiled machine and that cannot happen without everyone being equally trained.\"", "\"I would certainly say I'm a team player. I've been in organized sports my entire life, so I know that without a team, you can't accomplish very much. I value the relationships I have formed from working in teams throughout my life, not to mention how much I have learned from my coworkers when collaborating across departments or the hierarchy of the organization. All in all, I know the importance of a team and I work very well in a collaborative environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Tell me about your leadership qualities.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know what you consider to be strong leadership qualities. When describing leadership qualities, try to avoid general terms and give some unique ideas. \n\nA great leader is someone who people naturally want to follow. They have exceptional interpersonal skills and the ability to build relationships with nearly any personality type. A respected leader will take ownership of their mistakes and will always lead their team by example. True leaders see the importance of motivating others and recognizing even the smallest achievements. With which of these qualities do you most identify?", "\"I have taken many workshops and courses to improve my leadership skills over the years. My leadership qualities are best summed as dedicated, attentive, and motivating. I like to recognize my employees' small wins because that motivates them to continue achieving.\"", "\"To me, a leader is someone who is enthusiastic, knowledgeable, adaptable, and open. A leader wants to nurture others to their fullest potential, and that is something I have enjoyed doing since childhood.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "On a scale from 1 to 10, how honest are you?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you are a sincere person or do you have room for growth? This question could be a tricky one as nobody is always 100% honest. Answer to the best of your ability and back your reply by speaking about your ethics.", "\"I would love to give myself a 10/10 for honesty but truthfully - nobody is 100% honest all of the time. I will give myself an nine because I always do my best to be as honest as possible.\"", "\"I put a heavy focus on honesty and trustworthiness in the workplace, as well as in my personal life.  Because I strive for complete honesty, I will rate myself as a 10/10. My values are solid.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Do you have reliable transportation?", "answers": ["Even if you're not expected to drive for the job, you will need to have some form of reliable transportation. If you take the bus or ride a bike, that works too! Merely share that you have the means to get to work consistently and on time.", "\"I have reliable transportation. I have a well-maintained vehicle, and I am comfortable with the amount of travel required to get to your office every day.\"", "\"I take public transit; however, I find it to be very reliable. I was late to work only once last year, and that was due to a snowstorm which stalled all of our employee's commute - including those with personal vehicles. Rest assured, I am reliable and will always come to work on time.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "How do you handle stress on the job?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Looking at your resume, I see multiple gaps between employments, what were you doing during those gaps?", "answers": ["There are many reasons for having a gap in your resume, and it's best, to be honest about the reasons for the timeline discrepancies.", "\"I had a gap from 2014-2015 while I was on maternity leave and then another for six months in 2015 while I cared for an ailing parent. During that time I was vigilant in keeping up to date on the market so that my knowledge did not become redundant.\"", "\"Thank you for addressing this with me. There were a few gaps where I took some time to further my education and attend schooling for additional certification in hospitality.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Tell me about a time when you led a team. What was your biggest success factor?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to hear about a time that you led a team, with a positive outcome. Highlight for the interviewer the primary factors that made your leadership style a success. Your example could come from the workplace or perhaps a time when you led a group project during your post-secondary studies.", "\"Just last month I was asked to lead our day shift employees when my boss was away on sick leave. I took charge for two weeks, and the experience was quite positive! I believe the biggest success factor was that I tried to emulate his leadership style and did ask his help when I wasn't sure what to do. I feel this experience prepared me for a leadership role. I am excited to take on a team lead role again.\"", "\"Our company had a sales contest last month, and I was asked to be our team leader for the challenge. I enjoyed that responsibility, and we ended up winning the reward in the end because my team increased sales by the highest percentage.\""]}, {"topic": "Restaurants+and+Leisure", "question": "Do you think it is possible to be a good team member, yet disagree with the leader?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can be diplomatic in the workplace, even when you may not agree with your leader. \n\nShow the interviewer that it is possible for you to be a good team member, yet disagree with the leader from time to time. Explain that you believe everyone is entitled to their own professional opinion, yet capable of maintaining respect for each other at the same time. \n\nShow that even if you disagree with the final decision they make, you support the direction the team is heading.", "\"I think that it is possible to be a great team member, even when disagreeing with the leader. It's all in how you maintain respect for each other despite the difference in opinion.\"", "\"Yes, I think it is possible! What makes a great team member is not that they agree with everything but the level of respect and positive thought that goes into the person's communication style. It's okay to disagree you have to communicate your thoughts professionally.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "At Company ABC we value our customers and always put them first. Do you agree with the phrase 'The customer is always right'?", "answers": ["'The customer is always right' has been a long-standing mantra for service-based organizations. Do you agree with this mantra? Why, or why not? The interviewer would like to see you respond positively. If possible, take a look at the company website to see what their mantra or customer service statement is.", "\"Although I believe that the customer is not always right - it's important to treat them as though they are. Within the limitations of health and safety, etc.; I believe it's best to accommodate the customer within reason.\"", "\"Some customers are quite impossible to please so I would not go so far to say that the customer is always right. With that said, I do treat every customer with the utmost respect and do put their needs first in all reasonable situations.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Have you ever had a table 'dine and dash'? If so, how did you handle the situation?", "answers": ["'Dine and dash' occurs when customers of a restaurant leave without paying their tab. Often, the culprits will order the most expensive item on the menu, and the best bottles of wine, or order the highest end cocktails. There are ways that a restaurant can handle a 'dine and dash' situation, including having a host at the front door, having a highly attentive service standard, and getting to know the name of your guests. The interviewer would like to see if you have been in this terrible situation, and how you reacted.", "\"I have had one table dine and dash in my serving career. It was an unfortunate experience and bothered me because I continued to wonder what I could have done differently. I thought the couple had gone out for a cigarette break, but in reality, left without paying. If I witnessed the act, I would run out and look for a license plate number; however, I would not get into a physical altercation with the offender.\"", "\"I have been trained in how to handle a 'dine and dash' but have luckily never experienced the situation in person. Do you have training for this kind of situation? I see that your restaurant is well laid out, making it a challenge for someone to leave. I believe having the hostess station right at the door is a significant deterrent.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "We look for education from WSET (Wine & Spirit Education Trust). How many levels have you completed?", "answers": ["WSET (Wine & Spirit Education Trust) is a well-known organization through the restaurant industry, which provides courses and exams related to wine and spirit education. Many fine dining establishments prefer to hire those with some wine knowledge. Your education through WSET can include Level I, II, III, or IV for Wine and Spirits, and even Sake.  Discuss with the interviewer any formal training you may have from WSET, or other wine-related coursework.", "\"I have had a lifelong dream of becoming a sommelier one day. I have completed the Wine and Spirits Level I  Foundation Certificate and look forward to continuing my wine education.\"", "\"Although I have not taken coursework through WSET specifically, I have taken a couple of wine pairing classes through my neighborhood wine store. If you have a keen interest in hiring someone who will achieve WSET certification, I am happy to entertain this.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "At Company ABC, we require background checks on all employees. Will you comply?", "answers": ["To work for many high-end restaurant establishments, you will need proper vetting. Since you will be working around expensive food and alcohol products, you must assure the interviewer that you can pass a criminal record check. If you have a criminal record, this is the time to disclose it. In most cases, refusing to comply will result in your ineligibility for the role.", "\"I am happy to participate in a full criminal background check. I have a clean record.\"", "\"I will disclose to you that I received a DUI in 2014 but do not have any other marks on my criminal record. I am happy to comply with any background checks that you require.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Which aspect of serving do you dislike the most?", "answers": ["The intention of this question is not to hear you complain about the tasks that you do not like to do, as a server. Although the interviewer is technically asking for a critical answer, you will be a stand-out candidate by steering clear of the negative and focusing on the positive.", "\"As most servers will tell you, doing roll-ups or shining the utensils is the most tedious job, especially when you are preparing for a rush of customers. With that said, I take my time and am sure to be in the moment, knowing that it's all about the fine details.\"", "\"I make a conscious effort to do everything that I do, to the best of my ability. I may not enjoy the tedious counting and math associated with complicated cashouts, but it's always fun to see the ring-outs and tip amount at the end of a busy shift.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "How would you handle a co-worker who was acting unprofessionally towards our dining guests?", "answers": ["One difficult workplace situation is when a co-worker is not performing how they should be, yet, you may not be the manager or supervisor. The problem is - do you interfere or do you let it go? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have been in a position like this, and discuss what you did to remedy the situation.", "\"I once worked with a co-worker who unknowingly rolled her eyes a lot. Customers would be put off, and she wouldn't understand why her tips were so low. I asked her if she was open to receiving feedback, and she agreed. I went on to explain to her that she was an unintentional eye roller. She had no idea! We worked together for a few weeks on it, and she eventually retrained herself to no longer make that expression.\"", "\"I think it's important to the reputation of the restaurant that everyone, including myself, is held accountable for their behavior. If the restaurant receives a negative review, that can affect my livelihood as well. With that said, if a co-worker were unprofessional, I would discreetly pull them aside to discuss my concern.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "In high-end dining, you may come across very discerning customers. How do you handle a picky customer?", "answers": ["With high-end, fine dining usually comes customers who are very particular about their dining experience. Are you able to brush it off when a customer is extra picky, or do you take the event personally? Assure the interviewer that you can keep professional composure when it comes to demanding customers.", "\"I have spent many years working in the restaurant, hotel, and other customer service based industries. I no longer take it personally when a customer is picky or difficult. I will do my best to make them happy, but I fully understand that you cannot appease everyone.\"", "\"I handle an extra-choosy customer with utmost care! I listen, and do my best to deliver above their expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Do you feel that you are currently paid what you are worth?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you feel undervalued in your current role. Many employees will look for new work if they think that they are underpaid and underappreciated. Of course, this potential new employer wants to ensure that they will make you a competitive offer that will entice you to join their establishment, and stay there. Talk to the interviewer about your current compensation and whether or not you feel it is fair. Be sure to have researched your answer to back you up, versus throwing out a random number and hoping it will stick.", "\"I believe that I am ready for a restaurant manager position, which would bump up my pay quite significantly. I am paid fairly for being an assistant manager, but am craving an increase in responsibilities, which is why I am seeking out a new role.\"", "\"I feel that my current employer pays me fairly; however, I would like to see an increase in pay with an increase in responsibilities.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Have you dined here before? If so, describe your experience.", "answers": ["If you have a chance to dine at Company ABC before your interview, it's a great choice to make a reservation and have a first-hand look. If you have not eaten there before, be sure to express your interest in having the experience. Rely on any reviews you have read online or feedback that you have received from friends, family, or those in your network.", "\"I have dined at Company ABC once before, for a holiday party with a former employer. It was a private event, so I should point out that my experience, although marvelous, was not the typical dining experience. We ordered a huge array of delicious appetizers, and the cocktails were creative and paired very well with the food choices. I remember the service being very attentive as well.\"", "\"I came to Company ABC on a date night just one month ago. My experience was so wonderful; it's what prompted me to apply for a job here. I loved the atmosphere, the server was very attentive, and the menu was the best I have seen in a long time.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "What does the word 'hospitality' mean to you?", "answers": ["Hospitality is referring to the exchange between a customer and someone in the service industry. The hospitality industry can include restaurants, resorts, cruise ships, hotels, and even some recreation-based businesses. The interviewer understands what hospitality means, and now they want to see that you know the nuances behind providing excellent levels of hospitality to your guests.", "\"There is a famous quote by Maya Angelou that says, 'People will forget what you said, forget what you did, but people will never forget how you made them feel.' To me, hospitality is making my dining guests feel comfortable, cared for, and welcomed. They may forget a couple of months down the road what they ate, or which bottle of wine ordered, but they will remember leaving with a smile on their face.\"", "\"When a customer is smiling, appears relaxed, and tells me that they are coming back or recommending the restaurant to a friend, I know that I have delivered utmost hospitality. The concept is not only being hospitable but also making people want to have the experience again and again.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Explain to me, step by step, the proper way to serve wine.", "answers": ["Pop the cork. Chug. Okay - of course not. If you have been trained in the science of opening and serving wine, you will find this question simple to answer. There indeed is an art to proper wine service. \n\nEvery restaurant will have their way of training; however, here are the basics: \n\n1. Ensure the bottle matches the description on the wine list. \n2. Show the bottle to the customer to confirm their choice. \n3. Cut the foil under the lip, all the way around. Gently twist off the foil.\n4. Place the corkscrew into the middle of the cork, straight down, avoiding an angle. \n5. Pull the cork out straight, so you do not break the cork.\n6. Check for quality by smelling the cork. \n7. Pour a small taster for the client. \n8. Pour clockwise around the table.\n\nYou should know to avoid overpouring, twist the bottle to prevent drips when you pour, and more small tricks to impeccable wine service. In easy to understand steps, show the interviewer that you are capable when it comes to proper wine service.", "\"I first show the bottle to the customer, ensuring that I have the correct label before opening. Without twisting the bottle, always keeping the label out, I remove the foil, and place the corkscrew directly in the middle, to avoid cork breakage or residue. You should always pour a small taster for the person ordering the bottle. Once they approve, then serve the guests.\"", "\"I have not received formal wine training; however, I am able to open a bottle of wine easily. I look forward to furthering my training with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "There are many options for you in the fine dining industry. Why do you specifically want to work with Company ABC?", "answers": ["With many options in the upscale dining industry for employment, why do you want to work for Company ABC? Talk to the interviewer about your preference for their company. Dig deep when it comes to your response, bringing up specifics related to their menu, clientele, awards they have won, or their company mission.", "\"I am careful to be employed with a company that holds a strong industry reputation. I'd like to work for Company ABC because your training programs are above the industry standard and you have a reputation for treating your employees very well.\"", "\"I especially want to work for Company ABC because I have friends who have worked here previously, providing me with positive feedback on their experiences. I am looking for a positive work environment where I can stay for a long time to come. Also, I am passionate when it comes to fine wine, and your list is incredible.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "What do you feel is the most important characteristic in order to be successful with Company ABC?", "answers": ["It is essential to research Company ABC before your interview. You should be aware of the characteristics they value in their staff and leadership team. Likely, you will be able to find some great information on their website, a job description, or within their company values and mission statement. Show the interviewer the similarities in your characteristics, and what Company ABC seeks out in their new hires.", "\"Through my research on Company ABC I saw a theme surrounding honesty and diligence. I agree that these characteristics are fundamental. In addition to these, I would add a positive attitude, willingness to learn, and strong listening skills.\"", "\"I understand from researching Company ABC online, and also from being a customer in the past, that you seek people who are disciplined, intuitive when it comes to the needs of others, can remember the small details, and carry a highly positive attitude. I will bring all of these characteristics to Company ABC. My references can attest to the fact that I am diligent and honest as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Have you received any training in formal dining?", "answers": ["Many high-end restaurants will have a robust internal employee training program. Talk to the interviewer about any specialized training you have received in your career. The interviewer will take note, from your response, on the areas where you may need additional training.", "\"With my current company, I received two-week in-house training which included topics on best-practices, health and safety, up-selling, and wine pairings. They were beneficial training programs. Can you tell me a bit more about your training program here at Company ABC?\"", "\"I am new to the workforce and have not experienced a lot in the way of industry training. I do have my food safety certificate and look forward to gaining even more training through this role with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "You will be required to process expensive customer transactions. Do you consider yourself a trustworthy and honest person?", "answers": ["In the fine dining industry, you could be completing transactions from a few hundred dollars, into the thousands. Can you be trusted with a customers' black American Express card or a $4,000 bottle of wine? Draw on the strength of your references and assure the interviewer that you are a trustworthy and honest employee.", "\"One of my greatest strengths as an employee is my level of honesty and trustworthiness. I have multiple references who will attest to the fact that I am competent and honest. I have experience handling large amounts of cash and credit card transactions. I have opened bottles of wine worth up to $2,000 and invoices up to $8,000.\"", "\"I see myself and trustworthy and always honest. My integrity has never been in question, and my most recent manager will be happy to give you a solid reference regarding my reliability and transparent approach in the workplace; whether that be with large cheques or expensive food and beverage items.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Tell me about your food safety training or health and safety related certifications.", "answers": ["Health and safety is the main priority for all high-end dining establishments. Walk the interviewer through any related training. If you have any physical cards or certifications to show, be sure to bring those into the interview. If some of your certifications are close to expiration, be sure to disclose that.", "\"I have had training in my past three roles in regards to health and safety, and well as proper food handling. If there is additional training that you require me to participate in, I am happy to do so.\"", "\"I am new to the workforce and, having just graduated from university; I do not have formal training in health or safety. If you have any required coursework related to this position with Company ABC, I am happy to get a head start on that training.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "We will require you to be available on weekends, evenings, and holidays. Is there anything in your schedule hindering your availability?", "answers": ["Restaurants are often open late, on weekends, and on special holidays. Being in the service industry will require you to be flexible in your availability. Assure the interviewer that you can handle the schedule associated with this role. If you have scheduling limitations, this is the time to disclose them.", "\"I am accustomed to working a wide range of shifts that include evenings, weekends, holidays and a large amount of voluntary overtime. I enjoy working and am happy to work whenever required.\"", "\"I am very flexible with my schedule except for Wednesday evenings, when I attend evening university courses. Other than that evening, I am willing to accommodate any of your scheduling needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Looking at our wine list, what would you suggest as a pairing with our rack of lamb?", "answers": ["Whether you have formal training in wine pairings or not, the interviewer would like to see how confident you are when it comes to making suggestions to customers. Also, this question tests how much research you have done on their menu and wine list. \n\nSome suggestions for a rack of lamb include: \n\n- Syrah\n- Borolo \n- Bordeaux \n\nIt is safe to say that most old world wines will pair nicely with this style of meaty dish. Share your knowledge with the interviewer, being as specific to the Company ABC menu as possible.", "\"I have always enjoyed a Petite Sirah with a rack of lamb. I saw on your wine list that you offer Michael David's, 'Petite Petite.' Since this bottle is 85% Petite Sirah and 15% Petit Verdot, I find it a delicious selection that does not overpower a lamb dish. That bottle would be my suggestion.\"", "\"You have many amazing wines at Company ABC. Before making a final suggestion, I would ask the customer what their favorite wines are from home. Then, I would make an appropriate recommendation based on their palate. I see on your menu that you have an amazing Borolo which would be a fantastic pairing to any lamb dish.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "What does the term, 'a la carte' mean to you?", "answers": ["There are a few words and terms, based on the French language that you will likely come across while working in the upscale restaurant industry. The phrase, 'a la carte,' applies when you dine at a place where you can order dishes from a regular menu. The opposite offering is, 'd'hote,' which means a set menu. Just explain to the interviewer that you understand these terms.", "\"The term 'a la carte' to me, means, off the menu. I have worked only for a la carte style establishments; however, I have served on special occasions where there is a set menu. For instance, on Valentines Day.\"", "\"To me, 'a la carte' describes most restaurants, where diners can choose their desired selections from a menu with a significant amount of variety.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Have you already familiarized yourself with our menu?", "answers": ["Your response should always be 'yes!' The interviewer will gauge your interest in working for Company ABC, and your engagement level, by the effort that you exude. Do you want to be a stand-out candidate? It does not take much time to scan through a menu before your interview. Most restaurant menus are available online. Familiarize yourself with a couple of appetizers, entrees, desserts, and a bit of the wine and cocktail offerings.", "\"I have taken some time to study your menu, as I am very excited about this opportunity. I noticed that you have a wonderful selection for all dietary preferences including vegetarian and gluten-free options. Also, I appreciate that you have a robust wine list. I am a true wine enthusiast!\"", "\"I have dined at Company ABC a couple of times in the past and am familiar with your chef's style. The cuisine here is always incredible, and the overall experience unforgettable. I like that you have wine pairing suggestions listed under each entree and that the chef does a tasting menu which changes seasonally. I look forward to contributing to your talented and dynamic team.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "What does it mean to 'romanticize' a menu?", "answers": ["There are terms used in the restaurant industry that you should understand. When you are training for your new role, you may come across the word 'romanticize,' which refers to the way you describe a menu item. When you romanticize something, you are giving the beautiful and enticing details. For instance, rather than saying that the salad is spring greens with a vinaigrette, you may say that the dish is made from locally grown baby greens and topped with a house-made rosemary vinaigrette. Show the interviewer that you can bring passion and excitement when it comes to menu descriptions.", "\"I have training in the art of romanticizing a menu, and understand the importance of the practice. For instance, rather than saying that it's a steak, I could let the customer know that it's Japanese Wagyu beef, seared to perfection.\"", "\"I am newer to the restaurant industry, but I believe that to romanticize a menu is to make the menu items sound as delicious and enticing as possible. I could describe the details that go into the preparation, point out the items that are house-made, locally sourced, or organically grown.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "How would you respond if a customer wrote a bad review online, regarding your service?", "answers": ["In our digital age, with so much riding on our online reviews, it's imperative that negative reviews see a swift and adequate response. Some businesses will hire experts to handle their online reputation. These online reputation management services are precious to companies, such as restaurants, where many potential customers first go online to read reviews before making a reservation. \n\nIf this situation has happened to you before, you could give an example; however, be careful not to draw too much attention to the negatives and focus primarily on the positive outcome. \n\nExperts suggest the following when dealing with negative online reviews:\n\n- Respond quickly to any reviews that are reasonable or understandable \n- Do not become defensive \n- Give a brief public response then offer a more personal private response if possible\n- Address the most important parts of the feedback\n- Reinforce the fact that you care about your quality and customer experience", "\"I would be upset to see a negative review online because I put so much pride in the service that I give. However, I would address the situation quickly without becoming defensive. If the complaint were legitimate, I would ask the customer how I could win them back.\"", "\"If a customer wrote a bad review online, I would respond if it was appropriate to do so. Do you have policies in place when situations like this occur? I put a great amount of pride in the customer service that I deliver and hope that every one of my customers leaves, thrilled with the service they received.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "How would you react if a customer asked to send a $60 steak back, after eating over half of it?", "answers": ["Oh, the woes of working in the service industry! Whether you work at an upscale restaurant or a fast food establishment, you will come across customers now and then, who are difficult to please or take advantage of you or your restaurants' hospitality. Company ABC will likely have procedures in place for situations such as this. You can refer to previous training you received, and discuss with the interviewer how you would react. This question is not the opportunity to go on a tangent about terrible customers. Keep your answer to the point and present your solution.", "\"I come from the school of thought that the guest is always right. This philosophy means that no matter how far into their meal they are - they can send it back. Now, with that said, if the person is a repeat offender I may approach the situation differently. Do you have a policy in place for this type of situation?\"", "\"If a customer sent back an expensive dish or an inexpensive dish, I would take it back. To me, it is not the price that matters but the nature of the complaint. If the kitchen did not prepare it correctly, if it was cold, underdone, or overdone, that is what we want to know. I believe the only way to get better is to learn from constructive criticism, no matter how frustrating it may be in the moment.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Do you consider yourself a 'foodie'? Why or why not?", "answers": ["The term 'foodie' remains reserved for those who have a refined and adventurous interest in different cuisine experiences. They tend to be in-the-know on food trends and will usually try any food. The interviewer would like to know if you have a sense of adventure with your food. Being open to many foods will make you a better server, allowing you to give your take on a variety of menu items. When guests ask a server about a particular dish, and the server scrunches up their nose, saying, 'I don't like mushrooms, so I don't know,' it's not a particularly helpful exchange. Explain to the interviewer that you are interested in food and are excited to try the different items on the Company ABC menu.", "\"I do consider myself a foodie. I love to try new things and am open to a lot of tastes, spice levels, and textures.\"", "\"I am very adventurous with my food and would consider myself an emerging foodie, for sure. I would eventually love to become a food writer for a local food magazine or an online publication.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "Tell me about the worst dining guest you have ever dealt with, and how you persevered through the situation.", "answers": ["Guests will complain, be nit-picky, snarky, and downright rude. Situations like this are par for the course in the service industry. Luckily, these experiences are not the norm, and you get to choose how you react. Show the interviewer that you are not one to take it personally if a customer is acting out. Discuss a time when you have been in an awkward situation, and how you came out of it unscathed!", "\"I once had a customer dislike their meal so much that they threw their plate on the floor! It was the oddest experience for me to see a grown adult throw what looked like a tantrum. I politely let him know that we would not char him for his meal but that he was not welcome to stay. His behavior was disturbing to the other guests and likely would have continued to be a bad service through to the end. Do you have a policy at Company ABC for situations where guests are unruly?\"", "\"I once served a table where the boyfriend was planning to propose to his girlfriend over dessert. He came in earlier that day, gave the engagement ring to the kitchen manager, and we prepared for the exciting event. When the proposal came, his girlfriend said, 'no.' I honestly think it was the most awkward situation I have ever witnessed. The girl left, and the guy just sat at the table, expressionless. He wasn't terrible to deal with, but the situation was awful. The manager comped his bill, and we offered him an Uber home, on us. To persevere through this, or any other unsavory moments on the job, I remind myself that the situation isn't forever. I am kind, present solutions, and keep a smile on my face.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "If Company ABC hired you today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you would be ready to make an impact on their establishment, immediately after being hired. It's important to come to an interview with a 30-90 day strategic plan on how you would impact the business, should you be the successful candidate. Tell the interviewer what your impact goal is.", "\"I know you mentioned that the average tenure in this position, before promotion, is anywhere from 6 months to a year or more. I intend to prove over the first three months that I am a rockstar in the service industry and would be of greater benefit to you in a lead evening head server role than I am in a daytime service position.\"", "\"When we were speaking earlier, about upselling targets in this position, you mentioned that most servers reach their food and liquor sales expectations after 120 days. If hired today, my goal would be to exceed my goals after the first 90 days. I plan to make a positive impact very quickly by getting to know the menu in a very detailed way.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "We cannot always predict how busy we will be in our dining room. How do you react to a sudden increase in your workload?", "answers": ["Workloads often increase and decrease unpredictably, in the restaurant industry. The interviewer would like to know how you adapt when work suddenly piles up. Tables fill up, people demand more attention from you than usual, or there are hiccups in the kitchen. Show that you are willing to work faster, put in overtime, or take an extra shift when needed. You will also want to speak of your time-management abilities.", "\"I understand that my workload will increase unpredictably at times. It's the ebb and flow of the restaurant industry. When tables are piling in, I will ask for assistance from another team member who has a lighter workload; perhaps a hostess or a server with a smaller section. I offer the same assistance to my coworkers when they have a heavy workload as well.\"", "\"I tend to thrive under pressure, and always have, which is why I do very well as a server in a busy establishment such as Company ABC. I want to be the top server regarding customer feedback and ring-outs, which often means doing more than the basic expectations. I love being busy, so I thrive on those opportunities for more work and additional chances to prove my value.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "When entering a new job, describe how you build relationships with your new coworkers and managers.", "answers": ["The restaurant industry usually has a tight-knit employee culture so; the interviewer would like to know how you plan to start relationships with your new co-workers. Due to a wide variety of personalities, coworker connections can take time to form. How do you ensure that you have a strong line of communication with your co-workers and managers, right from the start? \n\nHere are some ideas for getting started on the right foot: \n\n- Be willing to accept feedback and help \n- Offer to assist in some way \n- Do not have an air of entitlement or act as though you know the ins and outs immediately\n- Avoid all company gossip, at all cost\n- Be early on your first day (and every day after that!) \n- Come dressed appropriately", "\"I understand that some relationships come quickly and others take time to nurture. When starting a new job all that I can do is be my true self and let my personality, integrity, and reliability speak for itself.\"", "\"I understand that people like to talk about themselves. The best way that I can create new relationships with others is by asking them about themselves. Hopefully, we find common ground and make a quick connection!\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "What is the worst thing a previous manager could say about you?", "answers": ["Word travels fast in the service industry, and the interviewer wants to make sure they are hiring someone with a sterling reputation. With that said, nobody is a perfect employee! Think about some mistakes you have made at work or any suggestions for improvement received. If a manager were to provide you with feedback or criticism, what might they say? Keep your answer brief and be sure to finish on a positive note by discussing your willingness to improve and take constructive feedback.", "\"When I started my first service job, I had a pretty big learning curve. The point of sale software and my daily tasks were all very new to me. I made a lot of mistakes in the beginning because I felt rushed and wanted to learn as quickly as I could. My manager suggested I slow down and not worry so much about keeping up with the servers who had been there for a while. He was understanding, and it helped me to learn that it's okay to take my time to avoid mistakes.\"", "\"When I was first out of school I had issues with getting to work on time.  Chalk it up to youth or poor planning, but my boss told me then, that my inability to get to work on time was a noticeable shortcoming. I have since resolved this problem and assure you I will arrive to work ten minutes early every day!\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Restaurants", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["Unfortunately, the service industry has a reputation for unreliable staff and high turnover. The interviewer would like to know that this is not the case with you. Discuss your dedication to being present and on time. A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance habits.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I come from the old school way of thinking where if you aren't in the hospital, you show up to work. I can honestly say that the last sick day I took was about six years ago. I expect dedication from my co-workers, which I first need to demonstrate.\""]}]